some of you have finished part 1 in the
last few days some of you finished part
1 in December and I did ask both of you
who took it in person to kind of revise
material and make sure it's up to date
but let's do a quick summary of the kind
of key things reload and so I came up
with these five things now Institue here
if anybody has other key insights that
they kind of feel that they came away
from for the postings of it
um stacks of nonlinear functions with
lots of wealth stacks of differentiable
nonlinear functions with lots of routers
of nearly any predictive modeling
program so when we say here or network a
lot of people are suggesting we should
use the phrase differentiable Network
you know if you think about things like
the collaborative filtering we did it
was really a couple of embeddings and a
dot product and that gave us quite a
long way there's nothing very neural
looking about that but we know that when
we stack certain kinds of nonlinear
functions on top of each other the
universal approximation theorem tells us
that can approximate any computable
function to arbitrary precision we know
that if it's differentiable we can use
SGD to find the parameters which match
that function so this to me is kind of
like the key insight um
some facts of functions are better than
others to some kind of data and some
kinds of problems one way to make life
very easy we learnt is transfer learning
and I am I think
really every Network we created in the
last course which is transfer learning a
big 60 division and in text so pretty
much everything so transfer learning
generally was always last layer replace
it with a new one that has the right
number of outputs pre compute the
penultimate layers output then very
quickly create a linear model that goes
from that to your for your preferred
answer you now have something that works
pretty well and then you can fine tune
more and more layers backwards as
necessary and we learnt that fine tuning
those additional layers generally the
best way to do that was to pre-compute
the last of the layers that you're not
fine-tuning and so then you could just
calculate the whack to the remaining
ones that papers large amount of time
and remember that CN n layer up in in
layers convolutional layers that mean to
say complex are slower so then it picked
up the previous one as well stack of if
the wrench she at all nonlinear
all right
I'm convolutional layers of slower dense
layers are bigger and there's an
interesting question I've added here
which is we remember remember in the
last lesson we kind of looked at red
snapped and infection apps and in
general more modern nets can not have
any gameplay so what's the best way to
do transfer learning I'm gonna leave
that as an open question for now we're
going to look into it a bit during the
class but it's not a question that
anybody has answered to my photo session
blast-jet some ideas that no one's
really no one's even written a paper
that attempts to address it as far as
I'm aware
[Music]
so given we have transfer learning to
give us scale it's a long way the next
thing we have to get us a long way is to
try and create an architecture which
suits our problem
both our data and our loss function so
for example if we have Auto correlated
inputs so in other words each input is
related to the previous input so each
pixel is similar to the next door pixel
or a sound wave each sample is optimal
to the previous sample and something
like that that kind of data we can -
like to use CNM tour as long as it of a
fixed size it's a sequence we like to
use an unerring anymore if it's a
categorical output we like to use a star
next or so there are ways we work of
tuning our architecture not so that it
makes a possible result problem because
any any standard dense network can solve
any problem but it affected a lot faster
and a lot easier to train if you make
sure that your activation functions and
your architecture booth the phone so
that is another thing I think we learn
and something I hope that everybody can
narrate is the five steps to avoiding a
thing if you've forgotten them they're
both here and discussed in more detail
lesson trees get more data
thank you more data using data
augmentation is more generalizable
architectures that architecture that
generalize well and particularly we
looked at batch normalization use
regularization techniques as few as we
can because by definition they destroy
it in data and that will not particular
using drop out and then finally if we
have to we can look at reducing the
complexity of the architecture so the
general approach we we learnt this is
absolutely key is first of all with a
new problem start with a network that's
too big it's not regular eyes that can't
help us solve the problem even if it has
to overfit terribly if you can't do that
is no point starting director eyes yet
so we start out by trying to overfit
terribly once we cut to the point that
we're getting 100% accuracy in a
validation set terrible because
overfitting then we start going through
these steps until we get a nice balance
okay so that's kind of the process that
we want
and then finally we learnt about
embeddings as a technique to allow us to
use categorical data and specifically
the idea of using words all the idea of
using latent variables so in this case
this was the rudiments data set for
favorite builder so that's the five main
insights I prefer
did anybody have any other kind of key
takeaways that they think people
providing should think about or remember
or things they found interesting
okay that's good if you come up with
something but you know
of one question and how does having
duplicates and training data affect the
model created and if you're using data
augmentation do you end up with
duplicate data just look at the input
data
I mean it's not a big deal right because
we agree shuffle the batch and then you
select them you know randomly
effectively you're you're waiting that
data point higher than its neighbors so
in a big data set is then they prayers
or difference if you've got one thing
repeated a thousand times and then if
any another 100 data points that can be
a big problem because you're waiting one
second point
so as you will have seen we've got a
couple of big technology foundation
changes the first one is we're moving
from Python to to Python 3 - 2 I think
is a good place to start
even that a lot of the folks in part one
had never coded in place and before and
many of them had never written you know
very substantial pieces of software
before and a lot of the tutorials out
there like example one of our first
static points which is a limb flatten
the hard way and platon tool or the
existing clothes out their apartment -
so if a person chooses the classes that
yesterday have two more questions one is
are you going to post the slides after
this I will press the slide yet and the
other is could you go through steps for
underfitting at some point give this as
far over that or you know how to deal
with overfit yeah let's do that in a
forum thread so why don't you create a
forum thread asking about underfitting
comp if you don't need to do that in the
plateau forum you could do that in the
in the main forum because the pops
people will be interested caring about
that if you want to revise that lesson
train started by talking about unfitting
okay so that seemed like a good place to
start I don't think we should keep using
plasm shoe though for a number of
reasons one is that since then the ice -
folks have come out and said that the
next version won't be compatible with
platon - so that's a problem indeed from
2020 onwards pleasantry will be end of
life which means there won't be patches
or so that's at all
also we're going to be doing more stuff
with concurrency and parallel
programming this time around and they're
the features in packs of three a lot
better and then pison 3.6 is just
released which has some very nice
features in particular so being format
in which some people it's no big deal
but to me it saves a lot of time and
next life a lot easier so we're going to
move across the class and three and
there are hopefully you've all gone
through the protests already and there's
some tips on the forum about powder as
both running at the same time
although I agree with the suggestion I
read from somebody which was so I have
suck it up and do the trench the
translation once now but you have to
worry about it
okay much more interesting and much
bigger is the move from piano to temper
flow so beyond oh we thought was the
better starting points that have a much
simpler API there's very few new
concepts to learn to understand piano
and it doesn't have a whole new
ecosystem you see tensorflow lives
within Google's
of ecosystem and has its own build
system called basil it's got its own
file serialization system called proto
bar it's got its own profiler method
based on Chrome it's got all this stuff
to learn but if you come this far then
you know you're already investing the
time we think it's worth investing the
time intensify because there's a lot of
stuff which just in the last few weeks
it started being able to do that's
pretty amazing so Rachel and I have the
rich perpetual wrote this post here it
is about how much tensorflow sucks for
which we got invited to attend to flow
dev summit and got to meet all the
typical flow core team and okay so
looking at moving from yellow to temp to
flow we got invited to the tensorflow
dev summit and we were pretty amazed at
all the starters literally just being at
it the tensorflow
one just came out
and here are some of the things that
you'd wrinkle for tensorflow dev summit
videos you can watch the videos about
all this and perhaps the most exciting
thing for us is that they are really
investing in a simplified API so if you
look at this code you can create a deep
neural network regressor on a mixture of
categorical and real variables using a
kind of almost our like syntax and fit
it in two lines of code and you'll see
that those lines of code at the bottom
the two lines to fit us look very much
like Paris France wash away the carrot
author has been a wonderful influence on
Google and in fact everywhere we saw at
the best climate was care up API
influences so tensorflow and Cara are
kind of becoming more and more one which
is terrific so one is that they're
really investing in the API a second is
that some of the tooling is looking
pretty good so Kent the board has come a
long way things like these graphs
showing you how your different layers
are distributed and how that's changed
over time and really helped to debug
what's going on so if you get some kind
of gravy and saturation in a layer you
can dig through these graphs and very
quickly find out where this was a one of
my favorite talks actually this guy
remember correctly his name was daffodil
and his signature was an emoji of a
daffodil very Google but here's oh I
think its staff at a lion or substitue a
lion I think you're right yes the truth
to emergence of espadrille hemline
ban corrected if you watch this video
you kind of had to walk through showing
some of the functionality that's there
and how to use it and I thought that was
pretty helpful
um one of the most important ones to me
is that tensorflow has a great story
about production ization and you know
part one and I didn't much care about
production ization it was really about
like playing around what we can what can
we learn so at this point I think we
might be starting to think about how do
I get my stuff online in front of my
customers and these points are talking
about something particular called
tensorflow serving and tensorflow
serving is the system that can take your
brain tends to flow model and create an
API for it which does some pretty cool
things for example think about how hard
it would be without the help of some
library to productionize your system
you've got one request coming in at a
time you've got an GPUs how do you make
sure that you don't saturate all those
GPUs if you send the request to one it's
free if you don't give up all of your
memory that is still how do you grab a
few requests put them into a batch put
them in all to the GPU at once get a bit
out of the batch put them back to the
people that requested it all that stuff
so serving does that for you it's very
early days for the software a lot of
things don't work yet but you can
download an early version and start
playing with it I think that's pretty
interesting
with the high level API and in
tensorflow what's going to be the
difference between the Karis API and the
tensorflow API yeah that's a great
question check in fact the tensorflow or
TS Kaos will become a namespace so
carrots will become the official top
level API or is implode in fact make
sure was a person who announced that yes
I was just going to add that tensorflow
is kind of introducing I think a few
different libraries at different layers
kind of depend
write different levels as well as our
action so it's kind of like this it's a
concept of kind of an evaluation API
that appears everywhere is basically is
the carrots API hey there's a layers API
below yeah yeah
so there's being mixed in lots of places
so all the stuff you put that carrot is
going to be very helpful not just in
using carrots in sort of tensorflow
that in using tensorflow directly
another interesting thing about
tensorflow
is that they've built a lot of cool
integrations where there is faster
managers in distributed storage systems
and stuff like that so it'll kind of fit
into your production systems will neatly
use the data in whatever place authority
is more neatly social data in s3 or
something like that you can general
intro Australian to sensor Club
something I found very interesting is
that they announced a couple of weeks
ago a machine learning toolkit which
brings really high quality
implementations of a wide variety of non
deep learning algorithm temp to flow so
these all these are GPU accelerated
paralyzed skill and supported by Google
and so and like a lot of these have a
lot of tech behind them so for example
the random forest there's a paper
actually called the tensor forests which
explains all of the interesting things
they did to create a fast GPU
accelerated vampire two more questions
one is cute or will you give an example
of how to solve gradient saturation and
for flow tools I'm not sure that I will
we'll see how we go because I think the
the video from the dead summit which is
available online and already shows you
that so I would say look at that first
and please do have questions and all the
videos from the summit are online and
someone asked about is there an idea for
using deep learning on AWS lambda not
that I said oh no and in fact
in general you know if Google has a kind
of a service version of chapter flow
serving called Google Cloud ml where you
can pay them a few cents you know a
transaction and they'll post your model
for you there isn't really something
like that
the Ramazan Arizona where and then
finally in terms of chance to flow I had
an interesting and infuriating a few
weeks trying to prepare for this class
in trying to get something working that
would translate French into English and
every single example I found online had
major problems even the official
tensorflow tutorial missed out a key
thing which is that the lowest level of
a language model really should be
bi-directional as this one shows by
directional arrow down and there one's
walton's I'm trying to figure out how to
make it work horrible going to get it to
work and care us nothing worked properly
finally basically the issue is this
modern RNA in systems like a full neural
translation system involve a lot of
tweaking and mucking around with the
innards of the RNA using things that
we'll learn about and there just hasn't
been at API that really that's that
happen so I finally got it working by
switching to PI torch which we'll learn
about doing but eventually going to
start the first lesson was going to be
about neural translation and I put it
back because tensorflow has just
released a new system for our own ends
which looks like it's going to make all
this lot easier
so this is a exciting idea is that
there's an API that allows us to create
some pretty powerful RNN implementations
and we're going to be absolutely needing
that when we learn to create
translations oh yeah there is one more
again early days but there is something
called excellet which is the accelerated
linear algebra neutral I think yeah
which is a system which takes tensorflow
code and compiled it and so for those of
you that know something that tiling and
you know that a compilation you can do a
lot of clever stuff in terms of like
identifying their code or unrolling
loops or accusing operations whatever
x-play tries to do all that now at this
stage but takes your pencil flow code
and turns it into machine code one of
the cool things that that you do is run
it on a mobile phone with almost no
supporting libraries using native
machine instructions on that phone much
less memory but one of the really
interesting discussions I had at the
summit was with Scott Gray who some of
you may have heard of he was the guy
that actively accelerated neural network
kernels when he was at nirvana
he had like kernels that were two or
three times faster than invidious
kernels that doesn't know anybody else
in the world who knows more about neural
network performance than him he told me
that he thinks that actually is a key to
creating a performant concise expressive
neural network code and I really like
that idea the idea is currently if you
look in the tensorflow code it's
thousands and thousands of lines of C++
all custom written the idea is you throw
all that away in a place it with a small
number of lines attempt to flow code
that get compiled to your extra layer so
that's something that's actually got me
pretty excited
so
so tensorflow is pretty interesting
having said that it's kind of hideous
the API is full of not invented here
syndrome it's clearly written by a bunch
of engineers to have not thoroughly
spent that much time learning about the
user interface of api's it's full of the
the Google isms in terms of having to
fit into their ecosystem but most
importantly it's still a kind of like
siano you have to set up the whole
computation graph and then you kind of
go run which means if you want to do
stuff in your computation graph that
involves like conditional Defense
statement you know if this happens you
do this other part of a loop it's
basically impossible direction
um
so it turns out that there's a very
different way of programming neural net
which is dynamic computation otherwise
known as defined through run there's a
number of libraries to do this torch a
torch Dana
dinette they're the one that come to
mind and we're going to be looking at
one that was I won't say released but an
early version was put out about a month
ago called PI torch which I've started
rewriting a lot of stuff in and a lot of
the more complex stuff just become
suddenly so much easier and because it
becomes easier to do more complex things
I often find I can create faster and
more concise code by using this approach
so even or by pi torch is very very very
new it is coming out of the same people
that built torch which really all of
Facebook's systems they're on top of I
suspect that Facebook or in the process
of moving across from watched apply
torch and it's already full of credibly
full stuff and as you'll see so we will
be using increasingly more and more
apply towards during this course
there is a question says pre compiling
means that will write tensorflow code
and test it and then when we train a big
model then we pre compile the code and
train our model yes so if we're talking
about Excel a Excel a can be use number
of ways one is that you come up with a
some different kind of different type of
kernels and different of factorization
something like that and arriving in
tensorflow you compile it with Excel a
and then you make it available to
anybody so when they use your layer you
know they're getting this compiled
optimized code it could mean that you
take when you use tensor flow serving
and supply serving might compile your
code using Excel a and B serving up an
accelerated version of it one example
which came up was to our ends Aaron ends
often involved you know nowadays that
you'll learn some kind of complex
customizations of you know a
bi-directional layer and then some
stacked layers and attention layer and
then a head into a separate stack to
decoder you can fuse that together into
you know a single layer called
bi-directional attention sequence the
sequence which indeed people have
actually bought that has done so there's
various wave which neural network
compilation can be very helpful
what is the relationship between
tensorflow and pi torch that there's no
relationship so that's Lori's Google
thing PI torch is that kind of Facebook
thing but also a community thing if the
flow is a
huge complex feast of a system which
uses all kinds of advanced software
engineering methods all over the place
in theory that ought to make it terribly
fast in practice two recent benchmarks
actually show to clear that as well and
I think the reason is because it's so
big and complex it's so hard to get
everything to work together in theory pi
torch ought to be the flawless it
consists of defined by relative cement
it's way less optimization that the
systems can do that attend aptly among
the fastest because it's so easy to
write code is so much easier to write
good code so you know it's interesting I
think there's such different approaches
I think it's really great to know those
because there are going to be some
things are going to be fantastic and
just a flow and something literally
fantastic only they couldn't be more
different which is why I think there are
two good things to learn
all right so they're wrapping up this
introductory part I wanted to kind of
change your expectations about what how
you've learnt so far to how we're going
to learn in the future what one to me
was about showing your best practices
right so genius like here's a library is
a problem you use these library and
these steps to solve this problem and do
it this way and what I behold we've got
this alternative cable home kitchen so
it was a tight race of selecting that
had best practice
so you now know everything I know about
best practices I didn't you know I don't
really have anything else to tell you so
we're now actually like stuff I haven't
quite figured out yet northern body else
but you probably need to know so some of
the for example like neural translation
that's example something that is solved
by a Google's Google solder but they
haven't released the way they solved
right so kind of the rest of us to try
to put everything together and figure
out how to make something work as well
as Google made that work more often um
it's going to be um use the sequence the
thing that you can do that can get some
pretty good result here but there's a
thousand things you could do to make it
better that no one's tried yet so that's
interesting or thirdly it could be
here's a sequence of things that solve
this pretty well but gosh we wrote a lot
of custom clothes there didn't we
I'm sure this could be abstracted really
nicely but no one has done that yet but
there's kind of three main categories
and so generally at the end of each
class it won't be like ok that's it
that's how you do this thing it'll be
more like here are the things you can
explore and so the kind of the homework
will be you know pick one of these
interesting things and dig into it and
generally speaking that homework will
get you to a point there hopefully no
one's done before or there's probably no
one's written down before I I found as I
built this I think nearly every single
piece of code I'm presenting I was
unable to find anything online which is
that thing correctly like there's often
example code it's claimed to be
something like that but again again I
found that was missing huge pieces and
we'll talk about some of the things that
you know it was missing as we go wonder
a common one was it would only work on a
single item at a time it wouldn't work
with
- therefore the GPU is basically totally
wasted or failed to get anywhere near
the performance that is claimed in the
paper that it was meant to be based on
so you know generally speaking there's
going to be lots of opportunities if
you're interested to you know write a
blog post about the things you tried and
what works and what didn't and you'll
generally find that there probably
there's no other post like that out
there particularly if you pick a data
set that in your domain area is very
unlikely that so is written
I'm not going back can we use tensorflow
and torch together
I don't think torched a PI torch torch
is very similar but it's written in Lua
which is a very small embedded language
very good for what it is but not very
good for what we want to do so pate
watch is kind of a port of torch into
piping which is pretty cool so can you
use them together yeah sure you know but
we'll kind of see a bit of that in
general you can reorder your cues
desperate and simpler to get to a
certain point and a few more step I
torch you can't like integrate them into
the same network and because they're
very different approaches you can
certainly solve a problem with the two
of them together alright so for those of
you who have some money left over I
would strongly to jet building a box um
and the reason is just building a box is
because you're pinging 90 cents an hour
for p2 I know a lot of you are spending
a couple hundred bucks a month on AWS
bills here is a box that cost $550 and
will be about twice as fast as paycheck
so it it's just not good value in p2 and
it's way slower and it needs to be so
and also building a box you know if one
of the many things that's just good to
learn you know is understanding how
everything fits together so I've got
some suggestions here about what box to
build the various different budgets you
certainly don't have to but this is my
recommendation a couple of points to me
more RAM helps more than I think people
who have discussed this stuff online
quite appreciate 12 gig of ram means by
specific advanced Isis which means half
as many steps necessary to get your
epoch it means more stable gradient
which means you can use higher learning
rates so more RAM I think is often
underappreciated
the Titan X is the card that has 12 key
gram it is a lot more expensive but you
can get the previous generations version
second hand is called the Maxwell to fit
as a black neck a scale just the current
one or the Titan X Maxwell previous
generation one the previous generation
one is not a big step back at all don't
have 12 gig ram if you can get one use
that would be a you know a great option
the gtx 1080 and 1070 are absolutely
fantastic as well they're nearly as good
as it's like maps that they just have
eight gig rather than quality
going back to a GTX 980 which is the
kind of previous generation consumers
hop in a car you have the RAM again you
know so of all the place you're going to
spend money in a box or nearly all of it
into the GPU you know every one of these
steps 1070 the type next Pascal you know
if they're big step up
um and as you will have seen from part
one if you've got more RAM it really
helps if you can pre-compute locked up
keep it in ground
having said that there's a new kind of
hard drive for an MDM a drive on
volatile memory clean nvme drives are
quite extraordinary they're like not
that far away from RAM like speeds but
there are drives you know their
persistent you have to get a special
kind of motherboard but if you can
afford it someone who is to be like Oh
non-poor five bucks right to get an MDM
eight Drive that's going to really allow
you to put all of your kind of currently
used data on that drive and access it
very very good so that's my other -
doesn't the batch size also depend
heavily on the video RAM or it does not
referring to the 12-gauge i screen I'm
probably Rams on the video con GPU
there's upgrading ram allowed bigger
batch sizes upgrading the card the video
the card that the video cards Ram you
can't upgrade the RAM on the card you
buy a card that has X amount of RAM so
Titan X has 1280 X 1080 850 X 984
thought that on the time upgrading the
amount of RAM that in your computer
doesn't change your batch size it just
changes the amount you can let pre
compute
and let's use an nvme drive in which
case where as much less fun you don't
have to plug everything in you can go to
central computers which is a San
Francisco computer shop for example and
still put it all together for you and
there's a fantastic thread on the forums
Brendon's is one of the participants in
the course as a great medium post went
there just explaining his whole journey
to getting something built in setup so
there's lots of stuff there did offer
you
alright it's time to build your box and
while you wait for things to install
it's time to start reading papers so
papers are if you're a philosophy
graduate like me verify they look like
here on 4.1 and florally 4.2 on the left
but that is an extract from the atom
paper and you all know how to do atom in
Microsoft Excel
it's amazing how most papers managed to
make simple things incredibly complex
and a lot of that is because academics
need to show other academics our worthy
they are of a conference button which
means showing up or their fancy math
skills so if you really need a proof of
the convergence of your optimizer rather
than just running it and if it works you
can study theorem 4.1 and Rory 4.0 and
blah blah blah in general though the way
philosophy graduates read papers is to
read the abstracts find out what problem
is solving read the introduction to
learn more about that problem and how
pages get work tackled it jump to the
bit at the end for experiments to see
how well the thing works it works really
well jump back to the bit which has the
pseudocode in and try to get that to
work
ideally hopefully in the meantime
finding that somebody else has written a
blog post in simple English like this
example with Adam and so
don't be disheartened when you start
reading deep learning papers and unless
you have a math background well even if
you're a PhD in math and they're still
terrifying Alastair felt disheartened
Germany
Rachel was complaining about a paper
just today in there so yeah you will
learn to read the papers the other thing
I'll say is that like you'll even see
now they'll be a bit that's like and
then we use a soft next layer and there
will be the equation for soft next layer
you look at the appraiser would like
what the hell and then like oh I already
know the soft next layer you know it'll
be like and then we'll use an LS p.m.
not literally still in every paper they
write the damn LS p.m. equations as if
that any help to anybody right okay it
adds more Greek symbols so big I'm
talking of Greek symbols it's very hard
to read and remember things you can't
pronounce right so if you don't know how
to read the Greek letters Google the
Greek alphabet and learn how to flavour
divested it's just so much easier when
you can look in the page and rather go
squiggle something squiggle something
you can say out for something in day
design I know it's a small little thing
but it does make a big difference so we
are all there to help each other brief
tapers the reason we need to be papers
is because as of now a lot of the things
we're doing only exist in very recent
paper form
you
okay
so I really think writing is a good idea
in fact all of your projects I hope will
end up in at least one blog if you don't
have a blog medium comm is a great place
to write we would love to feature your
work on faster AI so you know tell us
about what we create you know we're very
keen for most people to get into the
deep learning community so yeah when you
write this stuff say hey you know I'm
the system stuff based on its course I'm
doing and guess what I've learnt and
here's what I've tried and use what I
found out I put the code I'll get hard
it's amazing like even I'm asked putting
our little AWS setup scripts on github
for the MOOC Rachel had like a dozen
pull requests within a week with more
than that yes with all kinds of little
bits of like oh if you're on this
version of Mac it's on this special here
that's checked this out to make it work
in Ireland as well as in America and so
there's lots of stuff that you can do I
think the most important tip here is
don't wait to be perfect before you
start writing you know what was that tip
you told me Rachel you should think of
your target audience as the person who's
one step behind you or maybe your target
audience is someone that's just working
through the part one milk right now yeah
so your target audience is not young
presenting exactly it's used to sonica
another thing that you would love to
have seen because there will be far more
people in that target audience than the
Geoffrey Hinton target audience
okay how we going to find Rachel
7:45 so this might be a good time for
okay well looks let's just get through
this and then we can get on to the
initial so I've tried to lay out what I
think will study in part two as I say
what I was planning and so quite
recently to present today was a neural
translation and then two things happened
Google suddenly came up with a much
better RN and sequence of sequence API
and then also two to three weeks ago a
new paper came out for generative models
which totally changed everything so
that's why we've redone things and we're
starting with CNN generative models
today yeah
if things yes we have a question where
to find the current research papers okay
we'll get to that for sure let's do that
after everybody so giving the thing go
as planned there general kind of topic
areas in part 2 will be CNN's and NLP
beyond certifications if you think about
it pretty much every with everything we
did in plant one with classification or
a little bit of regression
we're going to now be talking more about
generative models little hard to exactly
define what I mean by generative model
but we're talking about creating an
image or creating a sentence
you know we're creating bigger output
okay so CN n see on classification so
generative models at CN n means the
thing that we could produce could be a
picture showing this is where the
bicycle is which is where the person is
this is whether graphic that's called
the segmentation or it could be tag
taking a black and white image and
turning it into a color image or taking
a low-res division turning into a higher
image or taking a photo and putting it
into a van Gogh or taking a photo and
turning it into a sentence describing it
actually um NLP beyond classification
can be taking a english sentence and
turning it into french or taking an
english story and the question and
turning it into an answer of that
question about a story at a chat box in
your name will be talking about how to
deal with larger data sets so that both
means data sets with more things in it
and data sets where the things are
bigger and then finally and something
I'm pretty excited about as I've done a
lot of work recently finding interesting
stuff about using deep learning for
structured data and for train theories
so for example we heard about fraud the
fraud is both of those things that
combines time theories of kind of
transaction histories and trick
histories and structured data in our
customer information traditionally
that's not being peppered with deep
learning but I've actually found some
theta P are in on world-class approaches
to solving those big learning so I'm
really looking forward to sharing that
with you
okay so let's take a ten-minute four
eight minute break come back at 5:00 to
8:00 thanks very much
okay so we're going to learn about this
idea of artistic style or neural style
transfer and the idea is that we're
going to take a photo and make it look
like it was painted in the style of some
painter so our inputs are
a photo
and
[Music]
I'm kind of call it well that's why else
and style and so these two things are
going to be combined together to create
a
an image which is going to hopefully
have the content of the photo
not working and the style
at the image
um so
what are we going to do this is we're
going to assume that there is some
function where the inputs to this
function are
the photo actually they're going to be
the input to the function is going to be
there the photo the style image and some
generated image that I've created and
that will return some number where this
function will be higher if the generated
image really looks like this photo in
this style and lower if it doesn't so if
we can create this lost function that
basically says here's my generated image
and it returns back a number saying oh
yes that generated image does look like
that photo in that style then we could
use FGD and we would use SGG not to
optimize the weights of a network we
would use fgt to optimize the pixel
values that the generated image that we
would be using using it to try to
optimize the value of this argument so
even quite done that before but
conceptually it's identical right
conceptually we can just find the
derivative of this function with respect
to this input right and then we can try
and optimize that input which is just a
set of pixel values try and maximize the
function
so all we need to do is come up with the
function come up with a function which
will tell us how much does some
generated image look like this photo in
this style and the way we're going to do
that step one is going to be very simple
we're going to turn it into two
functions
F content
we'll take the photo and the generated
image and that will tell us a bigger
number if the generated image looks more
like the photo if the content looks the
same and then there'll be a second
function
the final image and the generated image
and that will tell us the Ohio number if
this generated image looks like it was
painted in the same style of the style
image we can just turn it into two
pieces and add them together so now we
need to kind of come up with these boom
now the first part
it's very easy
um what's a way that we could
function that returns a higher number
that generated image is more similar to
some photo
we come up with a lock function do that
oh you're really obvious one
the values of four pixels the values of
the pixels in the generative image the
mean squared error between them and the
photo that mean squared error loss
function would be one way of doing this
and part now the problem with that
though is that as I start to turn it
into a van Gogh those pixel values are
going to change they're going to change
color because the Bank off might have
been a very blue looking van Gogh
they'll change the relationships to each
other so it might you know the the might
become a curve or you see a straight
line so really the pixel wise mean
squared error is not going to give us
many much freedom in trying to create
something that still looks like a photo
so here's an idea instead let's look at
what the pixels but let's take those
pixels and stick them through a
pre-trained enn like bgg and let's look
at like the fourth or fifth or eighth
convolutional layers activations
remember back to those like that those
Matt Matt baler visualizations where we
saw that the later layers kind of said
how much doesn't how much like doesn't
Abel look like here or how much does it
look like afar how much does this look
like the fur of a job right the later
layers who are dealing with bigger
objects and more kind of semantic
concepts so if we were to use a later
layers activations as our loss function
then we could really change the style
and the color and all kinds of stuff and
really would be saying just an eyes
don't look like an eye there's the big
still look like a big there's the rock
still look like a rock and if the answer
is yes
then okay that's good you know this is
something that matches in terms of the
meaning of the content even though the
pixel look very different and so that's
exactly what we're going to do so the s
content
okay we're going to say that just the
vgg activations of some convolutional
layer which one we can trace them
that's actually enough for us to get
started let's let's try and build
something that optimizes pixels using a
loss function of the vgg network some
convolutional layer
so this is the mural style notebook
and
um much of what we're going to look at
it's going to look very similar the
first thing you'll see which doesn't
look similar to before is the focusing
board limit men limit men
[Music]
remember you can always see the source
code for something that you've put into
question mark
alright limit name is just these three
lines of code which another somebody
kindly is already patient in the forum
tend to flow one of the many things they
gets like about tensor flow for our kind
of work is that it's all of the default
our production defaults so one of the
default is it will use up all of your
memory on all of your graphics cards but
I'm currently running this on a server
with four graphics cards which I meant
to be sharing with my colleagues at that
University here if every time I run a
notebook nobody else can use any other
graphics card they're going to be really
really pissed and this nice little
giggle I have of running these four
classes is going to disappear very
quickly so I need to make sure I run
limit then very soon as soon as I start
running the notebook I mean honestly I
think this is a or choice by the
tensorflow horses because like somebody
putting something in production is going
to be taking time to optimize things I
don't give a shit about the defaults
there is somebody who's hacking phone
together too quickly too forgiving
working very much once nice defaults
right so this is like one of the many
many places where Interpol makes some
odd little annoying decisions but anyway
every time now I created your notebook I
copy this line in and make sure I read
it and so this and does not use up all
of your memory okay
so
um I've got a link to the paper that
we're looking at and indeed we can open
it and now is a good time to talk about
how helpful it is to use some kind of
paper reading system I really like this
one it's free is called Mendeley desktop
mentally let's use as you find papers
you can save them into a folder on your
computer
Mendeley will automatically watch that
folder any PDF it appears there gets
added to your library and it's really
quite cool because what it then does is
a find the the archive ID and then you
can click this little button here and it
will go to archive
yes do an explain what archetype is I
will in a moment yep
it'll go to archive and grab all of the
information such as the abstract and so
forth and filled out for you
and so this is really great because now
anytime I want to find out what I've
read which has got only think of a style
I can type style and up up all of the
papers believe me after a long time of
reading papers without something like
this reading papers without something
like this it basically goes in one ear
and out the other and like literally
I've read papers a year later and at the
end of it I've realized I read that
before I don't remember everything else
about it but I know I read it before
well this way I really find that my
knowledge builds as I find references I
am immediately there looking at the
references um the other thing you can do
is that as you start reading the paper
as you can see my
my notes and highlights are saved and
they're also duplicated on my mobile
devices than my other computers and
they're all synced up it's really cool
so talking about archive is a great time
to answer a question we had earlier
about how do you find papers so the vast
vast vast majority of deep learning
papers
get put up on archive.org before a long
long long time before they're in any
journal or conference so if you wait
until they're in a conference
proceedings you're like many many months
or maybe even a year behind so pretty
much everybody uses archive you can go
to the AI section of archiving kind of
see what's there but that's not really
what anybody does and what everybody
does instead is use something well by
far my favorite is archived sanity
you know I attend
preserver
and this is something that the wonderful
Andre Qaddafi built and what it lets you
do is to create a library of articles
that somebody tells you to read or that
you're interested in or you come across
and as you create that library by
clicking this little Save button and it
didn't recommend more papers like it or
even once you start reading a paper you
go show similar and it will then show
you other papers that are similar to
this paper it seems to do a pretty damn
good job of it so you can really explore
and get lost in that whole area so
that's one great way to do it and then
as you do that you'll find that if you
go to
[Music]
five
one of the buttons that it has is a
bookmark parental a button so like even
for the abstract here then straight into
your library and this to me like that
men's lay it's all there and then you
can put things into
folders though the different parts of
the course they've created folders for
them and kind of keep track of what I'm
reading that way a good little trick to
know about archives org is that the
you often want to know where it's from
and if you go to the first page on the
left hand side you can see the date here
and another cool tip is that the file
name the first four digits are the year
and month well there's a couple of any
little tips as well as our clothes
remedy another really great place for
finding papers is Twitter now if you
haven't really used twitter before or
haven't going to use Twitter for this
purpose before it's hard to know where
to start
[Music]
so I try to make things easy for people
by favoriting lots of the interesting
deep learning papers that I come across
so if you go to Jeremy P Howard's page
and click on likes
you'll find that there is a thousand
links to papers here and as you can see
it is generally a few everyday that's
useful for a number of reasons one is to
get some ideas papers to read but
perhaps more importantly is to see who's
posting these calling right and then you
can follow them as well if you're coming
through that box that gentleman
the black yeah just speak okay
it's not question is just just
information about archive that is
someone who has built a skill on Amazon
Alexa I'm actually by asking Alexa to
give most recent paper from archive and
actually she is abstract for you and you
can filter the post you know okay every
paper every thank you
okay the other place which I find
extremely helpful is the reddit machine
learning
again there's a lot left goes through
Reddit than goes through Twitter but
generally like the really interesting
thing tend to turn up here and you can
often see kind of citizens of it so for
example there was a great discussion of
hi torch versus gentle flow in the last
day or two and so there's a couple of
good places to get data
anything I missed Rachel
I think that's good I have them two
questions on the image stuff when you go
back to okay I'm ready
so one of them was SP at Christmas is
using something like this yeah Christmas
using executives and the other is is it
better to calculate s content for a
higher layer for vgg and use a lower
layer for f-style since the higher layer
of abstracts are captured in higher
layer and the lower layer captures
textures probably let's try it shall we
and we haven't alleged that f-style yet
so we're just going to look at if
content at this okay
so custom or links to some things you
can look at here in the
um
[Music]
so the data is linked to in the lesson
thread on the forum I've just grabbed a
random sample of about 20,000 image snap
images and I've also put them into big
holes arrays so you can set up your ants
appropriately I haven't given you this
pickle you can figure out how to get the
filenames easily enough so I'm not going
to do everything for you
now I've grabbed a little one of those
pictures thank you for the person who's
showing all the other stuff to dip
install that's very thoughtful
so this is going to be our content image
so given that we're using vgg as per
usual we're going to have to subtract
out the mean pixel value from image net
and reverse the channel order because of
course that's what the original vgg
authors did so we're going to create an
array from an image by just running it
through that pre-processing fashion
later on we're going to be running
stream through a network and generating
images both generated images we're going
to have to add back on that mean and
undo that reordering so this is what
this e processing function is going to
be poor
and now I've kind of hand waved over
these these functions before and how
they work but I'm going to stop hand
waving for a moment is actually quite
interesting and have you ever thought
about how is it that we're able to check
X which is a four-dimensional sensor
batch size by hyped by rivers by
channels notice this is not the same as
ten saffiano the yellow with batch size
by channels by height by wigs so we're
not doing that anymore
now at a more natural route batch size
by hypo with a chance taking a four
dimensional tensor and we're subtracting
from it a vector
and how are we doing that how is that
making that work and the way of speaking
that work is because it's doing
something called broadcasting and
broadcasting refers to any kind of
operation where you have arrays tensors
of different dimensions and you do
operations element-wise operations on
two tenses of different dimensions and
and kind of how does that work
so this idea actually goes back through
the early 1960 to an amazing programming
language called APL APL stand for a
programming language APL was written by
an extraordinary person called Kenneth
Iverson originally APL was a paper
describing a new mathematical notation
and this new mathematical notation was
designed to be more flexible and far
more precise than traditional
mathematical notation and he then went
on to create a programming language to
implement this mathematical notation but
APL refers to the notation which she
described as notation as a tool for
thought so he really unlike the
tensorflow authors understood the
importance of a good API right it
recognized that the mathematical
notation can change how you think about
math and so he created a notation which
is incredibly Express it's incredibly
expressive and it's fun now have gone on
to carry the torch and he now continues
to support a direct descendant of APL
which is called Jay and so if you ever
want to find I think is the most elegant
programming language in the world you
can go to J software con and check this
out now how many of you here have used a
regular expression okay how many of you
the first time you look for complex
regular expression thought that is
totally intuitive
okay you will feel the same way about
Jane the first time that you look at a
piece of Jay you'll go what bloody hum
because it's even more expressive and a
much older language than regular
expressions here's an example of a line
of Jane but what's going on here is that
this is the language which edit art
almost never requires you to write a
single loop because it does everything
with multi-dimensional chances and
broadcasting so everything within a one
of upstairs broadcasting is a very plain
Richards simplify ratified version of
what APL created in the led which is not
to say anything rude about pythons
implementation it's one of the best but
Jay and APL totally blow it away and so
that's if you want to really expand your
brain and have fun check out okay in the
meantime and what does Paris slash key
on o / tensorflow broadcasting look like
but let's look at some examples right so
here we have I like them to import AI
and world in our music oh it's from
Rachel interracial they're excellent um
here is a vector of one dimensional
tensor - a scaler
okay that makes perfect sense that you
can subtract the scaler for another
one-dimensional tender okay but what is
it actually doing what it's actually
doing is taking this too and it's
replicating it three time for the sexing
element-wise one two three - two - two
it is broadcasted the scalar is
broadcast to the scalar across the three
element better on - Ettore so here's our
first example look forecasting
so in general broadcasting
has a very specific set of rules which
is this you can take two tenses and you
first of all check the shorter tenth of
a tensor with less dimensions and
prepend unit axes to the firm but I mean
when I take prepend unit axis is the
example of pretending prepending unit
active take the vector 2 3 and pre 10
free unit axes on the front it is now a
four dimensional cancer of shape 1 1 1 2
so if you turn a roll into a column
you're adding one unit masses if you're
then turning it into a single slice
you're adding another unit asset so you
can always make something is where
higher dimensionality by adding unit
acting so when you broadcast it takes
the thing with west active just left
mentions and adds pre cleanse unit
access to the phone and then what it
does is it says so let's take the first
example it's taken this thing which has
no axes as a scalar and turns it into a
vector of length well
and then what it does is it finds
anything which is at length 1 and
duplicate it enough times so that it
matches the other thing so here we have
something which is a four dimensional
tensor of size 5 1 3 2 right so it's got
two columns three rows one slice and
five tubes coming and then we're going
to subtract from it a vector of length 2
so remember from our definition it's
then going to automatically reshape this
by prepending unit axes interrupt the
same length and then it's going to copy
this thing three times this thing one
time and this thing five times so the
shape
is five one three two that's going to
subtract this vector from every row
every slice every cube
so you can play around with these for
broadcasting examples and later I had to
get a real feel for how to make
broadcasting work for you so in this
case we were able to take a four
dimensional sensor and subtract from it
a three dimensional vector
knowing that it is going to copy that
three dimensional vector channel to
every row every column to every batch
it's really and it's like it's just done
what we mean okay it subtracted the mean
average of the channels from all of the
images the way we wanted it to but it's
been amazing how often I've taken code
that I've downloaded off the internet
and made it often ten or twenty times
smaller in terms of lines of code just
by using what the broadcasting and the
reason I'm talking about this now is
because we're going to be using this a
lot right play with it and as I say if
you really want to have fun play with it
and Jay
okay
was a diversion that it's one that's
going to be important throughout it okay
so we've now basically got the data that
we want
[Music]
next thing we need is a BJJ model
here's the thing though when we're doing
generative models we want to be very
careful of throwing away information and
one of the main ways to throw away
information is to use max tooling when
you use max pooling that they - comma -
max falling you're throwing away 3/4 of
the previous layer and just keeping the
highest one in generative models when
you use something like max pooling you
make it very hard to undo that and get
back the original data so if we were to
use max pooling with this idea of our s
content right and we say oh what if the
fourth layer of activations look like if
we've used max pooling then we don't
really know what 3/4 of data will player
slightly better is to use average
pooling that if max pooling at least
with average pooling we're using all of
the data to create an average we're
still kind of thrown away recorded loved
it at least have all been incorporated
into calculating the average so the only
thing I did to turn zgg 16 into vgg 16
average just to do a search in replace
in that file from max pooling - Arabs or
and it's just going to give us some
slightly smoother slightly nicer results
and you're going to see this a lot with
generative models we do little twigs
just to try to make is to try to lose as
little information okay you can just
think of this as bgg 16
shouldn't we use something like ResNet
instead of bgg since the residual blocks
carry more context um we'll look at
using ResNet over the coming weeks it's
it's a lot harder to use Reds net for
anything beyond kind of basic
classification pictures or for a number
of reasons one is that just the
structure of ResNet blocks is much more
complex so if you're not careful you're
going to end up picking something that's
on one of those like little arms of the
rest net rather than one of the additive
edges of the rest net and it's kind of
not going to give you any meaningful
information you also have to be careful
because the resident blocks most of the
time are just slightly fine-tuning their
previous block in other adding the
residuals it's not really adding new
types of information so
honestly the truth is I haven't seen any
good research at all about how to use or
where to use resonate or inception
architectures for things like generative
models or for transfer learning or
anything like that so we're going to be
trying to look at some of that stuff in
this course but it's far from
straightforward
two more questions and should we put in
batch normalization
um
[Music]
so in hidden thought one of the cause I
never actually added batch norm to the
convolutional part of the model so that
kind of irrelevant because we're not
using a fully connected layer more
generally is batch normal helpful
generative models I'm not sure that we
have a great answer to that Hey well the
pre-trained weights change if we're
using average pooling instead of max
pool yeah that's a great question
[Music]
the pre-trained weights
then clearly the optimal weights would
change but having said that it's still
going to do a reasonable job without
tweaking the weights because the
relationships between the activations
isn't going to change so again this
would be an interesting thing to try if
you want to download image net and try
fine-tuning it with average pooling see
if you can actually see a difference in
the output or not not something I've
tried it ok so here is the output tensor
of one of the late players of BT g60
so the the way that if you remember
there are different blocks of H a G
where there's a number of 3 by 3 columns
in a row and then there's a polling
layer and then there's another block the
3 by 3 common Apollinaire so this is the
last block of the comp players and this
is the first column of that block so
this is maybe like the third last layer
of the convolutional section of vgg so
this is kind of like quite receptive
field very kind of complex concepts
being captured and at this late stage so
what
going to do is we need to create our
target so for our crowd bird
when we put that bird through dgg what
is the value of that layers activations
so what other things that the gesture to
revise was the stuff from the Karis FAQ
about how to get layer outputs one
simple way to do that is to create a new
model which checks our models input as
input and instead of creating using the
final output as output we can use this
layer as output but this is now a model
which when we call dot predict it will
return this set of activation all right
sewed up all we've done here
now we're going to be using this inside
inside the GPU we're going to be using
this at the target
so to give us something which is going
to live in the GPU a and B we can use
symbolically in a computation graph B we
wrap it with K dot variable so to remind
you K so whatever clear up in the docs
they use the care of back end module
they always call it capital K I don't
know what so k refers to the API that
kiosk provides which finds a way of
talking to either CRO or tensorflow with
the same API that so both Theano intend
to flow hyper-competitive variables and
placeholders and that functions
detection functions and softmax
activation and so forth and so this K
dot module is where all of those
functions live but this is just a way of
creating a variable which is using Giano
okay Theano variable for using
tensorflow accredited to flow through
and where possible I'm trying to use
this rather than tensorflow directly but
I could have absolutely have said the F
variable and it would work just as well
because we're using the temp to plug
back in okay so this is now created a
symbolic variable that contains the
activations of block five on one
so what we now want to do is to create a
degenerative image which we're going to
use FGD to gradually make the
activations of that image look more and
more like it's variable so how are we
going to do that let's just skip over to
our to for a moment and think about them
impedance so we're going to need to
define a loss function and the loss
function is just the mean squared error
between two things one thing is of
course that target that thing we just
created which is the value of our our
our layer using the third image so we
use the third image red okay so that's
our target and then what are we going to
get close to that but what we want to
get close to that is
whatever the value is of that layer at
the moment so what is layer equal the
layer is just
a symbolic object this state there's
nothing in it so we're going to have to
feed it with data later
so we can so remember this is kind of
the interesting way you define
computation graphs with tensor flow and
theano is like you define it with these
symbolic thing now and you feed it with
data later we've got the symbolic thing
called layer and we can't actually
calculate this again so this stage this
is just a computation graph we're
building now of course anytime you have
a computation graph we can get its
gradients
that's a given I should read it the
question for readability can you scroll
down when you're going over code snippet
so that they're centered yeah
thank you
okay so now that we have a computation
graph that calculates the loss function
we're interested in this is this is f
content if we're going to try to
optimize our generative image we're
going to need to know the gradients
alright so here we can get the gradients
and again we use K dot gradient rather
than in terms of flow gradients or the
are no gradient just so that it's we can
use it with any back-end we like see so
the things that the function we're
trying to get gradients on is the loss
function which we just calculated and
then we want it with respect to not some
ways that with respect to the input
that's a model right so this is the
thing that we want to change is the
input to the model so as to minimize our
loss and so they're the gradients
so now that we've done that we can go
ahead and create our function and so the
input to the function is just modeled or
input and the output to the function
will be the loss and the gradients so
that's nearly everything we need the
last step we need to do is to actually
run an optimizer now normally when we
run an optimizer where you use some kind
of SGD now the s and SGD is both
stochastic in this case there's nothing
stochastic we're not creating lots of
random batches and getting different
gradients every time but why use to
catch the gradient percent when we don't
have a stochastic problem to solve
so in fact there's a much longer history
of optimization methods which are
deterministic going back to Newton's
method which many of you will be
familiar with so the basic idea
I will current cover and the basic idea
of the much faster deterministic
optimization method is that rather than
saying okay where's the gradient which
direction to the goal let's just go a
small little step in that direction
the learning rate and spraying it's more
little step smaller because I have no
idea how far to go
right and it's stochastics are going to
keep changing the next time I log will
be a slightly different direction
instead with a deterministic
optimization we find out which direction
to go
and then we find out what is the optimum
distance to go in that direction and so
if you know this is the direction I want
to go and it looks like this okay then
the way we find the optimum is we go a
small distance then we go twice as far
as that twice as far as that tribe as
far as that and we keep going and chill
the slope changes sign and once the
slope changes sign we know we called
racketing is bracketed the minimum of
that function and then we can use
bisection to find the minimum so now
we've added it we find halfway between
the two okay it's on the left or the
right of that okay halfway between two
of those at the left or the right of
that so we use bracketing and bisection
to find the optimum in that direction
let's call it a line search so all of
these optimization techniques rely on
the basic idea of a line search now once
you've done the mind search you found
the optimizer you found the optimal
value in that direction in our downhill
direction that doesn't necessarily mean
we found the optimal value across our
entire space so what we then do is we
repeat the process find out what the
downhill direction now is line search to
find the optimum in that direction
so the problem with that is that in a
saddle point you will still often find
yourself going backwards and forward in
a rather unfortunate way so the meter or
the faster optimization approaches when
they're going to go in a new direction
that I'll just say which direction is
down they say which direction is the
most downhill but also is the most
different to the previous direction but
one that's called finding a conjugate
direction so the good news is you don't
need to really know any of those details
all you need to know is that there is a
module fold I know
by pi dot optimized and insight fighter
optimized lots of Andy deterministic
optimizes the two most common use
conjugate gradient or eg and BFGS
they differ in the detail of how do they
decide what direction to go in their
switch direction is both the most
downhill and also the most different for
the previous directions we've gone and
the particular version we're going to
use is a limited memory the APS
so the important thing is not how it
works the important thing for asked is
how do we use it
SHN okay
about boss plus grad yes so this is a
this is a an array containing a single
thing which is lost grads is already an
array or a list is a which is a list of
all of the of the lost with respect to
all of the inputs so plus in Python on
to lists simply joins the two lists
together so this is a list containing
the loft and all of the gradients and
someone asked of ant colony optimization
is something that can be sued and colony
optimization lives in the class known as
metaheuristics like genetic algorithms
or simulated annealing it's a wide range
of optimization algorithms that are
designed for very difficult to optimize
functions functions which are extremely
bumpy and so these are techniques or use
a lot of randomization in order to avoid
the bumps in our case we're using mean
square error which is a nice smooth
objective so we can use the much faster
convex optimization
and then that was the next question is
this a non-convex problem or convex
optimization right
so
how do we use one of these optimizes
well basically you provide the name of
the optimizer which in this case is
minimize something using the FPS and you
have to pass it three things a function
which will return the lost value at the
current point
a starting point
and a function which will return the
gradients at the current point
now unfortunately we have a function
which returns the lost and the gradients
together which is not what this one's so
a minor little detail is that we create
a simple little class okay and all this
class does and again the details really
aren't important but all this class does
is that when loss is called they call
that function that we created passing in
the current value of the data it gets
back the loss and the radiance and it
returns the loss later on when the
optimizer asks for the gradient it
returns those gradients that door back
here so all this is doing is it the
little class which allows us to
basically turn a Karass function that
returns the loss from the gradients
together into two function one return
loss one returns the gradients so it's a
pretty minor detail but it's a handy
thing to have in your toolbox because it
means you now have something that can
use deterministic optimizers on Keros
functions so all we do is we live
through a small number of times causing
that calling that optimize each time and
passing in we need to pass in some
starting point so the starting point is
just a random image okay so we just
create a random image and here is what
oh and an image looks like okay so let's
go ahead and run that so we can see the
results actually around this yet
[Music]
a second
okay
none
random image
Oh
okay so you can see you're cutting the
work going along and solving here here's
one I prepared earlier and here at the
end of the 10th iteration is the result
so remember what we did was we started
with this image okay we called an
optimizer which took that image
to optimize this log function
the target was the value of
this layer for a bird image
bring it to was the layer for the
generated image
so we started with this we ran that
optimizer a bunch of times
calculating the gradient of that loss
with respect to the input to the model
the very pixels of the build and after
ten iterations that have turned this
random image into 15 so this is the
thing which optimizes the funds block
five cons one I own and you can see it
still looks like a bird but by this
point it really doesn't care what the
background looks like it cares a lot
what the eye looks like and the deep
looks like in the feathers to apply
because these things are matter to
imagenet to make sure it correctly sees
its bird and if we look at an earlier
layer
let's look at block four on one
you can see it's looking getting the
details more correct so when we do our
artistic style we can choose which layer
will be our F content right and if we
choose an earlier one it's going to give
it less degrees of freedom to look like
a different kind of bird but it's going
to look more like our original bird and
so then here's
a video
showing how that happens there are the N
steps and it's often helpful to be able
to visualize your you know the
iterations if your generators at work so
feel free to borrow it it's very simple
code right you can just use matplotlib
we actually use this in the last club
remember we optimized our linear little
linear optimize that we are animated it
you just have to define a function that
gets called at each step of the
animation and then you can just call
animation animation passing in that
function and that's a nice way that you
can animate your own generators this
question arm where you can care Austin
tensorflow to extract the BG teachers
these are used by Syfy for BFGS right
I'm just the BFGS also run on the GPU no
there's really very little for the BFGS
to do really for an optimizer all of the
work is including the loss function and
the gradients the actual work of like
doing the bisection and doing the
bracketing is it's so trivial that we
you just don't care about that it
doesn't take any time there's a question
about the checkerboard artefact yes
geometric pattern yes appearing yeah
this is actually not a checkerboard
architect exactly
export out effects we will look at later
they look a little bit different now
it's my interpretation mistakes not the
questioners okay yeah
basically the yeah I mean I'm not
exactly sure why this particular item
why this particular kind of that noise
disappeared honestly an interesting
question how is batching work aerial um
it doesn't so there's no fetching stood
where we have a single image which is
being
[Music]
which is being optimized but yeah
there's really no batching yeah well
look at a version which uses a very
different approaching as batching surely
anyone tried something like this by
averaging or combining the activations
of multiple bird images and to create
some kind of prototypical or novel bird
um yeah generative adversarial networks
do something like that but probably not
quite yeah I mean it yeah I'm not sure
maybe not quite where where can people
get the pickle file they don't and you
have to get a list of file names
yourself from the vista file to content
editor
and then just to make sure I understand
this and someone says in this example we
started with a random image but what if
we started with the actual image is the
initial condition we would get the
original image back right I'm gonna
students though yeah yeah I mean I can't
see why I would
that they basically the gradient will be
zero they're interested to find out
where we initialize for the artist
dialing problem
just to follow up we're going to get
there and throw oh there's one more okay
and would it be useful to use a tool
like quiver to figure out which bgg
layer to use this um it's so easy just
to try a few and see what works
okay so we're nearly out of time so
let's um haven't got to as much as I
hope that we're going to finish off this
piece so um we're now going to do F file
now F style is nearly identical all of
the code is nearly identical the only
thing different is a we're going to not
feed in a photo they're going to feed in
a painting and here's a few styles we
could choose from we could do van Gogh
we could do the drawing or we could do
the sense
now so we pick one of those and we
create the style array in the same way
as before sound check it through vgg and
this time though we're going to use
multiple layers so I created a
dictionary from the name of the layer to
it Apple and so we're going to use that
to create an array of a number of the
outputs we're going to grab the first
second and third block app words
[Music]
so we're going to create our target as
before beverage use a different loss
function the loss function is called
spyro watts and just like before it's
going to use the MSE that rather than
just the MSC on the activations
it's the MSC on something called the
gram matrix of the activation so what is
the gray matrix a gram matrix is very
simply the dot product of a matrix with
its own transfer so here it is here dot
product of unmei tricks with if there
are transfers and I just going to divide
it by Kiev Korean average
um so what is this matrix that we're
taking the dot product of it and
transpose
so what it is is that we start with our
image remember the image is height by
width by channel and we change the order
of dimension so it channels by height by
width
and then we do a batch flatten or what
batch flatten does is it takes
everything except the first dimension
and flattens it out into a vector so
this is now going to be a matrix where
the rows the channels and the columns
are a flattened version of the height by
which factor this is Z by H by W the
result of this will be zeros and H times
W columns
so when you take the dot product of
something
with the transpose of itself what you're
basically doing is creating something a
lot like a correlation matrix right
you're saying how much is each row
similar to each other Road
all right so if you think about a you
know you think it was a number of ways
you can think about it like a cosine
cosine is basically just a dot product
you can think of it as a correlation
matrix is basically a normalized version
of this so maybe it's not clear to you
write it down on a piece of paper on the
way home tonight just think about
picking the rows of a matrix and then
flipping it around and you're basically
then turning them into columns and then
you multiply the rows by the columns but
basically the same as taking each row
and comparing it to each other oh that
so that's what this gram matrix is is
it's basically saying for every channel
how similar are its values to each other
channel so if channel number one in the
most part of the image is very similar
to channel 3 and most parts of the image
then 1 comma 3 if this result will be a
higher number so if the kind of a weird
matrix right it basically tells us it's
like a fingerprint of how the channel to
elect or each other in this particular
image or how the filters relate to each
other in a particular layer that this
particular image may be the most
important thing to recognize is that
there is no geometry left here or that
the X and the y coordinates are totally
drawn away like they're actually
flattened down at to this last function
can by by definition in no way at all
contain anything about the content of
the image because it's thrown away all
of the XY information and at all that's
left is some kind of fingerprint of how
the channel selector each other at a
filters relate to each other
so this style loss then says to the two
different images how does these
fingerprints differ how similarity
fingerprints
turns out that if you now do the exact
thing sisters are for using that as our
log function and you run it through a
few iterations
it looks like that
it looks a lot like the original van
Gogh
but without any of the content
so the question is
why the answer is
nobody the fuck not so a paper just came
out two weeks ago called the mystifying
euro style transfer with a mathematical
treatment where they claim to have an
answer to this question but at the point
at which this was created by a year and
a half ago until now no one really knows
why that happens right but the important
thing of the authors of this paper
realized is if we can create a function
that gives you a Content loss and a
function that gives you spiral loss and
you add the two together and optimize
them you can do your style so all I can
assume they don't see how to get in the
paper all I can assume is that they
tried a few different things they knew
that they had to throw away all of the
geometry at the public trial of using
the Toyota Way of geometry at some point
look business I should that's that's it
okay so now that we have this magical
thing there's a symptom
what we have to do is that the two
together right so here's up there it
shall call thoughts
um
[Music]
dial layer to make sure you take the top
5 mil here's our content layout and tech
block for com2 as promised through our
last function and it's going to add the
two together at a loss to all of the
style layers but the consent laws and
you provide the content lost by ten this
is something you can play with right in
the paper you'll see they play with it
but it's like how much they lost this is
how much fun checkmarks gradient
evaluator valvert and error and so other
than the fact that we don't really know
why the stylus works but it does
everything else kind of fits together so
there's the bird as then Gogh is the
bird is the Simpsons and there's the
bird in the style of a barrage
soon and since the publication of that
paper has anyone used any other lost
functions for app style that achieve
similarity yeah so as I mentioned a
difficult weeks ago there was a paper I
put it on the forum that tries to
generalize this class function it turns
out actually that this particular loss
function seems to be about the best that
they can come up with but there you go
so it's 9 o'clock and so we are have run
out of time so we're going to move some
of this lesson to next lesson but to
give you a sense of where we're going to
head what we're going to do is we're
going to take this thing where you have
to optimize every single image
separately and we're going to train the
CNN we're going to train at CNN which
will learn how to turn a picture into a
van Gogh version of that picture that's
that's basically going to be what we're
going to learn that phone and we're also
going to learn about adversarial
networks which is where we're going to
create two networks one will be designed
to generate pictures like this and the
other will be designed to train classify
whether this is a real Simpsons picture
or a fake isn't and then you're through
one generate the other discriminate
generate discrimination and by doing
that we can take any generative model
and make it better by basically having
something else learn to pick the
difference between the real and the fake
and then finally we're going to learn
about a particular thing that came out
three weeks ago called the loss of sine
Gann which is the reason I actually
decided to move us forward
generative adversarial networks
basically didn't work very well at all
until about three weeks ago now that
they do work suddenly there's a shitload
of stuff that nobody's done yet which
you can do the first time so we're going
to look at that next week