okay welcome again everybody so some
really fun stuff appearing on the forums
this week and one of the really great
projects which was created by I believe
our sole Bulgarian participant in the
course Slav even off wrote a great post
about picking an optimizer for style
transfer this post came from a forum
discussion in which I made an offhand
remark about how I didn't I know that in
theory BFGS you know is a deterministic
optimizer you know uses a line search
should approximate the Hessian it ought
to work on this kind of deterministic
problem better but I hadn't tried it
myself and I hadn't seen anybody try it
and so maybe somebody should try it I
don't know if you've noticed but pretty
much every week I say something like
that a number of times and every time I
do I'm always hoping that somebody might
go oh I wonder as well and so slobs
you've wonder and so he posted a really
interesting uh blog posts about about
that exact question and I was thrilled
to see that the blog post got a lot of a
lot of pick up on the machine learning
reddit it got fifty five uploads which
for that subreddit is put it in second
place on the front page it also got
picked up by the wild ml mailing list
weekly summary of interesting things in
AI as the second post that was looted so
that was a that was great for those of
you that have looked at it and kind of
wondered okay what is it about this post
that causes it to get noticed for us
other ones don't I mean I don't I'm not
sure I know the secret but when I as
soon as I read it I kind of thought okay
I think a little bit we're going to read
this it gives some background you know
like it assumes an intelligent reader
that it assumes that elephant reader who
doesn't necessarily know all about this
so you know something like you guys six
months ago
and so it describes like this is what it
is and you know this is where this kind
of thing is used and get some examples
and then goes ahead and shows talks
about you know sets up the question of
different optimization algorithms and
then shows lots of examples of those
learning curves as well as pictures a
commodity durman's and I think hopefully
it's been a great experience just loud
as well because in the reddit thread
there's you know all kinds of folks
pointing out you know other things that
he could try questions that were quite
clear and so now this whole kind of
actually kind of summarized in that
thread a kind of list of things that
perhaps could be done next so I'm going
to open up a whole interesting question
another post which I not even sure it's
officially posted yet I got the early
bird version from Brad is this crazy
thing here is Kanye drawn using a brush
of Captain jean-luc Picard
in case you wondering is that really him
I will show you a zoomed in version it
really is John look at the cards and
this is a really interesting idea
because he points out that generally
speaking when you try to use a non
artwork as your style image it doesn't
actually give very good results there's
another example the non our work does
give the response
it's kind of interesting but it's not
quite what I was looking for that if you
tile it you totally get it right
so it's Kanye using a Nintendo and
controller brush so then he tried out
this film look the card and got okay
results and kind of realized that
actually the size of the texture is
pretty critical and I've never seen
anybody do this before so I think I
think when this image gets shared on
Twitter it's gonna go everywhere it's
just the freakiest thing trick is good
so I'm you know I think I warned you
guys about your project when I first
mentioned them as being something it's
very easy to overshoot a little bit and
spend weeks and weeks talking about what
you're eventually going to do you've had
you know a couple of weeks really it
would have been nice to have something
done by now right rather than spending a
couple of weeks wondering about what to
do so if your team string of its low
agree on something to start working on
something yourself or you know as a team
just fix something that you can do by
next Monday and right up it you know
something brings about it so for example
if you're thinking okay we went through
the 1 million dollar data science Bowl
that's fine you're not going to finish
it by Monday but maybe by Monday you
could have written a blog post
introducing you know what you can learn
in a week about medical imaging oh it
turns out to use something called daikon
here are the plates and daikon libraries
and we try to use them and these are the
things they've got it's kind of confused
and these are the ways that we solve
them and here's a place a notebook which
shows you some of the main ways you can
look at these daikon for instance so you
know split up your project into little
pieces it's like when you enter a
careful composition I always tell people
submit every single day and try and put
in at least half an hour a day to make
it slightly better than yesterday so how
do you put in the first day submission
so what I always do on the first day is
to submit the benchmark script you know
which is generally like all zeroes and
then the next day I try to improve it so
I'll put in like all 0.5 the next day
I'll try to improve it I'll be like ok
with the average for cats the aperture
dogs they'll submit that and if you do
that every day for 90 days
you'll be amazed at how much you can
achieve where else if you wait 2 months
and spend all that time reading papers
and theorizing and thinking about the
best possible approach you'll discover
that you don't get any any submissions
it or you finally get your perfect
submission in and it because terribly
and now you don't have time to make it
better so
I think those tips equally useful for
cable competitions as well as their
making sure that at the end of this part
of the course you have something that
you're you know that you're proud of
something that you feel you you did a
good job in you know small amount of
time if you try and publish something
every week on the same kind of topic
you'll be able to keep going further and
further on that thing I don't know what
slavs plans are but maybe he'll next
week he'll follow up on some of the
interesting research angle to came up
and read it or maybe Brad will follow up
on some of his additional ideas from his
post okay
as a Lexington wickiup already which has
the notebooks and just do a kid pool one
we get on the github repo to get the
nonce up-to-date on time another thing
that I wanted to point out is that and
in study group so we've been having
study groups each each Friday here and I
know some of you have had to study
groups elsewhere around the Bay Area
what if you asked me I don't understand
this grand metric stuff I don't get it
what's what's going on I almost had the
symbol that is an a mask but what's
going on and I said maybe if you had a
spreadsheet it would all make sense
here's kind of like I'm doing it in
Python you know a nice to puzzler maybe
if you hit a spreadsheet it would all
make sense it's like maybe I'll create a
spreadsheet yes do that and 20 minutes
later I turn to him and I said so how do
you feel about Graham matrices now and
he goes I totally understand them and I
looked over and he had created a
spreadsheet this is a spreadsheet he
created it it's a very simple
spreadsheet where it's like here's an
image where the pixels just like 1 minus
1 or 0 it has two filters that are
either 1 or minus 1
he had the flattened convolutions next
to each other and then he's created the
little dot product matrix and so I
haven't been doing so much Excel stuff
myself and but you know I think you
learn a lot more by trying it yourself
and particularly if you try it yourself
and can't figure out how to do it in
Excel then we have firms
I love itself so if you ask me questions
that Excel I will have a great time
so I'm not going to put that one on the
forum for now so I think it's so easy to
create you get so much more out of doing
it yourself for anybody who's still not
quite understanding what grand matrices
all right so last week
[Music]
we talked about the idea of
loading with larger data centers and our
goal was to try and replicate the
devised paper and remind you the devised
paper is the one where we to a regular
CNN but the thing that we're trying to
predict is not a one hot encoding of the
category but it's the word vector for
the category yes so it's a it's an
interesting problem but one of the
things interesting about it is is just
okay we have to use all of imagenet
which has its own challenges so last
week we got to the point where we had
created the word vectors and remember
the word vectors we then had to like map
them to imagenet categories there are
thousand imagenet categories so we had
to create the work vector V each one we
didn't quite get all of them to match
it's something like two thirds of the
match so we're working on like two
thirds of imagenet we've got as far as
reading all the bio names the imagenet
and we then we're going to resize our
images so I'm going to resize all of our
images to 224 by 224 it's I think it's a
good idea to do some of this
pre-processing up front something that
tends to flow and apply towards both to
and care us recently started doing is
that if you use a generator it actually
does the image pre-processing in a
number of separate threads in parallel
behind the scenes and so some of this is
a little less important than it was six
months ago when clear us didn't do that
you know it used to be that we had to
spend a long time waiting for our data
to get processed before it could get
into the into the CNN um having said
that
actually image resizing when you've got
large JPEGs just reading them off the
hard disk and resizing them can take
quite a long time so I always like to
put it in to do all that resizing up
front and end up with something within a
nice convenient vehicle to read amongst
other things it means that unless you
have enough money to have a huge nvme or
SSD drive which you can put the entirety
of image net on you probably have your
big data sets on like some kind of
pretty slow spinning disk or slow rate
array so one of the nice things about
doing the resizing first is that it
makes it a lot smaller and you probably
can then fit it on your SSD there's lots
of reasons that I think this is good so
so I'm going to resize all of the image
net images put them in a big holes array
on my SSD right so here's the path and
the deep past is the past
- my fast SSD mount point and we talked
briefly about it all there are these the
things actually do the resizing and
we're going to do a different kind of
resizing in the past we've done the same
kind of resizing the Charis does which
is to add a black border like if you
start with something that's not square
you make it square you resize the
largest access to be the size of your
square which means you're left with a
black border re was concerned that any
model where you have that is going to
have to like learn to model the black
border a and B that you're kind of
throwing away information you know
you're not using the full size of the
image and indeed every other library or
pretty much paper I've seen uses a
different approach which is to resize
the smaller side of the image to the
square and now the big that now the
larger size is now too big for your
square so you crop off the top and
bottom or crop off the left and right so
this is called center cropping
Center cropping approach so I understand
continuing to learn with Google and you
said after that your time waiting on
data those scenes ledger
I'm through here this okay that's true
what you're doing is throwing away
you're throwing away compute like like
with the one where you do send to crop
you have a complete 224 thing full of
meaningful pixels for us with a black
border you have like a 180 by 224 bit is
meaningful pixels and a whole bunch of
like okay yeah that can be a problem so
it works well for image net because
image net things are generally somewhat
centered you may need to do some kind of
initial set to do like a hate map or
something like to get in lesson seven to
figure out roughly where the thing is
before you decide where to send to the
crop so these things are all compromises
but I've got to say since I switched to
using this approach I feel like my
models are trained a lot faster and
giving better results and certainly the
super resolution okay now I said last
week that we are going to start looking
at parallel processing and if you're
wondering about last week's homework
we're going to get there but some of the
techniques were about to learn we're
going to use to do last week so I'm
working even better so but don't worry
so what I want to do is I want to have
I've got a a CPU with something like 10
cores on it and then each of those calls
have hyper threading so it means each of
those calls can do kind of two things at
once
so I really want to be able to you know
have a couple of dozen processes going
on each one resizing an image that's
called parallel processing okay and just
to remind you this is as opposed to
vectorization or SIMD which is where a
single thread operates on a bunch of
things at a time and so we learnt that
to get SSD working you just have to
install
hello SIMD and the
this happened in six hundred percents
data I tried it it works now we're going
to as well as a 600 percent speed-up
also get another and on 20x speed up by
doing parallel processing
the basic approach to parallel
processing in Python 3 is to set up
something called either a process pool
or a thread pool so the idea here is
that we've got a number of little
programs running threads or processes
and when we set up that pool we say how
many of those little programs do we want
to fire up ok and then what we do is we
say ok now I want you to use all of
their code workers I want you to use all
of those workers to do some thing right
and the easiest way to do is being
inside some tree is to use Matt a lot of
you probably used how many of you have
used Matt before okay so for those you
who haven't maps is a very common
functional programming construct that's
found its way into lots of other
languages which simply says look through
a collection and call a function on
everything in that collection and return
a new collection which is the result of
calling that function on that thing in
our case the function is resized and the
collection is in Internet images well in
fact the collection is a bunch of
numbers 0 1 2 3 4 and so forth and what
the resize image is going to do is it's
going to open that image of disk access
turning the number 3 into the third
image resize to 224 by 224 and will
return that so the general approach here
this is basically what it looks like to
do parallel processing in Python it may
look a bit weird we're going result
equals exact map and this is a function
I want this is the thing to map over and
then I'm saying for each thing in that
list do something now this might make
you think we'll wait there's nothing in
this list has to have enough memory to
every single resize image and the answer
is no no it doesn't one of the things
that Python 3 uses a lot more is using
these things they're called generators
which is basically it's a something that
looks like a list but it's lazy it only
creates
thing when you ask for it so as I append
each image is going to give me that
image and if this mapping is not yet
finished creating it it'll wait so this
approach looks like it's going to use
heaps of memory but it doesn't it uses
only the minimum amount of memory
necessary and it does everything in
parallel
so resize image
is something which is going to open up
the image it's going to turn it into an
umpire ray and then it's going to resize
it okay and so then the resize of the
center cropping we just mentioned and
then after it's resize it's going to get
appended what is append image to so this
is a bit weird what's going on here what
it does is it says is it's going to
actually take it into what we call a
pre-allocated array so we're learning a
lot of computer science concepts here
anybody that's done computer science
before which familiar with all of this
already if you haven't you probably
won't but it's important to know that
the slowest thing in your computer
generally speaking is allocating memory
it's finding some memory it's reading
stuff from that memories writing to that
memory and let's suppose it's like cache
or something
and generally speaking if you like
create lots and lots of arrays and then
throw them away again
that's likely to be really really slow
and so what I wanted to do was to create
a single 224 by 224 array which is going
to contain my resize image and then I'm
going to append that to my big holes
tensor so but where you do that in
Python it's it's wonderfully easy you
can create a variable from this thing
called threading local now DL is now
just a it's basically something that
looks a bit like a dictionary it's a
very special kind of dictionary it's
going to create a separate copy of it
for every thread or process so normally
when you've got lots of things happening
at once it's going to be a real pain
because if two things try to use it at
the same time you get
bad results or even crashes but if you
allocate a variable like this it
automatically creates a separate copy
and every threat and you don't have to
worry about locks you don't have to
worry about race conditions whatever
so once I've created this special
threading local variable I then create a
safe folder inside it which is just an
array of zeros of size 224 by 224 by 3
and so then later on I create my big
holes array which is where I'm going to
put everything eventually and to append
the image i graph the bit of the image
that I want and I put it into that
pre-allocated that pre-allocated threads
local variable and then I can let my big
holes array so there's lots of detail
here in terms of lag using parallel
processing effectively I wanted to kind
of briefly mention it not because I
think somebody who hasn't thirty
computer science is now going to go OK I
totally understood all that but to give
you some of the things to like search
for and learn about over the next week
if you haven't done any parallel
programming before you're going to need
to understand regular storage and race
conditions
I'm sorry I'm not the young great boss
so somebody who knows their person and
person is looking for the global
interpreter lock which is one of the
many thoughtful things that open theirs
most of all in which is that in theory
true things can't happen at the same
time because Tyson wasn't really written
in a read safe way the good news is that
a lot of libraries are written in a
thread safe way so if you're using a
library where most of its workers the
emergency as is the case with pillow
simd actually you don't have to worry
about that and I can prove it to you
even if they drew a little picture here
is the result right of serial versus
parallel now the cereal without SIMD
version is six times bigger than this
right so the kind of default place and
code you would have written maybe before
today's course would have been 120
seconds process 2,000 images with SIMD
at 25 seconds
with the protest pool at eight seconds
for three workers for six workers it's
five seconds so on and so forth the
thread pool is even better 3.6 seconds
to 12 workers 3.2 seconds at 16 workers
now your mileage will vary depending on
what CPU you have given the that's
probably quite a lot of you are using
the p2s tool unless you've got your deep
learning box up and running you'll have
the same performance as other people
using the t2 but you should try
something like this right which is to
try different numbers of workers and see
what's the optimal for that particular
CPU and now once you've done that you
know once I went beyond 16 I didn't
really get improvements so I know that
on that computer a thread pool of size
16 is a pretty good choice and as you
can see once you get into the right
general vicinity it doesn't vary too
much and so as long as you're roughly
okay there's behind to Rachel
you
so that's the general approach here is
run through something in parallel each
time appender to my big holes array and
at the end of that I've got a big holes
array which I can use again and again so
I don't rerun that code very often
anymore I've got all of the image net
resized into each of 72 by 72 to 24 and
to 88 so I just and I give them
different names and I just use them for
our image of serving so the food they
are consuming recycle some number and
we'll just squish the title to square I
mean I usually will distort it but Brad
hopefuls right in fact I think that's
what Paris does nothing about helping it
squishes
yeah I okay so here's one of these
things I'm not quite sure right my guess
was that I don't think it's a good idea
because you're now going to have dogs of
various different squish levels and
you'll see an N is going to have to
learn that thing right it's going to
have it's got another type of you know
symmetry to learn about you know level
of squishiness wealth if we keep
everything the same kind of aspect ratio
I think it's going to be easier to learn
so we'll get better results with a C+
training yeah I that's my theory and I'd
be fascinated for somebody to do a
really in-depth analysis of like black
borders versus center cropping versus
squishing good image - okay so for now
we can just open the big holes array and
there we go so we're now ready to create
our model and run through this pretty
quickly because most of its pretty
boring the basic idea here is that we
need to create an array of labels which
are called vexed which contains for
every image in my in my vehicles array
needs to contain the word vector but
then the target word vector for that
image
and just remind you last week we
randomly ordered the file ends so this
they called array is in random order
okay so we've got our labels which is
the work vectors for every image we need
to do our normal pre-processing this is
a handy way to pre-process in the new
version of chaos we're using the normal
Clara ResNet model the one that comes in
Kherson applications it doesn't do the
pre-processing for you but if you create
a lambda layer it does the
pre-processing and you can use that
lambda layer as the input tensor so this
whole thing now we'll do the
pre-processing automatically without you
having to worry about it so that's a
good little trick I'm not sure it's
quite as neat as what we did in part one
where we put it in the model itself but
at least this way we don't have to
maintain a whole separate version of all
of the models so that's kind of what I'm
doing nowadays
all right
when you're working on really big
datasets you don't want to process
things any more than necessary and any
more time necessary
I know ahead of time but I'm going to
want to do some fine-tuning so what I
decided to do was I decided you know
this is the particular layer where I'm
going to do my fine-tuning so I decided
to first of all create a model which
started at the input and went as far as
this layer and so my first step was to
create that model and save the results
of that and then I was you know the next
step will be to take that intermediate
step and take it to the next stage I
would have fine-tuned to and save that
so it's a little shortcut there's a
couple of really important intricacies
to be aware of here though the first one
is
you'll notice that ResNet and inception
are not used very often to transfer
learning and again this is something
which I've not seen studies and I
actually think it's a really important
thing to study is which of these things
work best transfer learning but I think
one of the difficulties is just resonate
and inception the harder and the reason
they're harder is that if you look at
resinate you've got lots and lots of
layers which make no sense on their own
get over inception because if I keep on
splitting into two bits and then merging
again splitting into two bits and
noticing
so what I did was I looked in at the
care our source code to kind of find out
okay how is each block named and because
what I wanted to do was to say alright
we've got you know a resident block
we've just had a merge okay and then it
goes out it does a couple of
convolutions and then it comes back and
does an addition right and basically I
want to get one of these I want to grab
one of these unfortunately for some
reason chaos does not name these merge
cells so what I had to do was get the
next cell and then go back by one and so
it kind of shows you how little people
have been working with ResNet with
transfer learning is it like literally
the only bit of it the next chance to
transfer learn from a nameless in one of
the most popular probably the most
popular thing for transfer learning
isostatic care us okay there's a second
complexity when working with ResNet we
haven't discussed this much but renting
it actually has two kinds of ResNet
blocks while it is this kind which is an
identity block
and the second time is a redneck
convolution block
and which I also call a bottleneck block
and what this is is it's pretty similar
you know what one thing that's going up
through a couple of convolutions and
then goes and gets added together but
the other side is not an identity the
other side is a single convolution
and in ResNet they throw in one of these
every half a dozen blocks or so why is
that well the reason is that if you only
have identity blocks and all it can
really do is to continually fine-tune
where it's at so far you know we've
learned quite a few times now that these
identity blocks basically they map to
the residual so they keep trying to kind
of fine tune the types of features that
we have so far
where else these bottlenecks blocks
actually force it from time to time to
kind of create a whole different types
of features and because there is no
identity passed through here and the
shortest path still goes through a
single convolution so when you think
about transfer learning from ResNet you
kind of need to think about ok should I
transfer learn from identity blocks
before or after or from a bottleneck
block before or after again I don't
think anybody's studied this or at least
I haven't seen anybody write it down
I've played around a little bit and I'm
not sure I have a
totally decisive suggestion for you
clearly my guess is that the best point
to grab in ResNet is the block at the
end of the blocks immediately before a
bottle net block and the reason for that
is that at that level of kind of but at
that level of receptive field obviously
because each bottleneck block is
changing the receptive field so that
level of receptive field and at that
level of kind of semantic complexity
this is the most sophisticated version
of it because it's been through a whole
bunch of identity blocks to get there
that gradually finds you in fine tune
fine tune button times you and fine tune
fine tune bottlenecks so my belief is
that you want to get just before that
bottleneck is the best place to transfer
learning from so that's what it is this
is the spot just before the last
bottleneck layer in ResNet so it's
pretty late and so as we know very well
from plat one with transfer learning
when you're doing something which is not
too different and in this case we're
switching from one fighting coding to
work vectors which is not too different
you probably don't want to transfer
learn from too early okay so that's why
I've picked this fairly late stage which
is the just before the final bottleneck
block
okay so the second complexity here is
that this bottleneck block has these
dimensions the output is 14 by 14 by 102
4 so we have about a million images so a
million by 14 by 14 by 102 4 is more
than I wanted to deal with
so I did something very simple which was
I popped in one more layer after this
which is an average cooling layer seven
by seven so that's going to take my 14
by 14 output and turn it into a two by
two output all right so let's say one of
those activations was looking for thirds
eyeballs right then it's saying in each
of the 14 by 14 spots
how likely is that that this is a bird's
eye ball and so after this it's now
seeing in each of these four spots on
average how much were those cells
looking like bird's eye balls
this is losing information if I had a
bigger SSD I had more time I wouldn't
have done this but it's a good trick
right when you're working with these
fully convolutional architectures you
can pop an average cooling layer
anywhere and decrease the resolution to
something that you feel like you can
deal with so in this case this was my
petition with to go to Dubai to buy one
or two four and we talked about by means
of merge operation into many more
complex
we have our assignments which which is
basically that the merge with the thing
which does the plus yet that's the trick
to making it into a ResNet block is
having the addition of the identity with
the result when you have accomplished
so uh recently I was trying to go from
many filters so he kind of stopped going
down finding the time Jennifer yeah
they're good best practice ongoing
problem appeal I 512 filters down to
labs just as simple as doing
accomplishing with less filters yeah
there's not exactly a as I exactly that
after selects but and I think every
single successful architecture did she's
on in class about that every one of them
eventually had to end up with you know a
thousand categories if it's an edge or
trade channels of most 255 continuous if
it's generative so the best things you
can really do is legitimate kind of move
into successful exceptions I don't think
it's all completed kind of a last week
where maybe I'll be looking at images I
admitted briefly next week open with a
quick run through some of the things
that you could go back to a lot more a
monofin is going to be a paper attach a
different papers which have like best
practices you know really nice kind of
descriptions we did need hundreds of
things these monitor results but all
this stuff it's still pretty young
a biro
good question so from a society which
institutions for interment support and
that ended up being a bit because there
again so complex life beauty even worse
the native community ministry yes so
compressed and uncompressed it's like a
couple hundred gig yeah but you won't
you feel others injuries like why not
going to learn it memory you know states
all you describe employees a little
we're getting there yeah so so that's
exactly the right segue I was looking
for so thank you so what we're going to
do now is we want to run this model we
just built just just called basically
dot project on it and save the
predictions and the problem is that the
size of those predictions is going to be
bigger than the amount of RAM I have so
I need to do with a batch at a time and
save it a batch of times they've got a
million things each one with this many
activations so and this was going to
happen quite often right you're either
working on a smaller computer or you're
working with a bigger data set or you're
working with the data set where you're
using a larger number of activations
this is actually very easy to handle you
just create your big holes array where
you're going to store it and then all I
do is I go through from 0 to the length
of my array my saucer a a batch at a
time right so this is creating the
numbers 0 0 plus 128 128 plus 128 so on
and so forth and then I take the slice
with my source array from originally 0
to 128 and 128 256 and so forth so this
is now going to contain a slice of my
source equals array
and then well actually this is going to
create a generator which is going to
have all of those slices and of course
being a generator it's going to be lazy
so I can then enumerate through each of
those slices and I can depend my big
holes array the result of predicting
just on that one batch okay
so you've seen like predict and evaluate
and and fit and so forth and the
generator versions also in carest is
generally an on batch version so there's
a train on batch and they predict on
batch and what these do is they
basically they have no smarts to them at
all this is like the most basic thing so
this is just going to take whatever you
give it and call predict on this thing
it won't
shuffle that they want that shirt it's
just going to throw it directly into the
computation graph got a call predict
adjust this batch of data and then from
time to time I print out how far I've
got just so that I know how I'm going
also from time to time I called flash
that's the thing in big holes that
actually writes it to disk after this
make sure that's continuously written to
disk so this thing doesn't actually take
very long to run and one of the nice
things they can do here is I can do some
data augmentation as well so I've added
a direction parameter and what I'm going
to do is I'm going to have a second copy
of all of my images which is clipped
horizontally so to flip things
horizontally that's interesting I think
I screwed this up
should be here to flip things
horizontally
you've got batch height and then yeah
this is columns so this is the thing if
we pass in a minus 1 here then it's
going to flip it horizontally that
explains what some of my results haven't
been quite as good as I hoped
okay so when you run this we're going to
end up with a big big holes array that's
going to contain two copies of every
resized image net image the activations
at the layer that we one layer before
this so
all at once with Direction forward
someone runs direction backwards and so
at the end of that I've now got nearly
two million images or activations of two
by two by one or two four okay so
okay so that'd be pretty close to the
end of ResNet I then just copied and
pasted from the terrace code the last
few sets of ResNet right so this is the
last few blocks I added in one extra
identity block just because I had a
feeling that might help things along a
little bit again people have not really
studied this yet so I I haven't had a
chance to properly experiment but it
seemed to work quite well so this is
basically copied and pasted from Chaos's
code I then need to copy and copy the
weights and care us for those last few
layers of ResNet and so now I'm going to
repeat the same process again which is
to call predict on these last few layers
and the input will be the output from
the previous one okay so we went like
two-thirds of the way into reg net and
got those activations and put those
activations into the last few stages of
ResNet to get those activations now the
outputs from this are actually just a
vector of length two or four eight which
does fit in my RAM so I didn't bother
with calling predict on batch I can just
call doctored it if you try this at home
and you don't have enough memory you can
use the predict on batch trick again so
you know anytime you ran out of memory
when calling predict you can always just
use
this time
you
so at the end of all that I've now got
the activations from the penultimate
layer of Brezhnev and so I can do our
usual transfer learning trick of
creating a linear model and my linear
model is now going to try to use the
number of dimensions in my work vectors
at the output and you'll see it doesn't
have any activation function that's
because I'm not doing one hot encoding
my work batches could be any size
numbers so I'll just leave it as linear
and then I compile it and then I fit it
and so this linear model is now my very
first this is you know this is almost
the same as what we did in Lesson one
you know cryptographers cares
we're fine-tuning a model to a slightly
different objective functions one
slightly different target to what it was
originally trained with it's just that
we're doing it with a lot more data so
we have to be a bit more thoughtful
there's one other difference here which
is I'm using a custom loss function and
the last function I'm using is cosine
distance you can lock that up at home if
you're not familiar with it but
basically cosine distance says for these
two points in space what's their angle
between them rather than how far away
are they the reason we're doing that is
because we're about to start using K
nearest neighbors the K dearest
neighbors are going to basically say oh
here's a words actually predicted which
is the work vector which is closest to
it it turns out that in really really
high dimensional space the concept of
how far away something is is nearly
meaningless and the reason why is that
in really really high dimensional space
everything chips on the edge of that
space some basically because you can
imagine like as you add each additional
dimension the probability that
something's on the edge in that
dimension you know let's say the
probabilities too bright on the edge is
like 110 then if you're going to go one
dimension
you've got to probably have 110 it's on
the edge in one dimension or two
dimensions it's
there are basically multiplicatively
decreasing the probability that that
happens so in a 300 dimensional space
everything is on the edge and when
everything's on the edge everything is
kind of an equal distance away from each
other more or less and so distances are
very helpful but the angle between
things your barriers so when you're
doing anything with trying to find
nearest neighbors it's a really good
idea to Train things using cosine
distance and this is the formula for
cosine distance again this is one of
these things where I'm skipping over
something that you'd probably spend a
week in undergrad studying there's heaps
of information about cosine distance on
the web so those of you already familiar
with it I won't waste your time those of
you not it's a very very good idea to
become familiar with this and feel free
to ask on the forums if you find any
material that makes sense
okay so we've fitted our linear model as
per usual we saved our weights and we
can see how we're going so what we've
got now is something where we can feed
in an image and it will spit out a word
vector but it's something that looks
like a word vector it has the same
dimensionality is a word vector but it's
very unlikely that it's going to be the
exact as one of our thousands target
word vectors you know so if the word
vector for a part you know is this list
of 200 floats even if we have a
perfectly Pocky Pug we're not going to
get that exact list of 2,000 floats
we'll have something that is similar and
when we say similar we probably mean
that the cosine distance between the
perfect platonic plug and our Pug is
pretty small but that's why after we get
our our predictions we
you then have to use nearest neighbors
as a second step to basically say okay
for each of those predictions what are
the three work vectors that are closest
for that prediction so we can now take
those nearest neighbors and find out for
our you know a bunch of our images what
are the three things that thinks it
might be so for example for this image
here
it's best guess with trombone next with
flute and third with cello
this gives us some hope that this
approach seems to be working okay it's
not great yet but it's recognize these
things the musical instruments and its
third guess was better correct mutual
instrument so we know what to do next
what we do next is to find three and
more layers and because we have already
saved the intermediate results from an
earlier layer and that fine-tuning is
going to be much faster to do two more
things I briefly mentioned one is that
there's a couple of different ways to do
nearest neighbors one is what's called
the brute-force approach which is
literally okay what's the what's the
nearest word vector to this word vector
I'd like to go through every one and see
how far away it is there's another
approach which is approximate nearest
neighbors and when you've got lots and
lots of things you're trying to look for
nearest neighbors the brute-force
approach is going to be N squared time
it's going to be two this way where else
would approximate nearest neighbors are
generally n log n time
so orders of magnitude faster if you've
got a large data set the particular
approach I'm using here is an encoder
locality-sensitive hashing it's a
fascinating and wonderful algorithm
anybody who's interested in algorithms I
strongly recommend you go read about it
let me know if you need a hand with it
my favorite kind of algorithms are these
approximate approximate algorithms like
in data science you almost never need to
know something exactly yet nearly every
algorithm that people learn at
University and certainly at high school
are exact we learn exact
nearest-neighbor algorithms and exact
indexing algorithms and exact median
algorithms pretty much for every
algorithm out there there's an
approximate version that runs you know
an order of n or log n over n faster so
and one of the cool things is that once
you start realizing that you suddenly
discover that all of the libraries
you've been using for ages were written
by people that didn't know this and then
you realize that like every sub
algorithm they've written they could
have used naproxen
version next thing you've got know about
something it runs a thousand times
faster the other cool thing about
approximate algorithms is that they're
generally written to provably be
accurate to within so close and like it
can tell you with your parameters how
close they're so close which means that
if you want to make it more accurate we
run it more times there's like different
random feeds and so this thing called
LSH forest is a locality sensitive
hashing forest which means it creates a
bunch of these locality sensitive
hashing and the amazingly great thing
about approximate algorithms is that
each time you create another version of
it you're exponentially increasing the
accuracy or multiplicatively increasing
the accuracy but only linearly
increasing the time right so if the
error on one fall of LSH was eight then
the error of two calls is one - each
grade in three calls is 1 minus e cubed
and the time you're taking though the
time for one call was n is now 2 n 3 n
so when you've got something where you
can make it as accurate as you like with
only linear increase in time this is
incredibly powerful so this is a great
approximation algorithm
had more time I'd love to tell you all
about it so I generally used LSH forests
when I'm doing nearest news because it's
arbitrarily closed and much faster when
you publish words work vectors the
reason that they place the time that
becomes important is when I move beyond
image net which I'm going to do now so
let's say I got a picture and I don't
just want to say which one of the
thousand image net categories is it it
which one of the hundred thousand word
net nouns is it
that's much harder thing to do okay and
that's something that no previous model
could do right when you trained an image
net model the only thing you could do is
recognize pictures of things that were
image net but now
we've got a word sector model and so we
can put in an image that spits out a
word vector and that word vector could
be closer to things that are not an
image net at all or it could be a some
higher level of the hierarchy so we
could look for a dog rather than a park
or a plane rather than a 747 so here we
bring in the entire set of work vectors
and I have to remember to share these
with you because these are actually
quite hard to create and this is where I
definitely want LSH forest because this
is very pretty slow and we can now do
the same thing and not surprisingly it's
got works right the thing that was
actually cello that now cellos not even
in the top three and so this is a harder
problem so let's try fine-tuning so fine
tuning is the final trick I'm going to
show you are just behind your ritual
just to clarify what you were getting up
there we sing all over veterans Lane
everywhere in English language yeah yeah
you Mike remember last week we looked at
creating our word vectors and what we
did was we actually I created a list I
went to word net and I
yeah our website worth net and I
downloaded the whole of work net and
then I pick it out which team for nouns
and then I use the rich expertise out
those and then I saved that so yeah we
actually have the entirety of work net
nouns like children your limoncello not
close to it because it's because it's
not a good enough model yet alright so
now that there's 80,000 nouns there's a
lot more a lot more ways to be wrong all
right so what it only has to say okay
which of these thousand things is it
that's pretty easy
which of these 80,000 things is it is
pretty hard
okay sure you want to take that
[Music]
okay so to fine-tune it it looks very
similar to our usual way of fine-tuning
things which is that we take our two
models and stick them back to back
and we're now going to train the whole
thing rather than just the linear model
now the problem is that the input to
this model is too big to fit in round so
how are we going to call fit or fit
generator when we have an array data too
big to fit in RAM well one obvious thing
to do would USB to past in the big holes
array because to most things in place
than a big holes array looks just like a
regular array doesn't really look any
different the way a big holes array is
actually stored
is it actually stored as a
yeah a big holes array is actually
stored in a directory as I'm sure you've
noticed and in that directory that takes
got something that called chunk length
and plan actually I set it to 32 when I
created these big holes arrays what it
does is it takes every 32 images
puts them into a separate file
all right so each one of these has 32
images in it or 32 of the leading of
leading axis of the array now if you
then try to take this whole array and
passed it to dot set and care us with
shuffle it's going to try and grab one
thing from here and one thing from here
and there one thing from here here's the
bad news but they call to park get one
thing out of a chunk it has to read and
decompress the whole thing as it has to
read and decompress 32 images in order
to give you the one image you asked for
at B as a buzzer and that be
ridiculously horribly slow we didn't
have to worry about that
when we called predict on batch because
we were grab it we were going not
shuffling but we were going in order
that was just grabbing one
grabbing a single image out of the out
of a chunk but now that we want to
shuffle it would right so what we've
done is we've somebody very helpfully
actually on a cattle forum provided
something called a be called array
iterator and the be called array
iterator which was kindly discovered on
the forums actually by somebody named NP
Johnston originally written by this
fellow what it does is it
provides a Karass compatible generator
which grabs an entire chunk at a time so
it's a little bit less random right but
given that if this has got two million
images in and the chunk length is 32
then it's going to basically create a
batch of chunks rather than a batch of
images and so that means we have none of
the performance problems and
particularly because we remember
originally we randomly shuffled our
files so this whole thing is randomly
shuffled anyway and so this is a good
trick
so you'll find the big holes array
iterator on github feel free to take a
look at the code it's pretty
straightforward there was a few issues
with the original version so NP Jensen
life kind of tried to fix it up and I've
written some tests for us and he's
written some documentation for it but if
you just want to use it then it's as
simple as writing this wire equals big
holes array iterator this is your data
your labels couple equals true batch
size equals whatever and then you can
just call fit generator as per usual
nothing in that iterator and that
iterators number of items
okay so all of you guys who have been
asking you know how do I deal with data
that's bigger than memory this is how
you do it okay so hopefully that will
make life easier for other people so we
fine-tune it for a while we do some
loading repre kneeling for a while and
this basically runs overnight for me
kind of takes about six hours to run and
so come back the next morning and I just
copy and paste my K nearest neighbors so
I call predict to get my predicted work
vectors for each word vector R then pass
it into nearest neighbors this is my
gist thousand categories
and lo and behold we now have fellow in
the top spot as we hoped how did it go
in the heart a problem of looking at the
100,000 or so now nouns in English
pretty good I've got this one right and
just to pick another one at random let's
pick the first one
it said thrown that sure looks like a
throne so looking pretty good so here's
something interesting now that we have
bought images and words into the same
space let's play with it some more
so why don't we use nearest neighbors
with those predictions so predicted
that's me
early
argument boom boom what there's work yet
so to to the to the word Tyvek vector
which Google created and but the subset
of those which are nouns
according to word net maps - there are
ten set IDs both zu several know dreams
so yeah the word well the word vectors
are just the word to word two vectors
that we can download off the internet so
yes they were
pre trained by Google please versus
we like very beddings but they're not
really waste you're better than me I'm
gettin okay so Lincoln grew presumably
onwards which yes exactly so we're
saying here is this this image spits out
a vector from a thing we just trained we
have a hundred thousand word to that
word vectors for all the nouns in
English which one of those is the
closest to the thing that came out of
our model and the answer was from the
zoo in localization user excusive long
nourishment space hold that thought will
be doing language translation starting
next week so no we don't quite do it
that way but you can think of it much um
so let's do something interesting let's
um create a nearest neighbors not for
all of the work of X Factor's but for
all of our image predicted vectors and
now we can do the opposite let's take a
word we pick at random let's look it up
in our work to veterinary and let's find
the nearest neighbors for that in our
images
there it is okay so this is pretty
interesting you know you could now find
there's a touch-free right so you can
now find the images that are the most
like whatever words you come up with so
okay that's crazy but we can do crazier
here is a random thing I picked now
notice I picked it from the validation
set of image nets we've never seen this
image before and when honestly when I
opened it up my heart sank because I
don't know what it is
so this is a problem what is that
Riesling manta ray okay so I didn't pick
it so what we can do is we can call drop
predict on that image and we can then do
a nearest neighbors of all of our other
images and there's the first there's a
second and the third one is even
somebody putting their hand on it which
is slightly crazy but that was what the
original one for play in fact I've got a
if I can find it at this one I ran it
again on a different image
yeah here okay I took this one which is
like pretty I actually looked around for
something weird this is pretty weird
right this is the natural is it a fish
so when we then ask for nearest
neighbors we get fish in there okay so
it's like I don't know sometimes deep
learning so magic you just kind of go in
there possibly what ads this behind you
Rachel I don't assistant
we try to do that
Catherine
Oh
yeah
yeah I'm only a little bit and maybe you
know future course we model cadets go
thinking maybe even in your numerical
linear algebra course you might be
looking a desk so I don't think we'll
cover it this course
um but do look at that dask it's
difficult to show our problem issue in
training there and if they have easy
using them and fish no not at all
so these were actually labeled as this
particular kind of fish in fact that's
the other thing is it's not only found
fishing nets it has actually found this
more or less the same breed of fish in
the net but when we called predict on
those it created a word vector which was
probably like halfway between that kind
of fish and a net because it doesn't
know what to do right and so sometimes
when it see things like that there would
have been mark seen image net of the net
and sometimes it would have been a fish
and so the best way to minimize the loss
function would have been to kind of
pitch that's so attached and as a result
the images that were closest were the
ones which actually were half way
between the two themselves so it's kind
of a convenient accident all in in your
alone in that evening a chance and be
willing network that an asset yeah yeah
absolutely yeah this up at the back
there we'll just walk it over it
you
the bridge network to length with the
ring when you can't wear prison
you absolutely can and I have and but
really certain nearest neighbors I
haven't found anything nearly as good as
cosine and that's true and all of the
things I looked up as well by the way I
should mention the when you use
locality-sensitive hashing in Python by
default it uses something that's
equivalent to the cosine metrics so
that's why the nearest neighbors work
yes yes more than one yes exactly so
starting next week we're going to be
learning about sequence to sequence
models and memory and attention methods
they're going to show us how we can take
an input such as a sentence in English
and without input/output such as a
sentence in French which is the
particular case study we're going to be
spending two or three weeks on when you
combine that with this you get image
captioning I'm not sure if we're going
to have time to do it ourselves but it
will literally be trivial for you guys
to take the two things and combine them
into image caching I could serve it's
just those two techniques together
person
okay so we're now going to switch to
actually before we take a break I want
to show you the homework and the
homework hopefully you guys noticed I
gave you some tips because it's really
challenging one even though in a sense
it was kind of straightforward which
would take everything that we've already
learned about different resolution and
slightly change the loss function so
that it does perceptual loss it's the
cell transfer instead the details are
tricky and I'm going to quickly show you
two things and the first we're going to
show you how I did the homework if I
actually hadn't done it last week
luckily I have enough RAM that I could
read the two things all into memory so
don't forget you can just do that with a
big holes array to turn it into a numpy
array in memory
[Music]
so one thing I did was I created my
upsampling block to get rid of the
checkerboard patterns that was literally
as simple as saying upsampling 2d than
1x1 cotton so that got rid of my
triangle layer a checkable times the
next thing I did was I changed my last
function and I decided before I try to
do style transfer with perceptual losses
let's try and do super resolution with
multiple content last layers because
like that's one thing that I'm going to
have to do is they'll transfer is be
able to use multiple layers so like I
always like to start with something that
works and make small little changes so
it keeps working at every point so in
this case I thought okay let's first of
all slightly change the loss function
tour and took a resolution so that it
uses multiple layers so here's how I did
that I changed my get output layer so I
changed my PTT content so it created a
list of outputs climbs one from each of
the first second and third blocks okay
and then I changed my loss function so
it went through and added the mean
squared difference for each of those
three layers I also just have to add a
weight just for fun so I decided what to
go point one point eight point one
because this is the layer that they used
in the paper but you know but let's have
a little bit of you know more precise
super resolution and a little bit of
more semantic sticker resolution see how
it goes I created it functioned to kind
of a more general mean squared error and
that was basically it so other than that
line and that line everything else was
the same and so that gave me super
resolution working on multiple layers
and one of the things I found
fascinating is that this is the original
low res and it done a good job of
upscaling it but it's also
fixed up the weird white balance which
really surprised me right it's thinkin
this obviously over yellow is shot and
this is what ceramic should look like it
should be white you know and somehow
it's kind of adjusted everything so the
30s or whatever it is in the background
has come from a Yowie Brown to a nice
white as if these cast here I'm going to
figure it out with these slightly
pixelated things they're actually meant
to be upside down handles now this is
only 20,000 images so I I am very
surprised that it's fixing the color
because we never asked it to but I guess
it knows what a cut is meant to look
like then so this is what it's decided
to do is to make a up to where it thinks
it's meant to look so that is pretty
cool
so so then to go from there to style
transfer was pretty straightforward I
had to read in my style as before this
is the code to do their special kind of
ResNet block where we use valid
convolutions which means we lose two
pixels each time and so therefore we
have to do it Center crop I don't forget
lambda layers are great for this kind of
thing right that's whatever you whatever
code you can write check it in a lambda
layer suddenly it's a chaos' layer so do
my Center crop so this is our resident
block which does well it comes
so this is basically all exactly the
same we have to do a few down samplings
and then the computation in our up
sampling just like a supplemental paper
so the loss function looks a lot like
the loss function did before but we've
got two extra things what is the ground
matrix so here is a version of the
ground matrix which works a batch at a
time now if any of you tried to do this
a single image at a time
you would have gone crazy with that
slower talk I saw a few of you trying to
do that so here's the batch wise version
of Graham metrics and then the second
thing I needed to do was somehow feed in
my style target okay so another thing I
thought some of you do was feed in the
style target every time of feed in that
array into your loss function now you
can obviously calculate your style
target by just calling dot product right
with the thing which gives you your all
of your different style target layers
but the problem is this thing here
returns an umpire rain it's a pretty big
number array which means that then when
you want to use it as a style target and
training it has to copy that back to the
GPU and copying to the GPU is very very
very slow and this is a really big thing
to copy to the GPU so any of you who
tries this and I saw some of you try it
took forever okay so here's the trick
called variable art all right turning
something into a variable fix it on the
GPU for you all right so once you've
done that you can now treat this as a
list of symbolic entities which are the
GPU versions of this right so I can now
call this use this inside eye GPU code
so here my style targets I can use
inside my lost function there it is I
can use inside my loss function and it
doesn't have to do any copying passing
forward so there's a subtlety but if you
don't get that subtlety right you're
going to be waiting for a week or so if
your code to finish so those are the
little subtleties which were necessary
to get this to work and once you get it
to work it does exactly the same thing
basically it before so where this gets
combined with devise is I want to try
something interesting which is in the
original perceptual office paper they
trained it on on the cocoa data set
which has 80,000 images which didn't
seem like many I wanted to know what
would happen if we trained it on all of
imagenet so I did so I decided to train
a super resolution network on all of
image net and a codes all identical so
I'm not going to explain it other than
you'll notice we don't have the square
bracket colon square bracket here
anymore all right because we don't want
to try and read in the entirety of image
net into RAM so these are still big
holes arrays and all the other code is
identical until we get to
here so I use a be called array iterator
I can't just call dot fit because
that's it adopt it generator assumes
that your iterator is returning your
your data and your labels in our case we
don't have data and labels we have two
things that both get set in as two
inputs and our labels are just a list of
zeros okay so here's a quick trick and
just this answers your earlier question
about how do you how do you do multi
input models on large data sets and the
answer is create your own training loop
okay create your own training loop which
lives through a bunch of iterations and
then you can grab as many batches of
data from as many different iterations
as you like and then call trained on
batch right so in my case I big holes
array iterator is going to return my
high resolution and low resolution batch
of images so I go to a bunch of
iterations grab one batch of high res
and low res images and pass them as my
two inputs the Train on batch so this is
the only code
I changed other than changing that fit
generator to actually calling back
so as you can see this took me four and
a half hours to train and I then it
creates learning rate and I trained for
another four and a half hours actually I
did it overnight last night I only had
enough time to do about half of imagenet
so this isn't even the whole thing but
check this out so check that model and
we're going to call drop predict on this
is the original high-res image here's
the low res version and here's the
version that we've created and as you
can see it's done a pretty
extraordinarily good job you know the
when you look at the original ball
they'll just kind of a yellow thing here
it's kind of turned it into a nice
little inscription you can see that her
eyes would like to grade Lots it's kind
of spin turn it into some eyes you can
see that her you could just tell that's
an a maybe if you look carefully now
it's very clearly an A so you can see it
doesn't amazing job of upscaling this
Paul is still is this is a fully
convolutional net and therefore is not
specific to any particular input
resolution so what I can do is I can
create another version of the model
using our high risk as the input okay so
now we're going to call dot predicts
with the high-res input
and that
but we get that
look at that we can now see all of this
detail on the basketball which simply
none of that really existed here like it
was there but pretty hard to see what it
was okay
and like look at before like look at
over here right this kind of gray blob
here
here you can see it it knows it's like
little bit to pull back here so like we
can take any size image and make it
bigger and like this this to me is one
of the most amazing results I've seen in
deep learning when we train something on
nearly all of imagenet it's a single
epoch so there's definitely no
overfitting and it's like able to
recognize what hair is meant to look
like when pulled back into a bun it's
pretty pretty extraordinary result I
think something else which I only
realized later is that the
it's all a bit fuzzy right I'd like this
arm in the background for this fuzzy
the model knows that that is meant to
stay fuzzy it knows what out-of-focus
things look like so like equally cool is
not just tell like you know that a is
now incredibly precise and accurate that
the fact that it knows that blurry
things needs a stable area so I don't
know if you're as amazed that this is I
am but I thought this was a pretty cool
result and there you know we could run
this over 24 hour period on maybe 2 we
post of all of imagenet and presumably
it get even better still there we go
ok so let's take a 7 minute break and
see you back here at 5:00 class station
in general okay thanks everybody
that was fun so we're going to do
something else fun
and that is to look at Oh actually
prefer to continue I did want to mention
one thing in the homework that I changed
which is
I realized in my in my like manually
created loss function I was already
doing a mean squared error in the last
function but then when I like told
Terrace like make that thing as close to
zero as possible
I had to also give it the loss function
and I was giving it MSE and effectively
that was like kind of squaring right
squared errors that seemed wrong so I've
changed it to M ay e mean absolute error
so when you look back over the notebook
sense that's why is because this is just
to say hey get the last as close to zero
as possible I didn't really want to read
where it that didn't make any sense so
and that's that's why you'll see that
minor change the only thing to mention
is I I didn't notice that when I
retrained my super resolution on my new
images that didn't have the black border
it gave good results much much faster
and so I really think that thing is like
learning to put the black border back in
seemed to take quite a lot of effort for
it so again hopefully some of you were
gonna look into that in more detail
um
so we're going to learn about
adversarial Network generative
adversarial networks and this will kind
of close off a deep dive into German
generative models as applied to images
and just you know to remind you the
purpose of this has been to learn about
generative models not so specifically
learn about super-resolution or artistic
style but you know remember these things
can be used to create four kinds of
images so one of the groups is
interested in taking a 2d photo and
trying to turn it into something that
you can rotate in 3d or at least show a
different angle of that 2d photo and
that's a great example of something that
is you're totally work for you know it's
just a mapping from one image to some
different image just like what this
image look like from above versus from
the kernel but keep in mind the purpose
of this is just like in part one we
learn about classification which you can
use for thousand things now we're
learning about generative models that
you can enter a different certainty now
any generative model you build you can
make it better by adding on top of it
again a generative adversarial Network
and this is something I don't really
feel like it's been fully appreciated
people I've seen generally tree scans as
a different way of creating a job that a
generative model but I think of this
more is like why not create your
generative model using the kind of
techniques we've been talking about
but then think of it this way think of
that all the artistic style stuff we
were doing and the the like my terrible
attempt at a Simpsons cartoon version of
the picture and it looked nothing like
The Simpsons
so what would be one way to improve that
but one way to improve that would be to
create two networks there would be one
network that takes our picture which is
actually not the Simpsons and takes
another picture that actually is
Simpsons and maybe we can train a neural
network that takes those two photos
throw those two images and spits out
something saying is that a real Simpsons
image or not okay and this thing will
call the discriminator
so we could easily train a discriminator
right now right it's just a
classification networks just use the
same techniques we used in part one we
feed it the two images and it's going to
spit out a one if it's a real Simpsons
cartoon and a zero if it's Jeremy's
crappy generative model of Simpsons it's
easy right we know how to do that right
now
okay go and build that now
go and build another model
hi that's room there's two images is
input yeah
wonderful
what was that or do people know so you
would feed it one thing that's the
symptoms and one thing that's a
generative output it's up to you to feed
it one one of each okay or alternatively
you could feed it one thing in fact
probably easier is to just to feed it
one thing and it spits out is it the
Simpsons or is it isn't it the Simpsons
and you could just mix the matter
actually it's the latter that we're
going to do so that's probably easier as
my original wedding yes we're going to
have one thing which is either not a
Simpsons or it is a Simpsons and we're
going to have a bit of mix of 50/50 of
those two
and we're going to have something come
out saying what do you think is it real
or not so this thing this discriminator
from now on will probably generally to
this be calling it d thanks is the thing
Cordy and we can think of that as a
function right C is a function that
takes some input X
which is an image right and fits out a 1
or a 0 or maybe a probability
what we could now do is create another
neural network and what this neural
network is going to do is it's going to
take as input some random noise
just like our all of our generators have
so far okay and it's going to spit out
an image
and the lost function is going to be if
you take that image and stick it through
D
did you manage to fool us
all right so could you create something
where in fact we want it to say oh yeah
totally that's a simple that's a real
Simpsons so if that was our last
function but we're going to call this
the generator for call it G right it's
just something exactly like our
perceptual losses style transfer model
could be exactly the same model okay
that the last function is now going to
be take the output of that and stick it
through D the discriminator and try to
trick it right so the generators doing
well if the discriminate is getting it
wrong
in fact so one way to do this would be
to take our discriminator and train it
as best as we can to recognize the
difference between our crappy Simpsons
and real Simpsons and then get a
generator and train it to trick that
discriminator but now at the end of that
it's probably still not very good
because you realize that actually a
discriminator didn't have to be very
good before because my Simpsons
generators were so bad
so I could now go back and retrain the
discriminator based on my better
generated images and then I can go back
and retrain the generator and back and
forth I go and then is the general
approach of again is to keep going back
between two things which is training a
discriminator and training a generator
using a discriminator as a loss function
so we've got one thing which is
discriminator on some image and another
thing which is a discriminator on a
generator on some noise
you
yeah yeah so in practice these things
are going to spit out probabilities
okay so that's the general idea in
practice they found it very difficult to
do this like train the discriminator as
best as we can stop train the generator
as best as we can so instead of what the
original gand paper that's fine then
right now the original gand paper is
called generative adversarial Nets and
what they did was to and here you can
see they've actually specified this loss
function so here it is a notation right
is two and they call it minimizing the
generator whilst maximizing the
discriminator this is what min max is
referring to what they do in practice is
they do it a batch at a time and so they
have a loop I'm going to go through a
loop into a single batch through the
discriminator that same batch stick it
through the generator and so we're going
to do it a batch at a time so let's look
at that so here's the original game from
that paper and we're going to do it on M
list and what we're going to do is we're
going to see if we can start from
scratch to create something which can
create images which the discriminator
cannot tell whether they're real or fake
and it's a discriminator that has LEDs
the good at discriminating real from
fake pictures of init endless images so
a loaded in earnest and the first thing
they do in the paper is just used a
standard multilayered cetera so under
skip over that and let's get to the
perceptron so here's our generator it's
just a standard multi-layer perceptron
and here's our discriminator which is
also a standard multi-layer perceptron
their generator has a sigmoid activation
so in other words we're going to spit
out an image where all of the pixels are
between 0 and 1 so if you want to print
it out we'll just multiply it by 255 I
guess
so there's our generator there's our
discriminator so there's then the
combination of the two
so take the generator and stick it into
the discriminator so we can just use
sequential for that and this is actually
therefore the loss function that I want
on my generator is generate something
and then carefully fold the
discriminator
so these are my architectures setup so
the next thing I need to do is set up
this thing called train which is going
to do this adversarial training let's go
back and have a look at train
so what train is going to going to do is
going to go through a bunch of epochs
and notice here I wrap it in this TQ DM
this is the thing that creates a magical
progress bar doesn't do anything else to
just create a little progress bar we
learned about that last week
so the first thing I need to do is to
generate some data to feed the
discriminator so create a little
function to that and here's my little
function so it's going to create a
little bit of data that's real and a
little bit of data to fake okay so my
real data is okay let's go into my
actual training set and grab some
randomly selected emne stitches that's
my real bit and then let's create some
fake right so noise is a function that
I've just created up here which is
create some 100 random numbers okay
so let's create some noise orgy predict
right and so then I can catenate the two
together so now I've got some real data
and some fake data and so this is going
to try and predict whether or not
something is fake
so one means fake zero means real so I'm
going to return my my data and my maples
which is a bunch of zeros say they're
all real a bunch of ones to say they are
all fake okay so there's my
discriminative data now go ahead and
create a set of data for the
discriminator and then do one batch of
training
now I'm going to do the same thing for
the generator but when I train the
generator I don't want to change the
discriminators weights right so make
trainable simply go through each layer
and said it's not trainable
so make my discriminator non trainable
and do one batch of training where I'm
taking noise there's my inputs and my
goal is to get the discriminator to
think that they are actually real
so it's why I'm passing in a bunch of
zeros because remember zero means real
and that's it and then make
discriminator trainable again so keep
working through this train the
discriminator on a batch of up real
half-baked and then train the generator
to try and trick the discriminator using
all fake repeat
so that's the training loop that's a
basic game because we use TQ DM we get
an astral progress bar we can plot out
the I kept track of the last at each
step so there's our lofts for the
discriminator and there's our loss to
the generator so a question is what are
these lost curves mean are they good or
bad like
how do we know and the answer is but
this kind of can they mean nothing at
all like the generator could get
fantastic but it could be because the
discriminate is terrible and like they
don't really know whether each one is
good or not so like even the order of
magnitude of both of them is meaningless
so these curves me nothing the direction
of the curves mean nothing and this is
one of the real difficulty through
training dance and here's what happens
when I plot 12 randomly selected random
noise vectors duck through there and we
have not got things above terribly like
endless digits and they also don't look
terribly much like they have a lot of
variety this is called
you
load class very common problem when
training against and what it means is
that the generator and the discriminator
have kind of reached a stalemate where
neither you know neither 'litham
basically knows how to go from here and
in terms of optimization we've basically
found a local minima right so okay that
was not very successful can we do better
so the next page of paper that came
along was this one
the topic is called unsupervised
representation learning with deep
convolutional derivative adversarial
networks so this created something that
they called DC games and the main page
that you want to look at here is page 3
where they say core to our approach is
doing these three things and basically
what they do is they just do exactly the
same thing as gans
but they do three things one is to use
the kinds of one for all of them is to
learn the tricks that we've been
learning for generative models here's an
all convolutional net get rid of max
pooling and use trader convolutions
instead get rid of fully connected
layers and use lots of convolutional
features instead and add in national ok
and then use a CNN rather than MRP so
here is that right there's a little very
familiar it looks just like last lesson
and stuff right so the generator is
going to take in some random grid of
inputs it's going to do a batch norm up
sample you'll notice that I'm doing even
newer than this paper I'm doing the up
sampling approach because we know that's
better up sample one by one calms batch
norm of sample one by one cons batch
norm and then a final column player
discriminator basically does the
opposite which is some two by two sub
samplings so down sampling in the
discriminator another trick that they
mentioned I think it's mentioned in the
paper is to before you do the back and
forth batch for the discriminator and a
bachelor generator is to train the
discriminator for a fraction of an epoch
like there are few batches through the
discriminator so at least it knows how
to recognize the difference between a
random image and a real image a little
bit and so you can see here actually to
start by calling discriminative it it's
just a very small amount of data so this
is kind of like
bootstrapping the discriminator and then
I just go ahead and call the same train
as we had before with my other
architectures
and again these curves are kind of
totally meaningless but we had something
which if you squint you could almost
convince yourself of that survived any
so until a week or two before this all
started this was kind of about as good
as we had people were much better at the
artisanal details of this than I was and
indeed there's a whole page called gang
hacks which had lots of tips but then
couple of weeks before this class
started as I mentioned in the first
class along came the wasa Stein game and
the wasps tank and got rid of all these
problems and here is the wasa same can
ever
and this paper is
quite an extraordinary paper and it's
particularly extraordinary because I
think I mentioned this in playing in the
first class of this part both papers
tend to either be math theory that goes
nowhere or kind of nice experiments and
engineering where the theory gets kind
of tacked on at the end and kind of
minimus this paper is entirely driven by
theory and then the theory they go on to
show this is what the theory means this
is what we do and suddenly all the
problems go away the lost curves are
going to actually mean something and
we're going to be able to do what I've
said we wanted to do right at the start
of this gen Dan section which is to
train the discriminator a whole bunch of
steps and then do a generator and then
discriminator a whole bunch of steps
into the generator and all that is going
to suddenly start working how do we get
it to work
so in fact despite the fact that this
paper is both long and full of equations
and theorems and proofs and there's a
whole bunch of appendices of the back
with more theorems and proofs there's
actually only two things you need to do
one is remove the log from the loss
function so rather than using
cross-entropy loss we're just going to
use means Guidera that's one change and
the second change is we're going to
constrain the weights so that they lie
between negative 0.01 and positive point
no one we're going to constrain the
weights to make them more now in the
process of seeing that's all we're going
to do is to kind of massively is to not
give credit for this paper right because
this paper is is they figured out that
that's what we need to do and on the
forums some of you have been reading
through this paper and I've already
given you some tips as to some really
there's a really great walkthrough I put
it on our wiki that explains all the
math from scratch but basically what the
math says is is again the last function
for again is not really the loss
function you put into chaos like we
thought we were just putting in like a
cross entropy loss function but in fact
and again what we really care about is
the difference between two distributions
the difference between the discriminator
and the generator and the difference
between two blocks functions as a very
different shape for the loss function on
its own okay so it turns out that the
difference between the two loss
functions the two cross after loss
functions is something called the Jenson
Shannon distance and the this paper
shows that that loss function is hideous
it is not differentiable and it does not
have a nice smooth shape at all so it
kind of explains why it is that we kept
getting this mode collapse and failing
to find nice minimum which is basically
that mathematically this loss function
does
not behave the way a good loss function
should and you know previously we've not
come across anything like this because
we have been training a single function
at a time we really understand those
loss functions mean squared error cross
entropy but never though we haven't
already always derived the math in
detail plenty of people have you know we
know that they're kind of nice and
smooth and that they have pretty nice
shapes and they do what we want them to
do in this case by training true things
kind of adversarially to each other
we're actually doing something quite
different at this paper just absolutely
fantastically show shows with both
examples and the theory why that's just
never going to work
we use lysimachus
um
yes but the I mean even the cosine
distance so the cosine distance is the
difference between two things or else
these distances that we're talking about
here are the distances between two
distributions which is a much more
tricky problem to deal with the cosine
distance actually if you if you look at
the notebook during the week you'll see
it's basically the same as the Euclidean
distance that you normalize the data
first so it has all the same nice
properties that the Euclidean distance
so the so one things fun is that the
authors of this paper released their
code in pi torch and luckily Platzer pi
torch the first kind of pre-release came
out in mid-january he won't be surprised
to hear that one of the authors of the
paper is the main author of pi torch so
he was writing this before we even
released the code there's lots of
reasons we want to learn play torch
anyway so here's a good reason right so
let's look at the Wasserstein gain in
play torch most most of the code can
catch other than this pretty much all
the code I'm showing you in this part of
the course is very loosely based on lots
of bits of other code which I had to
massively rewrite because all of it was
wrong and hideous this code actually I
only did some minor refactoring to
simplify things so this is actually very
close to their code and so there's a
very nice paper with very nice code so
that's great thing
so before we look at the wealth of stone
I guess it's the fastest time really
does the stone again in play torch let's
look briefly a play torch okay
so pay torch basically what you're going
to see is that I torch looks a lot like
numpy which is nice we don't have to
create a computational graph using
variables and placeholders and later on
round in a session and blah blah blah
thank you I'm sure you've seen by now
with you know care a script tends to
flow you try to print something out that
some intermediate output it just prints
out like cancer and tells you how many
dimensions it has but that's because all
that thing is symbolic side of a
computational breath PI torch doesn't
work that way pi torch is what's called
a defined by run framework it's
basically designed to be so fast to take
your code and compile it that you don't
have to create that graph in advance
like every time you run a piece of code
it puts it on the GPU runs it sends it
back all in one go so it makes things
look very simple so this is a slightly
cut-down version of the PI torch
tutorial that PI torch provides on their
website so you can grab that from there
so rather than creating NPO terrain you
create torch tensor but other than that
it's identical right so here's a random
torch tensor
rather than a few guys all a little bit
different rather than Shaitaan size
but you can settle through similar right
and so unlike in enter flow or theano we
can just say X plus y and there it is we
don't have to say that equaled X plus y
equals function takes X and y inputs and
because there's output and then in
function dot a vowel no just X plus y
and there it is as you can see why it's
called defined by run we just provide
the code and it just runs it generally
speaking most operations in torch as
well as having this in fixed version
there's also a suffix of so prefix
version this is exactly the same thing
um you can often add and that nearly
always a day out equals and that puts
the results in this pre allocated memory
we've already talked about way it's
really important to pre allocate memory
it's particularly important on GPUs and
so if you write your own algorithms in
pipe torch you need to be very careful
of this perhaps the best trick is that
you can stick an underscore on the end
of most things and it causes it to in
place this is basically y plus equals x
that's what this underscore had again so
there's some good little tricks you can
do splicing just like numpy you can turn
numpy stuff into torch tensors and vice
versa by simply going numpy and one
thing to be very aware of is that a and
b are now referring to the same thing so
that if I now add underscore so in place
a plus equals one it also changes be
okay vice versa you can turn on play
into torch by calling torch from numpy
and again same thing if you change the
none fire change of the torch
all of that so far is been running on
the CPU to turn anything into something
that runs on the GPU your Chuck scooter
at the end of it okay so this X plus y
just ran on the GPU
you
so where things get cool is that
something like this no it's not just how
to do the that piece of arithmetic but
it also knows how to take the gradient
of that gradient you just take your
torch tensor
wrap it in variable and add this
parameter to it and now from now on
anything I do to X it's going to
remember what I did so that it can take
the gradient of it so for example X plus
2 okay I get back three just like a
normal tensor so a variable and attempt
to have the same API except that I can
keep doing things to it squared times
three mean later on I can go dot
backward and grad and I can get the
gradient
match the critical difference between a
tensor and the variable they have
exactly the same API exact variable also
has backward and that gets you the
gradient so when I say top gradient the
reason that this is the out DX is
because I typed out backward all right
so this is the thing it's the derivative
is for respect to
kind of crazy you can do things like
while loops
get the gradients of them this kind of
seeing pretty tricky to do with Spencer
flow or piano or these kind of
computation graph approaches so it gives
you a whole lot of flexibility to define
things in like much more natural ways so
you can really write play torch just
like you're writing
regular old kind of non play stuff it
has plenty of libraries so if you want
to create a neural network here's how
you do a CNN I want you early on that if
you don't know about
oh whoa and pipes immunity to my lotion
so here's why because in play torch
everything kind of done years ago oh I
really like this track because like in
in piano I'm sorry intensive flow they
kind of invent their own weird way of
programming rather than use Python over
real play torch just goes out we already
have these features in the language
let's just use them so it's way easier
in my opinion so to create a neural net
you create a new class you derive from
module and then in the constructor you
create all of the things that have
weights okay
so these you know cons one is now
something that has some weight 3d cons
come true is something with some weights
poly connected one is something with
some ways okay so there's all of your
layers and then you get to see exactly
what happens in your forward path right
now because max cool 2d doesn't have any
weights and revenue doesn't have any
weights there's no need to define them
in the initializer right you can just
call them as functions but these things
have works so they need to be at a
stateful persistent so in my forward
class you literally just define what are
the things that happen
dot view is the same as reshape okay so
like the whole API has different names
for everything which is mildly annoying
for the first week that you kind of get
used to it so dot reshape is called docu
during the week if you try to use pay
torch and you're like how do you say
blah and pay torch and you can't find it
feel free to post on the forum
having said that pay torch has its own
discourse based forums and as you can
see it is just as busy and friendly as
our forums people are posting on these
all the time so I find it a really great
helpful community so feel free to ask
over there or over here
um great so you can then put all of that
computation under the GPU by calling
Kuna
um now you can then take some input put
down the GPU with Doc CUDA you can then
calculate your derivatives calculate
your loss and then later on you can
optimiser
this is just one step of the optimizer
so we have to kind of put that in word
so there's the basic pieces at the end
here there's a complete process but I
think more fun will be to see the
process in the stone again so here it is
I've kind of got this torch utils thing
which refining github which has the
basic stuff you'll want for torch all
there so you can just import that same
can working so we set up the batch size
the size of each image the size of our
noise vector and look how cool it is I
really like this this is how you import
data sets it has a data sets module
already in the torch vision library is
the sci-fi 10 data set it will
automatically download it to this path
for you if you say download equals true
and rather than having to figure out how
to do the pre-processing you can create
a list of transforms alright so I think
it is really lovely API the reason that
this is so new it has such a nice API is
because this comes from a lower library
called torch that's been around for many
years and so these guys are basically
started off by copying what they already
had and whatever already works well so I
think it is very elegant there's another
so I've got two different things you can
look at here they're both from the paper
- a 5/10 which are the tiny little
images another is something we haven't
seen before which is called Elston which
is a really nice data set it's a huge
data set with
millions of images three million bedroom
images for example so we can use either
one
this is pretty cool we can then call up
create a data loader see how many
workers use we already know what workers
are right this is all built into the
framework okay so now that you know how
many workers your GP your CPU likes to
use you can just go ahead and put that
number in here
use your CPU to load in this data in
parallel in the background okay so we're
going to start with say five ten so
we've got 47 thousand of those images
[Music]
definition of the discriminator and the
generator architectures into a separate
place info bck and up a rata skip over
very quickly because it's really
straightforward here's a cons block that
consists of a come to D the batch non 2d
and a leaky value so in my initializer I
can go ahead and say okay we'll start
with a current block optionally have a
few extra comic blocks this is really
nice here's a while loop that says keep
adding more downsampling blocks until
you've varied up sampling blocks until
you've got as many as you need so that's
really nice kind of use of a while loop
to simplify our getting our architecture
and then a final comic block at the end
to actually create the thing we want and
then this is pretty nifty if you could
pass in ng to you greater than one
then it will call parallel data parallel
passing in those GPU IDs and it will do
automatic multi-gpu training so this is
like by far the easiest multi-gpu
training I've ever seen so yeah that's
it that's the that's the forward pass
behind huge
the reason
um we'll learn more about this over the
next couple of weeks in fact given we're
a little short of time let let's discuss
that next week and let me know if you
don't think you cover it um okay here's
a generator looks very very similar
again as a while loop to make sure that
we've gone through them great number of
decomp blocks so this is actually
interesting this would probably be
better off with an up sampling blocks
followed by a one-by-one convolution so
maybe at home you could try this and see
if you get better results because this
is probably got the checkerboard pattern
problem okay so there's a generator and
our discriminator 20 75 lines of code
nice and easy
you know everything is a little bit
different implied torch if we want to
say what initializer to use again we're
going to kind of use a little bit more
it's kind of more decoupled maybe at
first it's a little more complex there's
less things you have to learn you can
cut through in this case we can call
something called apply which takes some
function and asses it to everything in
our architecture so this function is
something that says oh is this a comp to
D your comm transpose to D if so use
this initialization function or if it's
a batch norm use this initialization
function okay so again you know
everything's a little bit different you
there isn't a separate initialize a
parameter this is in my opinion much
more flexible I really like it okay
so as before we need something to create
some noise so let's go ahead and
creating some fixed noise we're going to
have an optimizer for the discriminator
we've got an optimizer for the generator
here is something that does one step of
the discriminator right so we're going
to call the forward pass and then we
call the backward pass and then we
return the error just like before we've
got something called make trainable so
this is how we make something trainable
or not trainable in play torch and just
like before we have a train loop the
Train loop has got a little bit more
going on
partly because of the vs. playing again
partly because of high torch but the
basic idea is the same for each epoch or
each batch
make the discriminative trainable
and then this is the number of
iterations to train the discriminator
for so remember I told you one of the
nice things about the Vasa so again is
that we don't have to do one best
estimator one best generator one better
scream it at one best generator but we
can actually train the discriminator
properly for a bunch of batches and in
the paper they suggest using
[Music]
five iterations or five batches of
discriminator training each time through
the loop unless it's one of less you're
still in the first twenty five
generations to twenty five iterations
and say if you're in the first twenty
five iterations through our hundred
matches and then they also say from time
to time through 100 batches so it's kind
of nice
by having the flexibility here to really
change things we can do exactly what the
paper wants us to do so basically at
first we're going to train the
discriminator carefully and we're also
from time to time train the
discriminator very carefully otherwise
we'll just do five batches
so this is where we go ahead and pain
the discriminator and you'll see here we
plant as it's the same as clip the
weights in the discriminator to fall in
this range and if you're interested in
reading the paper the paper explains
that the basically the reason that is is
that they're their assumptions are only
only true in this kind of small area
that's that's why we have to make sure
that the way to stay in a small area so
then we go ahead and do a single step of
the discriminator then we create the
noise and to a single step at the
generator we get our fake data for the
discriminator that we can subtract the
fake from the real to get our error the
discriminator so there's one step of the
discriminator we do that either 5 or 5
or 100 times make our discriminator not
trainable and then do one step of the
generator you can see here we call
generator with some noise and then pass
it into the discriminator to see if we
tricked it or not so during the week you
can look at this these two different
versions and you're going to see
basically the pi torch and the carrot
version of basically the same thing and
the only difference is in the two things
one is the presence of this clamping and
the second is that the loss function is
mean squared error rather than cross
interview
so let's see what happens here is
samples from 510
so they're like certainly a lot better
than our crappy DT game mm most examples
but they're not great why are they not
great so probably the reason they're not
great is because say 510 has quite a few
categories different kinds of categories
of different kinds of things and so it
doesn't really know what it's meant to
be drawing a picture of sometimes I
guess it kind of pickets it out like
this must be a plan I think but a lot of
the time it's kind of it hatches and
kind of draws a picture of something
that looks like it might be a reasonable
picture but it's not a picture of
anything in particular on the other hand
the elf son data set as 3 million
bedrooms so we would hope that when we
train the vastest and Gannon else on
bedrooms we might get better results
so but here's the real side by 10 by the
way
so here are a fake victims
and they are pretty freaking awesome so
literally they started out as random
noise and everyone has been turned in
like that definitely a bedroom when
they're all definitely different and so
and then here is the real victims to
compare you can kind of see here that
like imagine if you talk of this and
stuck it on the end of
kind of generator you could you know I
think really use this to make your
generator much more believable you know
like whatever any time you kind of look
at it you say oh that doesn't look like
the real X maybe you could try using a W
again to try to make it look more like a
real next
so this paper is that and like so
important like this is basically so
here's the other thing the last the lost
function for these actually makes sense
like the discriminator and the generator
loss functions actually decrease as they
get better so you can actually tell if
your thing is training properly you can
actually kind of you can't exactly
compare through different architectures
to each other still but you can
certainly see that the training code
sort of working so now that we like have
you know in my opinion a gain that
actually really works reliably for the
first time ever I thought like this
changes the whole kind of changes the
equation for what generators can and
can't do and this has not been applied
to anything yet so you can take any old
paper that produces 3d outputs or
segmentations or depth outputs oil
colorization or whatever and add this
and it would be great to see what
happens right because none of that's
been done before and it's not been done
before because we haven't had a good way
to train can swivel so
you know this is kind of I think
something where anybody who's interested
in in a project yeah this would be a
great project and something that maybe
you can do reasonably quickly another
thing you could do as a project is to
convert this into chaos
like so you can take the care of dcen
notebook that we've already got and
change the loss function at the weight
tipping and try training on this elf own
bedroom data set and you should get the
same results and then you can add this
on top of your any of your care of stuff
so yeah there's so much you could do
this week I'm I don't feel like I want
to give you a assignment per se because
there's a thousand assignments you could
do I think you know as per usual you
should go back and look at the papers
the original Dan paper is a fairly easy
read there's a section called
theoretical results which is like this
is kind of like the pointless math bit
you know like here's some theoretical
stuff it's actually interesting to read
this now because like you go back and
you look at this stuff where they like
prove various nice things about their
game so like they're talking about how
the generative model perfectly
replicates the data generating process
it's interesting to go back and look and
say like okay so they like prove these
things but it turned out to be totally
pointless like like it still didn't work
like it didn't really work so it's kind
of interesting to look back and say oh
so how you know how is it the people we
just doesn't say this isn't a good paper
it is a good paper but it is interesting
to see like when when is the theoretical
stuff useful and we're not well then you
look at the Buffett sign Gann
theoretical sections and it spends a lot
of time talking about why their Theory
actually matters so they have this
really cool example for example that
they say that's creating really simple
what if you want to learn like let's
just parallel lines
and they show like why it is that the
kind of old way of doing games can't
mine parallel lines and then they show
how their different objective function
Emlyn parallel was so I think anybody is
interested in kind of getting into the
theory a little bit it's very
interesting to look at kind of like ok
why did the you know proof of
convergence
you know like showed something that
didn't show something that really turned
out to matter where else in this paper
the theory turned out to be super
important and basically created
something that allowed gangs to work for
the first time so there's lots of stuff
you can get out of these papers if
you're if you're interested in terms of
the notation we might look at some of
the notation a bit a little bit more
next week but if we look for example at
the
see if we can find the algorithm
sections
you
I think in general like the most the bid
I find the most useful nothing nothing
much of a math guy is the bit where they
actually write the pseudocode and even
that it's useful to learn some kind of
nomenclature so for each iteration the h
step easy what does it mean sample noise
samples from noise prior probability no
main structure which you can very
quickly translate but a prior simply
means NP random dot nothing right so in
this case you know we probably like you
know NP random normal so this just means
you know some random number generator
that you get to pick this one here
sample from a data generating
distribution that means randomly pick
some stuff from your array okay so these
are the two steps right generate some
random numbers and then randomly select
some things from your array and actually
in the and there's a bit where you
talked about the gradient you can kind
of lightly ignore except the bit in the
middle is your loss function they can
here you see here this said these things
here is your noise sets your noise okay
so noise generator on noise
discriminator on generator on noise okay
so there's the bit where we're trying to
fool the discriminator and we're trying
to make that trigger so that's why we
drew one minus and then here's the
getting the discriminator to be accurate
because these x's is the real data okay
so that's a math version that will be
displayed the Bossip sign can also has a
algorithm section and so it's kind of
interesting to compare the two
so here we go mr. Stein GAD is the
algorithm and basically this says
exactly the same thing as the last one
said but you know I actually find this
one a big Stara sample from the real
data sample from your priors okay so
hopefully that's enough to get going and
yeah look forward to talking on the
forums and see how everybody gets along
thanks everybody
[Applause]