so welcome back everybody thanks for
coming and I hope you had a good week
and had a fun time playing around with
artistic style I know I did I started to
show you so I tried a couple of things
myself over the week with this artistic
style stuff just like I've tried a
couple a simple little changes which I
thought you might be interested in
yeah Oh actually yeah okay so one thing
before I talk about the artistic style
is I just want to point out some of the
really cool stuff that people think
contributing over the over the week if
you haven't come across it yet be sure
to check out the wiki so the there's a
nice thing in this course where you can
basically fit any post as being a wiki
which means it anybody can edit it so I
chose this wiki post early on and by the
end of the week we now have and all
kinds of stuff with the links to the
stuff from a class a summary of paper
examples a list of all the limp folk
snippets handy listed steps that a kind
of stew necessary when you do install
transfer and lots of stuff about the
10th uploaded summer and so forth we
keep it every week so look over that and
lots of other threads one sources are
going to popped up which is great from
chin chin country and talked about
trying to summarize what they've learned
from lots of other threads across the
weekend this is really straight across
their forum this is a great thing that
we can all do is you know when you look
at lots of different things and kind of
take some notes so if you put them on a
forum for everybody else and this is
super handy and so if you haven't quite
caught up on all the stuff here on the
forum looking at this curating listen at
experiments rapidly probably very close
to CERN
so a couple of little changes I made in
my experiments
I tried thinking about like why'd what
quite appear if you pointed out how
depending on what your starting point is
to your optimizer you get to a very
different place and so clearly our
convex optimization is I'm not
necessarily finding a local minimum but
at least saddle point is not getting out
of so I tried something which was to
create a take the random image and just
add a Gaussian blur to it so calcium
filter is just a blur and so that makes
the random image into this kind of thing
and I just found that even the playing
style looks a lot smoother and that is
one change that I made which I thought
worked quite well another change that I
made just to play around with it was
they added a different weight to each of
the style layers and so my mosaic now
has a third thing in which is the
weights notice modified by the weight
and so I thought that those two things
made my little bird book a significantly
better than motor Bieber book before so
I thank you in that you could do a
similar thing for content loss you could
and also maybe add more different layers
of content lost and pick some different
weights as well and I'm sure if anybody
tried that as yet
particular question and the question
regards I remember cartoon the cartoons
and we think of transferring the style
what we really mean is transferring the
contours of the cartoons redraw the
content in that style and this is not
what style transferring is doing here
how might one implemented yeah I don't
know that anybody's quite to get that
out but I'll show you a couple of
directions that may be useful as yeah
I've tried selecting activations
correspond with edges and such as
indicated by one of the cons
visualization papers and sharing outputs
or specifically those activation yeah
yeah so I'll show you something so some
things you could try I haven't seen
anybody through a great focus yet but I
mean here's one example from the from
the forum is somebody pointed out that
it's cartoon approach didn't work very
well with dota 2 but then when they
change their initial image not to be
random but to be the picture of the dog
it actually looked quite a lot better
and so there's one thing you could try
there's some very helpful diagrams and
some somebody posed too which is
fantastic is summarizing what we learned
I liked this summary of what happens if
you add versus remove each layer so this
is what happens if you remove block 0
block 1 to block 3 and block 4 to get a
sense of how they impact things so you
can see for the style that the last
layer is really important to making it a
little group coming to the finish
why don't you have some particularly
nice examples I loved it like seems like
there's a certain taste they're kind of
figuring out what photos covered what
images like of this Einstein the truth I
thought this wasn't terrific as well
Brad came up with this really
interesting insight that starting with
this picture and adding that style to it
creates this extraordinary shape here
whereas expense out you can tell us the
man sitting in the corner but is like
ten brushstrokes but sometimes is that
what can survive being Bishop
surprisingly fantastic um I have no idea
what this is even in the photo so I've
noticed what the fan thing I did I guess
I don't watch that kind of music enough
so there's lots of interesting ideas you
can try and I've got a link here in the
you might have seen it in the PowerPoint
to a Kaos implementation that has a
whole list of things that you can try
and here are some particular examples
this is something called and all of
these examples you can get the details
shown in certainly there's something
called chain blurring and to some things
this is this might work for cartoons
notice how the matrix doesn't do a good
job with the cat when you use the bullet
classic this is our paper right but if
you use this chain word approach it does
a fantastic job and so I wonder if that
might be one secret to the cartoons
some of you I saw in the forum we've
already tried this which is using color
preservation and luminance matching
which basically means you're still
taking the style which you're not taking
the color and I think in these
particular examples this is really great
results I think it depends a lot on what
working to try to lose and you can go a
lot further for example you can add a
mask and then say just to color
preservation for one part of the photo
so here the top part of the photo has
got color preservation and the bottom
hasn't for evil um
they even show in that code how you can
use a mask to say one part of my image
should not be stylized and again I'm
getting somebody results well it is
really crazy use masks to decide which
one of two style images to use and then
you can really generate some creative
stuff so as one of the suspects we can
play with them you can go beyond this
coming up at your own areas
now some of the best stuff you're going
to learn a bit more today about how to
do some of these things better
but just to give an idea if you go to
like move net you can literally draw
something using four colors and then
choose a style image and it will turn
your drawing into an inch it's basically
a deadly with blue is going to be water
and green is going to be full edition
because red is going to be foreground
but there's a lot of good examples of
this kind of neural doodle
they call it automate something else
we'll learn more about how to do better
today is if you've got a fine layer comm
there's a very rich and paper cortex
depicts which is basically we're going
to be learning quite a bit in this class
about how to do segmentation which is
where you take a photo and turn it into
a comet image basically saying the
horses here the bicycles here the
person's here this is basically doing
the opposite is that by drawing
something saying I want you to create
something that has a window here and a
windowsill here and draw here and column
there and it generates a photo which is
fairly remarkable so the stuff we've
learnt so far won't quite get you
through these two things but by the end
of the day we should be able to this is
a nice example that I think some folks
at Adobe built showing that you could
basically draw something and it will try
and generate an image that is close to
your drawing where you just needed a
small number of lines and again you can
find this but we'll link to this paper
from the resources and this actually
shows to you in real time you can see
that this
there's some new way of doing art that
studies work here where you don't
necessarily need a lot of technique I'm
not commenting it's going to tell you
into a bear got but you can at least
generate images that may be in your head
in some style that someone's doing a lot
of somebody else's I think it's really
interesting okay one thing I was thrill
to see is that at least two of you have
already written blog post so I'm medium
that was fantastic see so I hope more if
you might try to do that this week
definitely doesn't need to be something
that takes a long time and I know some
of you already planet also planning on
telling your forum posts into blog posts
hopefully we'll see a lot more blog
posts this week and popping on I know
the people have done that have found
that a digital experience as well so one
of the things that I suggested doing
pretty high on the list of priorities
for this week's assignment was to go
through the paper knowing what it's
going to say you know I think this is
really helpful is when you already know
how to do something is to go back over
that paper and this is a great way to
learn how to repeat it because you
already know what it's telling you this
is like the way I learn to read papers
was totally this method so I'm going to
come through and I've highlighted a few
key things which I as I went through I
thought were kind of important so in the
abstract of the paper but let me ask say
how many people kind of went back and
relook to this paper again but a few
okay so
abstracts they basically say what is it
they're reducing so it's a system based
on a deep neural network that create
artistic images and high perceptual
quality okay so we're going to read this
paper and hopefully at the end of it we
will know how to do that then in the
first section there tell us about the
basic ideas
so when CNN's obtained an object
recognition they developed a
representation of an image along the
processing hierarchy that network is
transformed into representations to
increasingly care about the actual
content compared to the pixel values so
it describes the basic idea of content
models and then they describe the basic
idea of spiralize which is looking at
the correlations between the different
filter responses over the spatial
extents of the picture nests and it is
one of these sentences that read on its
own doesn't mean very much now that we
know how to do it you can read it in
this way okay okay so what that means
and then when you get to the method
section we learn more so the idea here
is that by including the feature
correlation so this answers one of the
questions that we want to be had on a
form by including feature correlations
of multiple layers we obtained a multi
scale representation of the input image
this idea of a multi scale
representation is something we're gonna
be coming for across a lot because a lot
of this as we discussed last week a lot
of this class is about generative models
and one of the tricky things that
generative models is both to get the
kind of the general idea of the thing
you're trying to generate correct should
also get all the details correct and so
the details generally requires you to
zoom in to a small scale and getting the
kind of big picture corrected about
zooming out to a large scale so this was
one of the key things that in this paper
was show you how to create a spiral
representation that included multiple
resolutions and we know now know that
where they did that was to use multiple
style layers and as we go through the
layers of each eg they gradually become
lower and lower resolution uttering
larger receptive fields
creates a look at the figures and make
sure another thrill to see that some of
you were trying to recreate these
figures which actually turns out to be
slightly non-trivial so we can see
exactly what that figure is and if you
haven't tried it for yourself yet you
might want to try it see if you can
recreate this figure
um okay it's good to try and find in a
paper the key finding you know the key
the key thing that they're showing in
this case they found that
representations of content and style and
a CNN a separable and you can manipulate
both create new new users is again
hopefully that now we look at that and
say oh yeah that makes sense
you
you can see that with papers certainly
with this paper there's often quite a
lot of introduction that often says the
same thing about your different ways so
it's often worth you know the first time
you read it one paragraph might not make
sense but later on they say a different
way in it that's to make more sense so
it's worth looking through the
introductory remarks maybe two or three
times
um they can certainly see they're
cooking talking about the different
layers and how they have
again showing
results of some experiments again you
can see if you can recreate these
experiments make sure that you
understand how to do it and then there's
a kind of whole lot of stuff I didn't
find that interesting until we get to
the section called methods so the method
section is the section that hopefully
you'll learn the most about reading
papers after you've implemented
something by reading the section called
methods now I want to show you a few
little tricks if notation you did it to
be careful of little details that fly by
it like here they use average pulley as
the sentence which if you weren't
reading
carefully you could skip over now we
know okay we need to use average volume
on masculine
so they will often have a section which
explicitly says now I'm going to
introduce the notation and this paper
doesn't then paper just type introduces
the notation as part of the discussion
area but at some point you'll start
getting great letters or you know things
with subscripts or whatever notation
starts appearing and so at this point
you need to start looking very carefully
and at least for me I find I have to go
back and read something many times to
remember what's l what's M what's there
okay this is the annoying thing with
math notation is single letters they
generally don't have any amount of
mnemonic often though you'll find that
across papers in a particular field
they'll tend to reuse the same kind of
English and Greek letters for the same
kinds of things right so M will
generally be the number of rows capital
n capital n will often be the number of
columns K will often be the index that
you're summing over so on and so forth
um so here we've got the first thing
which is introduced is X with an arrow
on top so X with an arrow on top meant
is the vector right it's actually an
input image but they're going to turn it
into a vector by flattening it out
so okay so our image is called s and
then the CNN has a whole bunch of layers
and every time you see something with a
subscript or superscript like this you
need to look at both of the two bits
because it goes for a meaning right the
thing the big thing is like the main
object so in this case a capital N is a
filter and then the subscript or
superscript is like in an array or a
tensor in Python it's like the thing in
square brackets right so each filter has
a letter L which is like which number of
the filter is a and so often as I read a
paper I'll actually try to write code as
I go and like put little comments so
that are like right layer square bracket
layer number close square bracket and I
have a comment after there like n yeah
that was to remind myself so I'm trading
the code and mapping it to the lives so
there any old filters we know from a CNN
that each filter creates a feature map
so that's why there are in our picture
nets so remember anytime you see the
same letter it means the same D come
within a pepper not necessarily
processors each fixture map is of size M
and as I mentioned before M tends to be
rows M tends to be columns so here it
says M is the height times the width of
the feature mass so here we can see if
it is they've got plan basically to make
it all one row
now this is another piece of notation
you'll see all the time a layer L can be
stored in a matrix called F for now the
elbow to the top doesn't matter
same basic idea just an index so the
matrix F is going to contain our
activations and this thing here where it
says R with a little superscript this
has a very special meaning it's
referring to basically what is the shape
for this so when you see this shape it
says these are our means that air flows
and this thing here means that the
matrix you can see the X so means it's
rose by a column so there n rows and n
columns in this matrix and every matrix
there's one matrix each layer and
there's different number of rows and
remember columns each layer so you can
basically go through and map it to the
color that you're already written so I'm
not going to read through the whole
thing but there's not very much here and
being good to make sure that you
understand all of us perhaps with the
exception of the derivatives because we
don't care about derivatives because
they get done Boris and Sofie Arnault in
terms of flow so you can always skip the
bits about derivatives
ok so then they do the same thing
basically just writing the grand matrix
so they show here that the basic idea of
the grand matrix is that they create an
inner product between the vector eyes
feature map inj so vector right here
means turned into a vector so the way
you turn a matrix into a vector is
lambda this is the flattened inner
product between the flattened feature
masks so those matrices we saw now so
I'll clear your
it's helpful your theater will be like
small little differences so rather than
taking the mean they tend to use here
the sum and then they kind of divide
that out the number of rows and columns
to kind of create a mean this way in our
code we actually put division inside the
sum and seriously these little
differences of how we implement things
and sometimes you may seem see actual
meaningful differences and that's often
a suggestion of like others some you
need to try you know so the difference
is your control
okay so let's subscribe see the notation
and the method and that's it but then
very importantly is throughout this
anytime you come across some concept
which you're not familiar with it'll
pretty much always have a reference for
citation right so you'll see there's
you
little numbers all over the place
there's lots of different ways ordering
these references but anytime you come
across something which has a citation
like it's a new piece of notation or a
new concept you don't know what it is
generally the first time I see it in a
paper I ignore it alright but if I keep
reading and it turns out to be something
that actually is important and I can't
understand the basic idea at all I
generally then put this paper aside I
put it in my to read file and make the
new paper I'm reading the thing that is
floating because like very often a paper
is entirely meaningless until you've
read one or two of the key takers it's
better
sometimes this can be like reading the
dictionary if you don't get low English
it can be like layer upon layer of
citations at some point you have to stop
I generally thought you should I think
you should find that the basic set of
papers that things refer to is pretty
much all stuff you guys know at this
point I don't think you're going to get
start to an infinite loop but if you
ever do you know let let us know in the
forum and we're trying to help you get
unstuck well if there's any notation you
don't understand let us know when other
was a horrible things about math is it's
very how to search for you know not like
you can take that function name and
search for typing in the function names
to do some weird squiggly shape and so
again feel free to up if you're not sure
about there and there is a great
Wikipedia page which lists I think it's
just called notate our math notation or
something which lists pretty much every
piece of notation there are various
places you can look at notation as well
okay so that's the place
yes let's move to the next step so I
think what I might do is to kind of try
and draw the basic idea of what we did
before so that I can draw the idea of
what we're going to do differently this
time
so previously and now this thing is
actually calibrated you'll be pleased to
hear we had an a random image
and we had
a loss function doesn't matter what the
loss function was right we know that it
happened to be a combination of style
lofts Plus content was okay and what we
did was we took our image and we're our
random image and we put it through this
loss function and we got out of it two
things one was the loss and the other
words the gradients
and then we use the gradients with
respect to the original pixels to change
the original pixels okay and so we've
basically repeated that loop again and
again and the pixels gradually change to
make the loss go down
so that's the basic approach that we
just used it's a perfectly fine approach
for what it is and in fact for if you
are wanting to do lots of different
photos with lots of different files like
if you created a web app where you said
please upload any file image and any
Content image
here's your artistic style version this
is probably still the best particularly
with some of those tweaks I talked about
but what if you wanted to create a web
app that was a van Gogh Iris's generator
upload any image and I will give you
that image in the style of their most
irises
you can do better than this approach and
the reason you can do better is that we
can do something where you don't have to
do a whole optimization run in order to
create that output instead we can train
a CNN to learn to output photos in the
cyber band God's irises the basic idea
is very similar and what we're going to
do this time is we're going to have lots
of images right and we're going to take
each image and we're going to feed it
into the exact same lost function that
we use before right with a zero loss of
the content lives right but we're going
to use for the style loss we're going to
use van Gogh irises and for the content
loss we're going to use the image that
we're currently looking at we've got
lots of images going to go through
and what we do is we're going to rather
than changing the pixels of the original
photo instead what we're going to do is
we're going to train a CNN so a whole
bunch of layers of a CNN we're going to
train a CNN to take this
the best way to choose let's move this
out of the way
yeah so let's put a CNN in the middle
this is the layers of the CNN all right
and we're going to try and get that CNN
to spit out a new image so there's an
input image and as an output image and
this new CNN we've created is going to
spit out an output image that when you
put it through this loss function
hopefully it's going to give a small
number and if it is a small number it
means that the content of this photo
still looks like the original photo is
content and the style of this new image
looks like a style of band off saracens
so if you think about it
when you have a CNN
you can really take any loss function
you like right we objected to using
pretty simple most functions so far like
mean squared error or cross cross
entropy in this case we're going to use
a very different loss function which is
going to be style plus content loss
using the same approach that we use just
the flow okay and because that was
generated by a neural net
we know it's differentiable and you can
optimize any loss function as long as
the loss function is differentiable so
if we now basically take the gradients
of this output not with respect to the
input image but with respect to the CNN
weights and we can take those gradients
and use them to update the weight to the
CNN so that the next iteration through
the CNN will be slightly better at
turning that image into a picture that
has a good sail magic with the angle
Cyrus's does that make sense so at the
end of this we run this through lots of
images just because training a regular
CNN and the only thing we've done
differently is to replace the lost
function with the style loss plus
content loss and that we just use and so
at the end of it we're going to have a
CNN that is learnt to take any photo and
we'll fit out that photo in a style of
bangle Cyrus's and so this is a win
because it means now in your web app
which is your van Gogh irises generator
you now don't have to run an
optimization path on the new photo you
just do a single forward pass to a CNN
which is instant
yes greenbox over there
and so this can limit the children see
looks ready significantly you like let's
say you have Photoshop if you want to
change multiple styles yeah this is
going to this is going to each neural
network you can learn to just one type
of side that their way of like combining
multiple styles or is it just going to
be a combination you can combine
multiple sales by just like having
multiple bits of style of the multiple
images it's not going to have the
problems that that network has only
learned to create one kind of image it
hasn't learnt now it may be possible to
treat to Train it to the text photo
style image and the content niche but
don't think I've seen I've done it early
on
okay it's a very version having clip
that there is something simpler and in
my opinion more useful we can loop which
is rather than doing style loss plus
content lights let's think of another
interesting problem to solve which is
called super resolution super resolution
is something which honestly when Rachel
and I started playing around with it a
while ago nobody was that interested in
it but in the last year or so it's
become really hot yes Rachel yeah yeah
so we were kind of playing around at the
club and what we thought it's really
interesting but suddenly it's got hot
and the basic idea of super resolution
is that you start off with a low res
photo so the reason I started getting
interested in this because I wanted to
help my mom take her family photos that
were often pretty low quality and blow
them up into something that was big and
high quality is you can print out so
that's what you do is you're trying to
take something which starts with a small
low res photo and turns it into a big
high res photo LR low res H
IRA's now perhaps you can see that we
can use a very similar technique for
this what we could do is between the low
res photo and the high res photo we
could introduce
at CNN
all right and what that say and let CNN
could look a lot like the CNN from our
last idea but it's taking in as input a
low-res for image and then it's sticking
it into a loss function
and the last function is only going to
calculate content loss and the content
logic will calculate is between the
input that is brought from the low-res
after going through the CNN compared to
the activations from the high ribbons so
in other words have CNN successfully
created a bigger photo that has the same
activations as the high-res photo does
and so if we pick the right layer for
the high-res photo then that ought to
mean that we've constructed a new image
what's the ratio there's a question can
we just stick at CNN between any two
things and it will learn the
relationship yes absolutely and this is
one of the things I wanted to talk about
today is in fact I think it's at the
start of the next paper we're going to
look at if they even kind of talk about
it so this is the paper we're going to
look at today perceptual losses for
real-time style transparency resolutions
this is trim in 2016 so it took like
about a year or so to go from the thing
we just saw to this next stage and 0.o
maybe half year okay so what they point
out in the abstract here is that people
had done to resolution with CNN before
but previously the last function they
use to simply the mean squared error
between the pixel outputs of the scaling
Network and the actual high-res image
and the problem is that it turns out
that that tends to create blurry images
and attempt to create blurring images
because the the CNN has no reason not to
create blurry images and blurry images
to actually tend to look pretty good in
the last function because as long as you
get the general you know oh this is
probably somebody's face I'll put like a
face color here and it's going to be
fine where else if you take the second
or third comb flock of vgg then it needs
to know that this is an eyeball or it's
not going to look good right this no
this is the mode it's not good so if you
do it not with pixel loss but with the
content loss we just learnt about
you're probably going to get better
results so this like many papers and
defining this paper introduces its own
language and in the language of this
paper perceptual was is what they call
the main squared errors between the
activations of a network with two images
so the current thing we've been calling
content was they call deception world
one of the nice things they do at the
start of this and I really like it when
peppers do this is to say okay why is
this paper important well this paper is
important because many problems can be
found at image transformation tasks
where a system of some input and Chuck's
out some other output for example
denoising learn to take an input images
full of noise and spit out a beautifully
clean image super-resolution take an
input image which is low res and spit at
a high risk colorization they can import
image which is black and white and spit
out something is just color now one of
the interesting things here is that all
of these examples you can generate as
much input data as you'd like by taking
lots of images to each other from your
camera or exam load on the internet or
from internet and you can make them
lower res you can add noise you can make
them black and white right so you can
generate as much level better as emotion
less one of the really cool things about
this whole topic of generators vectors
to your left but a debt has to do
something well with 30 people so
only the lower less imagery and it's
algorithmically done so just so knowing
that only going to learn how to like
transfer out something is
algorithmically done versus an actual
lower than the jury that doesn't act
like
yeah so one thing I'll just mention is
the way you would create your label data
is not to do that low res on the camera
you would grab the images that you've
already taken and make them low res just
by doing filtering you know in open CV
or whatever and yes that is algorithmic
and it may not be it may not be perfect
but there's lots of ways of generating
that low res image you know you can add
yes so there's lots of ways of creating
a low res image so part of it is about
how do you do that creation of low res
image and how well you match the real
low res data you're going to be getting
then in the end in this case things like
low resolution images or black-and-white
images it's so hard to start with
something that's just like it could be
like an a as seen versions with just an
8x8 picture and turning it into a photo
like it's so hard to do that regardless
of how that APA thing was created that
often the details of Albert low res
image was created don't really matter
too much um there are some other
examples they mentioned which is turning
an image into an image which is
segmentation we learn more about this in
coming lessons so the segmentation
refers to taking a photo of something
and creating a new image that basically
has a different color for each object
clear horses a green car the blue
buildings are red that's anything that
is called segmentation as you know from
things like the fisheries competition
segmentation can be really important as
a part of solving other bigger problems
another example they mention here is
depth estimation there's lots of
important reasons you would want to use
depth estimation for example maybe you
want to create some fancy video effect
where you start with a flat photo and
you want to create some cool new Apple
TV thing that like moves around the
photo the parallax effect you know is
difficult ridi so if you were able to
use a CNN to figure out how far away
every object was automatically
and you could like turn 2d photo into a
3d image automatically so yeah taking an
image and sixteen image out is kind of
the idea in computer vision at least of
generative networks or generative models
and this is why I wanted to talk a lot
about generative models during this fuss
it's not just about artistic style
artistic style is just no sneaky way of
introducing you to the world of
generative models okay so let's look at
how to create this super resolution idea
and your homework or part of your
homework this week will be to create the
new approach to style transfer okay so
I'm going to build the super resolution
version which is a slightly simpler
version and then you're going to try and
build on top of that to create the sale
transfer efficient okay so make sure you
let me know if you're not sure at any
point so I've already created a folder
of twenty thousand a sample of 20,000
image net images and I've created two
sizes one is to a taper to 80 and one is
72 by 72 and they're available as a big
hole to raise
and okay so I actually posted the link
to these last week and it's on
platformed on Part VI so we'll open up
those big holes arrays and one trick you
might have perfectly learnt in part one
is that you can turn a big full array
into a numpy array by slicing it with
everything and so anytime you slice the
big holes array you get that numpy array
so if your slices everything and then
this turns it into a non-player this is
just a convenient way of sharing numpy
errors in this case so we've now got an
array of low resolution images and an
array of high resolution images so let
me start start maybe by showing you the
final Network
okay this is the final network so we
start on off by taking in a batch of
images low res images and the very first
thing we do is stick them through a
convolutional block with a straight of
one okay this is not going to change its
size at all but a convolutional block at
the filter size of nine
and it generates 64 filters so this is a
very large filter size essentially
nowadays filter size of 73 actually in a
lot of modern networks the very first
layer is very often a large filter size
just the one just one very first layer
and the reason is that it basically
allows us to immediately increase the
receptive field of all of the layers
renowned so by having mine by nine and
we don't lose any information because
we've gone from three channels to 64
filters okay so each of these nine by
nine convolutions can actually have
quite a lot of information because we've
got 64 filters so you'll be seeing this
quite a lot in modern CNN architectures
just a single large filter comes layer
of this won't be unusual under the
future now the next thing out is a green
box behind you
oh just a moment sir yeah describe one
of those are pretty popular pieces yeah
well the striped one is important for
this first layer because you don't want
to throw away any information yet right
so the very first layer we want to keep
the full image size so with Austrade one
it doesn't change it doesn't down temple
at all there's also a lot of
complication rate that in mind mr.
Seidman yeah it is a big overlap a lot
absolutely but that's okay a a good
implementation of a convolution is going
to hopefully memorize some of that or
just keep it in cash so hopefully what
slow it down too much
one of the discussions I was just having
during the break was like
how how practical you know other things
that we're learning at the moment
compared to like part one where
everything was just designed entirely
revealer here those practical things
which we have best practices for and the
answer is like a lot of the stuff you're
going to be learning no one quite knows
how practical it is because a lot of it
just hasn't really been around that long
and little bit under stored and move
there only great libraries for it yet so
one of the things I'm actually hoping
from this part too is by learning the
edge of research staff will be on
amongst a diverse group is that some of
you will look at it and think about your
whatever you do nine to five or eight oh
six or whatever and think oh I wonder if
I could use that for this and if that
ever pops into your head
please tell us grad please top happen on
the forum because that's that's what
we're most interested in it's like
although you could choose
super-resolution burglar or death
finding for this or generative models in
general for this thing you know I do in
pathology or architecture or satellite
engineering or whatever so
to terrify some imagination of plants on
your part and so often that's why I do
want to spend some time looking at stuff
like this where it's like okay what are
the kinds of things this could be done
for but one of the you know I'm sure you
know in your own field like one of the
differences between expert and the gear
is the way an expert can look at
something in first principles and say
okay I could use that for this totally
different thing which is what nothing to
do with the example that was originally
given to you because I know that the
basic sets are the same and that's what
I'm hoping you guys will will be able to
do is kind of not just say oh this is
rather better it again just since
yeah it's not to say okay now I know how
to do much this ik so you know are there
things in your field which have some
similarities to so we were going to talk
about on the super resolution
and we talked about the idea of the
initial cannot sew up the initial
complex we have the computation and I
save their computation and any kind of
generative network there's like the exit
the key work it has to do which in this
case is starting with a low res image
figure out like what might that blacktop
be is it is an able or is it like is a
wheel like it basically if you want to
do really good upscaling
you actually have to stick it out what
the objects are so that you know what to
draw back so that's kind of like the key
computation is CNN is going to have to
learn to do in generative models we
generally like to do that computation at
a low revolution and there's a couple
reasons why the first is that at a low
resolution is less work to do so the
computation is faster but more
importantly at higher resolutions which
generally means we have a smaller
receptive field it generally means we
have less ability to kind of catch a
large amount of the image at once and if
you want to do really really great and
the computations where you recognize
that oh this this blob here is a face
and therefore the dot inside of this
eyeball then you're going to need enough
of a receptive field to cover that whole
area I noticed a couple of you asked for
information about receptive fields on
the forum thread so there's some a lot
of information about this online so
Google is your friend here that the
basic idea is if you have a single
convolutional filter or 3x3 the
receptive field is 3-bedroom so it's how
much space can that convolution your
filter in sense
okay so here's our 3x3 filter now on the
other hand what if you had a tree by
tree filter
which had a 3x3 filter as its input
right so that means that the center one
to call up this right but what is this
one take well this one would have taken
depending on the stride probably these
ones here and and this one over here
will taken
these ones here so in other words in the
second layer assuming a strata one the
receptive field is now five by five not
three by three okay so the receptive
field depends on two things one is how
many layers deep are you and secondly is
how much did the previous layers either
have a non unit stride or maybe they
have max cooling and so in some way they
were coming down sample those two things
increase the receptors here and so the
reason it's great to be doing layer
computations on a large receptive field
is that it then allows you to look at
the big picture and look at the context
not just edges anymore the eyeballs and
nervous so in this case we have four
blocks of computation where each block
is a red network so for those of you
that don't recall how resident works it
would be a good idea to go back to part
one and review but to remind ourselves
let's look at the code here's a resident
one so all the red step blocks does is a
checksum input and it does two
convolutional blocks on that input and
that is adds the result of those
convolutions back to the original input
so you might remember can part one we
actually kind of drew it whether there's
an input and it goes through two
convolutional blocks
and then it goes back and is added to
the original and if you remember we
basically said in that case we've got y
equals x plus some function of X and
which means that the function equals
why minus X and this thing here is a
residual right to a whole stack of
residual blocks resident blocks on top
of each other can learn to gradually get
hone in on their whatever it's going to
do in this case what it's trying to do
is get the information it's going to
need to upscale distance nowhere so
we're going to be using a lot more of
this idea of kind of taking blocks that
we know work well to something and just
reuse them and so then what about the
comp lock well all the term fuck is in
this case is it's a convolution followed
by a batch norm optionally followed by
an activation and one of the things we
now know about resident blocks is that
we generally don't want an activation at
the end and that's one of the themes of
the more recent taper discovered you can
see that's my second home block area no
exhibition I'm sure you've noticed
throughout this course that I refactor
my network architectures a lot my
network architectures don't generally
listen every single layer that they're
generally functions which had a bunch of
functions is there a bunch of layers in
a lot of people don't do this it's like
a lot of the architecture to fine online
like hundreds of line of layer
definitions I think that's crazy it's so
easy to make mistakes when you do it
that way and so how to really see what's
going on
so if you know in general I would
strongly recommend if you try to read
back to your architectures so that by
the time you write the final thing it's
you don't pop the page and you'll see
plenty of examples of that so we though
that'll be awful
all right so we've increased the
receptive field we've done a bunch of
computation but we still haven't
actually changed the size of the image
which is not very helpful so the next
thing we do is going to change the size
of the image and the first thing we're
going to learn is to do that with
something that goes by many names
some what is deconvolution another is
and it's also known as transposed
convolutions
and it's also known as fractionally
strided convolutions in carrots they
call the deconvolution and the basic
idea is something which I've actually
got a spreadsheet to show you okay so
here's pitch here's a spreadsheet the
basic idea is that you've got some kind
of initially here's a four by four image
for whiteboard area all right and you
put it through the 3x3 filter
convolutional filter and if you're doing
valid convolutions and that's going to
leave you with a 2x2 output because
here's one 3x3 another 3x3 practical
four of them and so each one is having
the whole filter and the appropriate
part of the data is just a standard 2d
accomplished so we've done that now
let's say we want to undo that right we
want something which can take this
result and recreate this input how would
you do that so one way to do that would
be to take this result and so it's
popular here right and put back that
implicit padding so it's surrounded with
all these zeros such that now if we use
let's have some filter would have
started at zero and we have some
convolutional filter okay and we're
going to put it through this entire
matrix a bunch of zeros with our result
metrics in the middle and then we can
calculate our results in exactly the
same way just a normal conversational
gutter so if we now use gradient descent
we can look at and see okay what is the
error right so how much does this pixel
differ from this stencil and how much
says this pixel difference in this pixel
and let me add them all together to get
our mean square error so we can now use
gradient descent let's check to your
nutrition pipeline in excel is called
solver
and we can say okay set this cell to a
minimum by changing these cells okay so
this is basically like the simplest
possible optimization fold that
and here's what it's carpet right so
it's come up with a convolutional filter
you'll see that the result is not
exactly the same as the original data
and of course how could it be right we
don't have enough information we only
have four things that try and regenerate
16 things but it's not terrible and in
general this is this is a challenge with
upscale right when you've got them in
this forward and down sampled if you've
thrown away information I said any way
you can get information back is to guess
what was there but the important thing
is that by using a convolution like this
we can learn those filters so we can
learn how to up sample it in a way that
gives us the loss that we want so this
is what a deconvolution is it's just a
convolution on a padded input now in
this case I've assumed that my
convolutions had a unit straight it was
just one pixel the cleaning solution if
your convolutions are straight to that
it looks like this picture
okay and you can see that as well as
putting the two pixels around the
outside we've also put a zero pixel in
the middle that so these four cells is
now our data cells and you can see it
calculating convolution through here as
John we suggest looking at this link
which is where this picture comes from
and in turn this link comes from a
fantastic paper called the convolution
arithmetic guide which is a really great
paper and so if you want to know more
about both convolutions and D
convolutions you can look at this page
and it's got lots of beautiful
animations including animations on they
call a transpose revolutions and so you
can see there we go this is the one I
just showed you all right so I want you
to saw in Excel ton so that's a good
really great flow
okay so that's what we're going to do
first is we're going to do D
convolutions so in Kara a deconvolution
is exactly the same as convolution
except with te on the front but all the
same stuff how many filters to one
what's the size of your filter
what's your stride or subsample as they
call it on auto mode circles
the question is tensor flows the back
end shouldn't Sebastian normalization
axis equals negative 1
you
and then there was a link to github
conversation where Francois said that
for Theon oh I know it's tricky and
affects access minus one is the default
so yes thank you
most butter thanks David Guttman he is
also responsible for some of our
beautiful pictures you saw earlier as I
was interested again let's remove this
that way fucking look at that and go
faster as well so just in case you went
clear on that you might remember from
part one that we reason we have that
access equals one is because Indiana doe
the channel axis so we basically wanted
not to throw away the XY information
that National Lacrosse had in piano and
channel will never last answers and
since have minus one is the default
should I visit
um okay so that's therapy completion
blocks and so we're using a strive of 2
comma 2 alright so that means that each
time you go through this C convolution
it's going to be doubling the size of
the image for some reason I don't fully
understand and haven't really looked
into in care ups you actually have to
tell it the shape of the output so you
can see here I've actually SH you can
actually see but from 72 by 72 to 144 by
144 to 288 283 assess learning to
upscale and it's not upscaling there's
just three channels it's subsiding with
64 filters so that's how can a parent do
what is Chester and then finally we
we're kind of reversing things here we
have another treat like another 9 by 9
convolution in order to get back to our
3 channels so the idea is we've
previously have something with 64
channels and so we now wanted to invent
something there's three channels for
three pallets and to do that we want to
use quite a bit of context so we have a
nine by nine single one by nine filter
at the end to get our three shelter so
at the end we have a 288 by 288 5 310 in
other words an image
so if we go ahead now and train this
then it's going to do basically what we
want so the thing we're going to do is
to create our last match okay and
creating our loss function is a little
bit messy but I'll take you to it slowly
and her fever will make sense
so we've taken distance remember some of
the symbols here input F is the original
low resolution input gesture and then
the output of this is called a pin at
work and so let's call this whole
network here but followed the up
sampling network and so this is the
thing that's actually responsible doing
the answer so we're going to take the up
sensing network and we're going to
attach it to the GG and the V but V G G
is going to be used only as a loss
function and get the content once
so before we can check this output and
stick it into BCG we need to stick it
through our standard means of traction
pre-processing
so this is just the same thing that we
did over and over again in part one
so let's now define and this output as
being this lambda functions applied to
the 1/2 foot around upsampling
Network okay so that's what this is this
is just our pre-processed up sampling
network
so we can now create a vtg Network
and let's go through every layer and
make it not tradable okay like you can't
ever make your loss function between all
a lot function is fixed in stone thing
that tells you how well you do so
clearly you have to make sure each GG is
not fair
all right now which bidders on the VG G
network we want we can try a few things
I'm using block to con - ok so
relatively early and the reason for that
is that if you remember when we did the
content reconstruction last week the
very first thing we did we found that if
you you could basically totally
reconstruct the original image from
early layer activations where else by
the time reversal layer for a so it's
blocked for we've got pretty horrendous
things right so we're going to use the
somewhat early block as our content loss
or if the paper calls it the perceptual
loss and you can play around this see
how it goes
correct so now we're going to create two
versions of this dgg output and this is
something which is I think very poorly
understood or appreciated with the
carats of functional API which is any
kind of layer and the model is a layer
far as characters concerned can be
treated as if as a function right so we
can take this model and pretend it's a
function and we can't answer any chance
that we like and what that does is it
creates a new model where those two
pieces is joining together okay so the
gg2 is now equal to this model on the
top and lift model on the boat and
remember this model was the result of
our up sampling network ID by P
president and the up sampling network is
the lambda function to normalize the
output image yeah that's a good point so
we use a and activation which can do
negative 1 to 1 so if you then go that
plus 1 times 1 2015 1 half that gives
you something that's between naught into
T to 5 which is the range that we want
interestingly this was suggested in the
original paper and such initial
materials and more recently in rather
than I think it was the author said that
they tried it without puts an activation
and therefore without the final key
processing and it worked just as well so
you can try doing that in order to try
it you just remove the activation and to
distribute this last thing inside but
obviously if you do you have a fan and
you need the output and this is actually
something I've been saying with a lot of
different models any time I have some
particular range that I want and when
way to enforce that is by having a fan
or sigmoid followed by something that
turns out easier
she won not just images okay so we've
got two versions of our vtg layer output
one which is based on the output of the
optical network and the other which is
based on just an employee right and this
just an input is using the
high-resolution ship input okay so that
makes sense because this PGG network is
something that we're going to be using
at the high resolution scale we're going
to be taking the high resolution target
image and high resolution up sampling
results and compare
now that we some of that we're nearly
there we've now got the high res to
sexual activations and we've got the low
res upsampled perceptual activations we
now just need to check the mean sum of
squares between them and here it is here
Sin Cara anytime you put something into
a network that hasn't seen a layer so if
you want to take it just a plain old
function and turn it into a layer you
just chuck it inside a locker there
capital and that's all that form
so our final model is going to check our
up simple input and our sorry our low
res input and our high res input is
actually input and return this loss
function and Apple okay one last trick
when you fit things in Care Act's it
assumes that you're trying to take some
output and make it close to some target
in this case our loss is the actual loss
function we want it's not there's some
target correct we want to make it as low
as possible
and since it's a sum of squared errors
for a mean square error actually it
can't go beneath zero so what we can do
is we can basically check care UPS and
say that our target for the loss is zero
and you can't just use the scalar 0
remember every time we have a target set
of labels in care you need one to every
row rightly one for every input so we're
going to create an array of zeros okay
so that's that's just so that we can fit
it into a chaotic set and I kind of find
that increasingly as I start to move
away from the kind of you know the
trodden path of deep learning more and
more ticket if you want to use care us
you kind of have to do weird little acts
the Soviet is a relative there I'm
probably more elegant ways of doing this
but this works so we've got our love
function that we're trying to get every
row is close to zero possible we have a
question for only using up to block to
cons to could we pop off all the layers
afterwards to say complication sure
wouldn't be ahead of you
okay so we compile it we fit it and one
thing you'll notice I started doing is
using understeer this callback called TQ
DM notebook call back empty QT m is a
really terrific loading and basically it
does something very very simple which is
to add a here at a progress meter to
your loops you can use it in console as
you can see and so basically anywhere
you're going to looking at t QT m around
it okay
and that loops does just what it used to
but it gets progressive and it even
guesses you know how much time is left
in circles you can also use it inside a
gym in a notebook and it creates a neat
little
neat little grant eventually goes up and
shows you how long left and so forth so
this is just a nice little trick you
some learning ready kneeling and at the
end of training it for a few he talks we
can try out a model now the model we're
interested in is just the up sampling
model right they're going to be feeding
the up sampling model loaded inputs and
getting out the high-res applets we
don't actually go to care about the
value of the Lots so I'll now define a
model which takes its input the lower
the input and spits out as output now I
remember
so with that model we can trace call
predicts so here is our original low
resolution mashed potato
and here's a high-resolution editor and
it's it's amazing what it's done like
you can see in the original like the
shadow of the laces are in clear the
kind of the beats in the mashed potato
which is kind of big blobs in this
version we had like their shadows hard
edges and so forth
question can you explain the size of the
target it's the first dimension of the
high-rez times 128 why
you
yes okay so let's see it's this number
so this is the particular number images
that we have
ah and then
it's fun pays oh it's 128 because that
layer has 128 filters so this ends up
giving you the mean square error of 128
mm well since Isis yes there is another
question but popping the unused layers
really save anything aren't you only
getting the layers you want when you do
the BG layer block to cons - yeah I'm
not sure
I don't have a can't quite see quickly
enough you can try it the bundle and
intuitively what features is this model
learning
but what it's learning is looking at
20,000 images very very very low
resolution images like this ad it's
learning like when there's a kind of a
soft gray bit next to a hard bitch you
know in certain situations that's
probably a shadow and when there's a
shadow sort of share example it's
learning that when there's a curve it
doesn't actually need to look like a
jagged edge that it actually does look
like no it's really learning what the
world looks like you know and then when
you take that well and blur it and make
it small you know what does it then
replace and so it's just like when you
when you look at a picture like this
particularly if you like blur your eye
you focus your eyes you can often see
you know what originally look like is
your brain basically is doing the same
thing it's like when you read a really
blurry text you'll read it because the
brain thinking like an old car the help
you need
so are you suggesting there is a similar
universality on the other way around
like you know when vgg saying the first
layers are learning a line and then a
square then those are I are you saying
the same thing is true in this case
yeah absolutely it's an SP when it is no
way to sample all right this is in the
number of ways lots of information so in
order to do it in the way that decreases
log function actually has to figure out
you know what what's probably their
persona so this but don't you agree just
intuitively thinking about it like
example of there you say suggesting like
the album pictures for your mom we do
you think like be easier for just
feeding it pictures of humans because
it's like the interaction of the circle
the eye and the nose if I are like oh
I'm so good in the tree business event
listener to take 8 by 8 inches you'll do
that all of the people keep saying they
essentially equal to 8/3 a these are
pictures of celebrity faces in all
celebrity faces of the reason one you
know and so they show the same time
independent a Canadian Club relating to
people keeps your face and it looks
pretty colors and look because they're
saying eventually you okay we put 40,000
years is imaginaries it's not going to
doing any as well if we want to see as
well as a version sweetly I'm just a
very expensive object it just has a high
for me to imagine mashed potatoes and a
face kind of like in the same category
that's fine yeah the biggest the big key
thing to realize is there's nothing
policy really different between what
necessary looks like a one-person
software so you know something to learn
to recognize the image teaches is
necessary and so in a big enough network
sharing a lot example simpler not just
national photo but writing
and the pictures and so you know for
your examples you'll most likely be
doing thought this is modernized Pacific
and so you should use North American if
data the advantages that you know these
permissions
questioner shit okay so
one thing I mentioned here is I haven't
used to test set
so another piece of the homework is to
add a note out there right and and tell
us it's this mashed-potato
overfit okay this is actually just
matching the particular training set
version of this mashed potato or not and
if it is a de fitting can you can you
create something just doesn't have it
so there's another piece of homework so
I'm it's very simple now to take this
and turn it into our past style transfer
so our style transfer is going to do
exactly the same thing that rather than
taking something turning something
low-res into something high res it's
going to take something that's a photo
and send it into standoff Cyrus's
so we're going to do that in just the
same way we're going to rather than go
from low res through a CNN to find the
content loss against high res we're
going to take a photo go through a CNN
and do both sigh Oh lots and content
lots against a single text sale image
I've given you links here so I have not
implemented this for you this is see you
to implement but I have given you links
to the original paper and very
importantly also to the supplementary
material to the little hard to find
because it's two different versions and
only one of them is correct and a
profitable industry so the supplementary
material goes through all of the exact
details
what was their last function what was
their processing or service architecture
and so on and so forth so while I wait
for this load yeah like we did a doodle
regeneration using the models
photographers wait could we create a
regular image to see how you would look
if you were a model
I know I learn exact like it if you
could come up with a lot function which
is how much to somebody look like a
model you could so you have to turn up
the last match and it has to be
something where you can generate labeled
data
one of the things they mentioned in the
paper is that they found it very
important to add quite a lot of padding
and specifically they didn't add zero
padding in a normal area to set a black
border but they add reflection padding
so reflection padding literally means
take the edge and reflective reoccurring
I've written it for you because there
isn't one but you may find it
interesting to look at this because this
is like one of the simplest examples of
a custom layer okay so we're going to be
using custom layers more and more and so
I don't want you to be afraid of them so
a custom layer in carrots is a Python
class so if you haven't done that as I
mentioned before for the class palette
if you haven't done our programming in
Python now's a good time to go and look
at some tutorials because you're going
to be doing quite a lot of it
particularly the pipes pipes words
absolutely alive in them so we're going
to create a class it has to inherit from
layer in Python this is how you could
create a constructor pythons our syntax
is really gross you have to use a
special weird custom new thing which
happens to be the projector every single
damn thing inside of class you have to
manually type out so color is the
parameter if you forget you'll get
stupid errors sorry
and then in the constructor for a layer
this is basically where you just save
away any of the information you are
doing so in this case you need you since
I want this much padding so you just
have to save that somewhere I say only
this much time and then you need to do
two things in every class custom layer
one is you have to define something
called get output check for that is
going to pass in
the shape of an input and you have to
return what is the shape of the outputs
that that would create so in this case
if f is the shape of the input then the
output is going to be the same batch
size and the same number of channels and
then we're going to add in twice the
amount of padding both the rows and
columns but this is going to tell it
because remember when we pull things out
corrupt is like you just check the
layers on top of each other and it
magically knows how big or the
intermediate things are it magically
knows because every layer has this thing
designed that's how it works
the second thing you have to define is
an import call and follow the thing
which will get your layer data and you
have to return whatever your layer does
right in our case we want to call caused
it to add reflection padding and in this
case so happens the tensor flow has
something built in to that called TSN
obviously generally it's nice to create
chaos layers that would work with both
piano and tensorflow beckons by using
that capital K dot notation but in this
case piano didn't have anything obvious
that it is easily and since it's just
through our class I just decided just to
make a test phone okay
so here is a complete layer I can now
use that layer in a network definition
like this I can call drop predict which
will take an input and turn it into you
consider the bird now has the left and
right sides here being reflected okay so
that is there for you to use because in
the supplementary material for the paper
they add that they add spatial
reflection padding the beginning of the
network and they add a lot 45 40 and the
reason they add a lot is because they
mentioned the supplementary material
that they don't want to use
same convolutions they want to use valid
convolutions in their computation
because if you add any black borders
during those computation steps
it creates weird artifacts on the edges
of the images so you'll see that through
this computation for their residual
blocks the size get smaller by for each
time and that's because these are valid
convolutions so that's why they have to
add padding to the stat so that these
sets are called the image to come
through small
so this section here should look very
familiar because it's the same as our
absently Network a bunch of residual
blocks 2d convolutions and one nine by
nine convolution and so this is
identical there you can copy this is the
nib it okay and so why do we have we've
already talked about why we have this
line by line con but why do we have
these downsampling convolutions to start
with we start with an image up here of
three three six five three three six and
we have its size and then we have its
size again why do we do that like the
reason we do that is that as I mentioned
earlier we want to do our computation at
a lower resolution because it allows us
to have a larger receptive field and it
allows us to do less computation so this
is Katun where it's like reflective
right like the last thing is the same as
the set the top thing second one thing
and the second thing you can see it's
like a reflection to make sure it's
really really common in generative
models its first of all to take your
object down sample it increasing the
number of channels at the same time so
increasing the receptive field you're
creating more and more complex
representations you then do a bunch of
computation on those representations and
then at the end you're up sampling in so
you're going to see this pattern also
and so that's why I wanted you guys to
implement this yourself okay
so there's that all right the last major
piece of your homework yesterday
question about what is triangles 1/2
that exactly the same as deconvolution
strive to so I remember I mentioned
earlier that another name for the
convolution is fractionally straighter
convolution
so you can remember that little picture
we saw this ideas like you put little
columns and rows of zeros in between
each row and column so that's kind of
think of it as doing like that ah drive
at the time
so that's why yeah this is exactly what
we are in here thank you mister changes
Rollo exceptionally to change my same
convolutions to Vella collisions
but this is well worth reading the whole
supplementary material because it really
has the details and fits it's so great
when a paper has something actually
material like this you'll often find
that the majority of papers don't
actually tell you the details that had
to do what they do and then you don't
even know code these guys both have code
and supplementary material which make
this absolute very plus Turner classic
works great okay so that is super
resolution sexual losses and so on
Nicholas I'm glad we got there
no that's it
let's make sure I don't have any more
slides oh there's one of the things in a
tree um which is these D convolutions
can create some very ugly outer fence
and I can show you some very ugly a
defense because I have some out here you
see these these hit on the screen Rachel
this checkerboard I think this is called
a checkerboard pattern the the
checkerboard pattern happened through a
very specific reason and I've provided a
link to this paper along with water to
disappear it's an online pair so you
guys might remember Chris Ola he had a
lot of the best kind of learning
materials we looked at in part one he's
now got this cool thing for distilled a
pub that some of his colleagues at
Google and - he wrote this thing
discovering why is it that everybody
gets these goddamn stackable pens and
what he shows is that it happens because
you have tried to size three
convolutions which means that every pair
of convolutions see one pixel price
right so it's like a checkerboard it's
just a natural thing that's going to
come out and so they talk about you know
this in some detail and all the kind of
things you can do time but in the end
they point out two things the first is
that you can avoid this by making it
that you're your stride divides nicely
into your size so if I change size to 4
click on alright so one thing you could
try that you're getting checkable
patterns which you will is make your 5/3
convolutions into clothes for
populations the second thing that he's
just doing is not to use the
convolutions instead of using the
deconvolution easy-chair
first of all doing an absinthe and what
happens we do an up sampling is it the
basically the opposite of max for you
you take every pixel and you turn it
into a 2x2 grid of that exact pixel okay
called up center if you do an up
sampling followed by a regular
convolution and also get rid of the
checkerboard pattern and as it happens
caris has something to do that which is
called it's called up sampling to D so
all this does is kind of the opposite of
next pooling it's going to double the
size of your image at which point you
can use a standard normal units data
convolution and avoid EMS so extra
credit
after you get your network working is to
change it to an up sampling and unit
straight from pollution Network and see
a few technical ad packs go away okay so
that is that at variant here I put some
suggestions system or things that you
can look at although most of those were
already in the PowerPoint so there's
anything out there okay so let's move on
I want to talk about going be going big
can mean two things of course does mean
we can see big data which is important
you have to do that I'm very proud that
even during the big data being I never
said big data without saying rude things
about this Cupid over here if you do
who cares about how big it is but in
deep learning you know sometimes we do
need to use either large objects like if
you're doing diabetic retinopathy you'll
have like 4,000 by 4,000 pictures of
eyeballs or maybe you've got lots of
images while lots of lots of objects
unlikely to work in the village near and
to handle this data that doesn't pick
and ran the kneading tricks so I thought
we would try some interesting projects
that involves looking at the whole image
net competition data set so the unitary
competition dataset is the one and a
half million images in a thousand
characters as I mentioned I think in the
last class if you try to download it in
available forms and using research
purposes and they're going to check it
and blah blah blah
in fact if you go out the forum you'll
get back an answer a seconds later well
anybody who's got a terabyte of space
and since you're building your own boxes
you know editor about a face you can go
ahead and download image net and then
you can start with for this project so
this project is about implementing the
paper called divides and divides is a
really really interesting paper actually
just
chatter to the altar about it quite
recently amazing lady named Andrea Frome
is now fire fire I'm just a computer
vision startup and what she did was
devised was she created a really
interesting multi modal
the multimodal means that we're going to
be combining different types of objects
and in her case she was combining
language with images it's quite an early
paper to look at this area and she did
something which was really interesting
she said normally when we do an
initiative Network our final layer is a
one hot encoding of the category and so
that means that a parks and golden
retriever are no more similar or
difference in synthetic coding than a
tug and Java Java gist and that seems
kind of weird right
if you happen encoding where similar
things were similarly encoding you could
do some pretty cool stuff
and in particular what she was trying to
do one of the key things you're trying
to do is to create something which went
beyond the thousand image net categories
so that you could work with types of
images that were not an initiative at
all and so the way she did that was to
see all right let's stroll away the one
part of coder category and let's replace
it with a word in being of the thing
okay so time is now no longer zero zero
zero one zero zero zero but it's now the
word too big venture upon
and that's it that's the entirety of the
thing train them and see what happens
I'll provide a link to the paper and one
of the things I loved about the paper is
that what she does is to show quite an
interesting range of the kind of cool
results and cool things you can do when
you replace a one part of credit output
with a vector
I just clarify so every pixel one
hard-coded pixel suddenly becomes a
vector was like no pixels not one marker
area pixels are encoded by their canvas
sorry I mean bit bit of hands all
station no so here the and the lipstick
and let's say this is a image of the
park that's the type of dog and so park
gets turned into a target is the 300
class in image net and it's going to get
turned into a 1000 one vector with a
thousand zeros after another minute of
zero and a one institution 300 so that's
normally what we use without that our
target when we're doing a new
certification we're going to throw that
one thousand one thing away and replace
it with a three hundred one thing and
the three hundred long thing will be the
word vector for pub that we downloaded
from work
so
normally we have our input image comes
in it goes through some kind of
computation you know CNN and it has to
predict something and normally the thing
it has to predict there's a whole bunch
of zeros and a one here and so the way
we do that is that the last layer is a
softmax layer which encourages one of
the things to be much higher than the
others so all we do is we throw that
away and we replace it with the word
vector
or that but I think Fox or Pike or jumbo
jet and since the word vector so
generally that might be say 300
dimensions
and that's that's dense that's not lots
of zeros so we can't use a soft max
layer at the end anymore
we've probably now just use a regular
linear layer okay so the hard part about
doing this really is processing
initiative not you know there's nothing
weird or interesting or tricky about the
architecture all we do is print the last
layer and so we're going to leverage
them big holes quite one so we start off
by and put in unusual stuff and don't
forget the tensor flow to call this
limit men thing I created that if you
don't use up all of your memory and one
thing which can be very helpful is to
define actually two parts once you cut
your own box you've got a bunch of
spinning hard disks that are big and
slow and cheap and maybe a couple of
pass expensive small SSDs or nvme drives
so I generally think it's Gladiator to
find a path the boat right one two this
actually happens to be a mount point
that has my big slow it's cheap fitting
discs and this past happens to live
somewhere which is my fast SSDs and that
way throughout my when I'm doing my code
anytime I've got something going to be
accessing a lot particularly if it's in
a random order and I want to make sure
that that thing from it's not too big
sits in this path and then he's fine I'm
accessing something which I'm accessing
generally sequentially or just really
big I can put it in this file
this is one of the good reasons and
other good reason to have your own box
is if you get this kind of activism okay
so the first thing we need is some more
vectors
so interestingly actually the the paper
built their own Wikipedia work versus
actually think that the word to vex
vectors you can download from Google are
really maybe a better choice here so
I've just gone ahead and shown how you
can load in one of the very nice things
about Google's words of X with vectors
is that where else doing the lower left
in type one when we use word vectors we
tend to use love-love would not have a
word vector for Golden Retriever they
would have a word vector for problem and
they don't have low phrase seen where
else Google's where vectors have phrases
like golden retriever so for our thing
we really need to use Google's word to
vet vectors or anything like that which
has like multi-part content as things
that we can look at so you can download
words of X I will make them available on
our platform below slash because the
only way to get in other ways is to get
them from like this the author's Google
Drive directory and trying to get to a
Google Drive directory from Linux is
absolute nightmare so I will save them
for you so that universe'
so once you've got them you can load
them in and then I they're in a weird
proprietary binary it's like more like
going to share data why put it in a
weird the prior to binary format and a
Google Drive thing you can access two
minutes anyway this guy did so I didn't
save this text they had a very easy to
work with the work vectors themselves
are in very simple format they're just
the words followed by a face followed by
the vector space separated I'm going to
save them in a simple dictionary format
so what I'm going to share that you guys
will be the dictionary the dictionary
from word or phrase to an umpire correct
okay I'm not sure I've used this idea of
lips are before so I should talk about
this a little bit so if I put a
dictionary a dictionary which maps from
word to vector how do I get out of that
a list of the words and the rest of the
vectors the short answer is like this
but let's think about what it's do it so
I don't know like we've used it quite a
bit right so normally was if you go like
tip this one plumber list to come up
whatever right and what that returns is
an iterator which first of all gives to
element one of list one element one of
this to element one over three and then
a two of this one so forth that's what
gifts normally does
there's a nice idea in Python that you
can put a star before any argument and
if that argument is an iterator
something that you can look through it
asks if you had taken that whole list
and actually put it inside those
brackets right so let's say that W to
the list contained like Fox :
and then some array and there v :
and then some array and so forth right
when you go zip star that if the same is
actually taking the contents of that
list and putting it inside there you
would want star star if it was a
dictionary start for list
not quite start to speed you're treating
as an iterator
you're right in this case we are using a
list so that's that's not where so yeah
you can use let's talk about sales there
another time figure right in this case
we have a list which is actually just in
this limited box comma array hug comic
array and then a lot more okay so what
is it going to do is when we exist it is
it's going to basically take
all of these things and create one risk
to those week onwards and all these
things get one whiff to those myths and
some vectors so this idea of them
zip star is something we're going to use
quite a lot
honestly I don't normally like think
about what it's doing
I just know that anytime I've got like a
list of tuples and I want to turn it
into a couple of lists you just do this
stuff so and that's all that is just a
little Python thing okay so this gives
us a list of words and most effectors so
anytime I start looking at some new data
I always want to test it and so I want
to make sure this work the way I thought
it ought to work so one thing I thought
was okay let's look at the correlation
coefficient between small j2me and each
territory and indeed there is some
correlation she would expect for else
the correlation between Jeremy and
banana I ate bananas so I was hoping
this to be like national be-
unfortunates not but it is at least
lower than the correlation between
Jeremy and picture so like okay it's not
always easy to exactly test data but you
know try and come up with things that
want to be true make sure they are true
and so in this case this is giving me to
comfort that these word vectors behavior
where expect them to now I don't really
care about capitalization so let's go
ahead and create a lowercase word to Vic
dictionary whereas through the lowercase
version for everything
one trick here is I go through in
Reverse and because word to Vic is
ordered where the most common words at
first so they're going in Reverse
it means if there is but the capital
h-i-m unit small Jeremy the one is going
to end up in my dictionary will be the
more common
so
what I want to divide is to now get this
work vector for each one of our 1000
categories in image 10 and then I'm
going to go even further than that
because I want to go beyond image net so
I actually went and downloaded the
original word net categories and they
filled it down to find all the noun and
I discovered that they're actually 18 mm
now in work which is quite a few it's
quite fun looking through them so I'm
going to create a map of word vectors
for every image net category we once s
and every word net noun that'll be
another set and so my goal in this
project will be to try and create
something that can do useful things with
the full set of word net now we don't go
beyond the internet we've already got
the a thousand Usenet categories we've
used setting a sensor for software those
bug min um I can okay and then I do the
same thing for the full set word
entities which I will share with you
and so now I can go ahead and create a
dictionary which goes through every one
of my every one of my imagenet thousand
categories and converts it into the word
vector and notice I have a filter here
and that's because some of the imagenet
categories won't be in words of X and
that's because like sometimes the
imagenet categories will say things like
target bracket doc you know they won't
be exactly in the same format if you
wanted to you could probably get a
better match than this but I found even
with this simple approach they managed
to match 50 1600 out of the 82,000 worth
net nouns which I thought was pretty
good
so what I did then was they created a
list of all of the categories which
didn't match and this come into the
outfit as you can see is something
that's literally just moved those
folders out of the way so that they're
not in my internship path anymore okay
so the details are very important but
hopefully you can see at the end of this
process I've got something that masks
every imagenet category - a word vector
as estimated - and every word net noun
to a vector at least if I hit then find
it and that I've modified my image net
data so that the categories I couldn't
find I move those borders out of there
okay
nothing particularly interesting there
and that's because wasn't it's not the
thing just in there that's pretty
straightforward the image is a bit
harder because we've got you know a
million or so images so we're going to
try everything we can to make this run
as quickly as possible
so
to start with even the very process of
getting a list of the file names that
everything an image set takes a
non-trivial amount of time so like
everything it takes a non-trivial and
time going to save its output okay so
the first thing I do is I use a blob
blob I can't really figure slop in part
one I think we did yeah is this the
thing that's like LS star dot star press
sort of lot so we use plod to grab all
of the internet training set and then I
just go ahead people don't then fight
and people don't lower their so there is
recent we'll see shortly it's actually a
very good idea though at this point to
randomize that Mister farmers put them
in a random order the basic idea is
later on if we use a chance to file name
to the next to each other they're not
all going to be the same type of seed
okay so by randomizing the file names
now in a very sort of time but then I
can go ahead and save that randomized
yes again is different then when we come
back
so I want to resize all of my images to
a concise I'm being a bit lazy here and
then a green size in two to three foot
by two 24 that's the input size for a
lot of models obviously to the one that
we're going to use and would prolly be
better if we resize to something bigger
and then we like randomly zoom and crop
maybe if we have time we'll we'll try
that later but so now we're just going
to use resize everything into 24 by 24
okay so we have a nearly a million
images it turns out to resize to 24 30
to 24 that could be pretty slow so I've
got some handy tricks to make it much
faster generally speaking there are
three ways to make an algorithm
significantly faster
the three ways are cash a memory
locality to explain these Mohammed and
locality second is Cindy also known as
vectorization
the third is parallel processing
so Rachel's very familiar with these
this is currently creating a course for
the master students here on numerical
linear algebra which is like very happy
about these things so these are the
three ways you can make data processing
faster memory locality simply means in
your computer you have lots of different
kinds of memory you have for example
level 1 cache level 2 cache Ram
subjective
regular or hard drives the difference in
speed as you go up from one to the other
is generally like 10 times or 100 times
or thousands owners floor like you
really really really don't want to go to
the next level of the memory hierarchy
if you can avoid it
unfortunately level 1 cache might be
more like 16 K level two caches might be
a few milk brands going to be a cube gig
solid safe drives is really going to be
a few hundreds of gig and your hard
drives are probably going to be apt
reminders so in reality you've got to be
careful that elevators so you want to
try and make sure that you're putting
stuff in the right place and if you're
not filling up the resources
unnecessarily and that if you use if
you're going to use piece of data
multiple times try to use it each time
like immediately use it again so that
it's already in your cache
the second thing which is what we're
about to look look at is SIMD which
stands for single instruction multiple
data something that a shockingly large
number of people even who plan to be
professional computer programmers don't
know is that every modern CPU is capable
of in a single operation in a single
thread calculating multiple things at
the same time and the way that it does
it is that you basically create a little
vector generally about eight things okay
and you put all the things you want to
calculate so you want to take the square
root of something you put eight things
into this little vector and then you
call a particular CTU instruction which
is basically a take the square root of
eight floating-point numbers that is in
this register and it does it in a single
clock cycle so when it's a clock cycle
you know your CPU IV say is 2 or 3
gigahertz and so it's doing 2 or 3
billion things per second whatnot it's
doing 2 or 3 billion times eight things
per second if you're using si ending
so few people are aware of this AMD and
because a lot of programming
environments that make it easy to use
this AMD a lot of stuff is not written
to take advantage of SIMD including for
example pretty much all of the image
processing in Python
however you can do this you can go pip
install hello SIMD and that will replace
your pillow and the pillow is like the
main types of imaging library with a new
version that does use this AMD correctly
some of this things because this AMD
only works on certain CPUs I mean any
any vaguely weekly video works but
because it's only some you have to add
special directives to the compiler to
tell it I want to use I have this kind
of CPU there please do use these kind of
instructions and what chelo SMD does is
actually literally replaces your
existing pillow and so that's why you
have to say for sri install this it's
going to be much or you already have
pillow but this is like no I want build
with Sandy so if you try this you will
find that the speed of your resize
literally goes up by six hundred percent
you don't have to change anything okay
so I'm like a huge fan
faad in general one of the reasons I'm
not particularly fond of Python because
it doesn't make it at all easy to use sa
ND some but luckily some people have
written stuff in C which does use this
AMD and then provided these path
interfaces okay so this is something to
remember to try to get working when you
go home before you do it
right a little benchmark that resizes a
thousand images times it and then run
this command and make sure that it gets
60% faster that way you know it's
actually working and we have two
questions I don't know if you want to
finish this free ways to do things
faster first ER and one is how could you
get the relation between a pug and a dog
and the photo of a pug and it's really
which is a bigger category of dogs
yes sure we'll think about that and
there why do we want to randomize the
file names can't we use shuffle equals
true on the chaos flow from directory
you'll see ya
the short answer is kind of to do with
locality if you say shuffle equals true
you're jumping from here on the hard
disk to here and add this to here in the
hardest and I just take that like
literally the rivers a sitting disk with
a little needle we are looking moving
all over the place so you want to be
getting things all over the first unit
as you'll see this is going to basically
work for a competitive dog this is
parked because he words act as a dog
it's very similar to what go to the park
so at the end we'll try it we'll try and
we'll see if we can find and box the
other workers I'm sure it will finally
it is parallel processing parallel
processing refers to simply as you all
know any modern CPU has multiple cores
which literally means multiple CPUs in
your CPU and often boxes that you both
are might even have multiple CPUs in
again pythons not great for parallel
processing plant and three is certainly
much better but a lot of stuff in Python
doesn't use parallel processing very
effectively but a lot of modern CPUs
have ten cords or more even for you know
consumer CPU so if you're not using
parallel processing you're missing out
on a 10 X theta if you're not using SIMD
you're missing out on a 6 to 8 X theta
ok so if you can do both of these things
you can get 50 plugs
I mean you will you'll get 50 plus B
then assuming your CPU has a nut cause
so we're going to do both to get this
AMD we're just going to install it and
to get parallel processing and probably
not there see all of us say but we're
going to be using parallel processing
so I define a few things to do my
resizing one thing is I've actually
recently changed how I do resizing as
I'm sure you guys have noticed in the
past when I resize things to square I've
tended to add a black border to the
bottom or a black border to the right
because that's what Care Act is now that
I've looked into it like no best
practice tapers cackled result in adding
use that way and it makes perfect sense
because the cnn's that has like learns
deal with the black border and you're
throwing away all that information and
what pretty much all the best practice
approach use is to rather than
reschedule the longest side to be the
size of your square and then fill it in
with black instead take the smallest
side and make that the size of your
square the other side's now too big to
just chop off the top and bottom or top
off the rival right and left
that's called center cropping so
resizing and center protein so what I've
done here is I've got something which
resizes to the size of the shortest side
and then over here somewhere
over here I've got something which does
the center cropping you can look at the
details from your own if you like not
particularly exciting so I've put
something about the resizing this is
something you can improve currently I'm
making sure that it's a three channel
image and so I'm not getting a black and
white or something with an alpha Channel
just ignore there okay so before I
finish up is I think about opponents so
what we're going to learn next time when
we start is we're going to learn about
parallel processing so anybody who's
interested in pre-reading yep feel free
to start reading and playing around with
a parallel process alright thanks
everybody
see you next week
hope your assignments go really well and
let me know if I can help you out in the
barn