okay so welcome back to deep learning
lesson 2 last week we got to the point
where we had successfully trained a
pretty accurate image classifier and so
just to remind you about how we did that
can you guys see okay I think the
actually we can turn the phone once all
right
can you guys all see the screen okay we
can to adjust these ones can we some
pictures all into darkness but if that
works then is that okay that's better
isn't it yeah can I dream the other two
and maybe that one as well
oh but that one oh that's great sorry I
don't know your renders oh okay great
that's better isn't it me so just to
remind you the way that we built this
image classifier was we used a small
amount of code basically three lines of
code and these three lines of code
pointed at a particular path which
already had some data in it and so the
key thing for this to know how to train
this model was that this path which was
data dogs cats and had to have a
particular structure which is that it
had a train folder and a valid folder
and in each of those trained and valid
folders there was a cats folder in the
dogs folder and if the cats on the docs
folders was a bunch of images of cats
and votes but this is like a pretty
standard it's one of two main structures
that are used to say here is the data
that I want you to train an image model
from so I know some of you during the
week went away and tried different data
sets where you had folders with
different sets of images and in credit
your own image classifiers and generally
that seems to be working pretty well
from what I can see on the forums so to
make it clear at this point this is
everything you need
to get started so if you create your own
folders with different sets of images
you know a few hundred or a few thousand
at each folder and run the same three
lines of code that will give you an
image classifier and you'll be able to
see this third column tells you how
accurate is so we looked at some kind of
simple visualizations to see like what
was it uncertain about what was it wrong
about and so forth and that's always a
really good idea and then we learned
about the one key number you have to
pick so this is this number here is the
one key number is 0.01 and this is
called the learning rate and so I wanted
to go over this again and we'll learn
about the theory behind what this is
during the rest of the course in quite a
lot of detail and for now I just wanted
to talk about the practice yes you know
they cannot see you in the medium
turnout I just turned it around you tell
us about the other three numbers being
bad we did these three here we're going
to talk about the other other ones
shortly so the main one we're going to
look at for now is is the last column
which is the accuracy the first column
as you can see is the epoch number so
this tells us how many times has it been
through the entire dataset trying to
learn a better classifier and in the
next two columns is what's called the
loss which we'll be learning about
either later today or next week the
first point is the loss on the training
set these are the images that we're
looking at in order to try to make a
better classifier and the second is the
loss of the validation set these are the
images that we're not looking at and
we're training but we're just sitting on
the side to see how accurate we are so
we'll learn about littering loss in
accuracy later
okay so so we've got the epoch number
the training loss is the second column
the validation loss is the third column
and the accuracy is the fourth column
you
okay so the basic idea of the loading
rate so the basic idea of the learning
rate is it's the thing that's going to
decide how quickly do we zoom do we kind
of hone in on the solution and so I find
that a good way to think about this is
to think about like well what if we were
trying to fit to a function that looks
something like this right we're trying
to say okay where's where abouts is the
minimum point this is basically what we
do when we do deep learning is we try to
find the minimum point of a function now
our function happens to have millions or
hundreds of millions of parameters but
it works the same basic way and so when
we look at it you know we can
immediately see that the lowest point is
here but how would you do that if you
are a computer algorithm and what we do
is we we start out at some point at
random so you pick say here and we have
a look and we say okay what's the what's
the loss or the error at this point and
we say what's the gradient in other
words which way is up and which way is
down and it tells us that down is going
to be in that direction and it also
tells us how fast is it going down which
is at this point is going down pretty
quickly and so then we take a step in
the direction that's down and the
distance we travel is going to be
proportional to the gradient sort of
unfortunately how steep it is the idea
is if it's deeper then we're probably
further away that's the general idea
right and so specifically what we do is
we take the gradient which is how steep
is it at this point and we multiply it
by some number and that number is called
the learning rate okay
so if we pick a number that is very
small then we're guaranteed that we're
going to go a little bit closer and a
little bit closer and a little bit
closer each time right but it's going to
take us a very long time to eventually
get to the bottom if we dig a number
that's very big we could actually step
too far could go in the right direction
but we could step all the way over to
here right as
result of which we end up further away
than we started and we could oscillate
and get worse and worse so if you start
training a neural net and you find that
your accuracy or your loss is like
spitting off into infinity
almost certainly your learning rates too
high so in a sense learning rate too low
is is a better problem to have because
you're going to have to wait a long time
but wouldn't it be nice if there was a
way to figure out like what's the best
learning rate something where you could
kind of go quickly go like Bom Bom Bom
right and so that's why we use this
thing called a learning rate finder and
what the learning rate finder does is it
tries each each time it looks at another
remember the mini-batch how many batches
a few images that we look at each time
so that we're using the parallel
processing power of the GPU effectively
we look generally at around 64 128
images at a time for each mini batch
which is labeled here as an iteration we
gradually increase the learning rate
multiplicatively increase the learning
rate we started really really tiny
learning rates to make sure that we
don't start at something too high and we
gradually increase it and so the idea is
that eventually the learning rate will
be so big that the loss will start
getting worse
and so what we're going to do then is
we're a look at the plot of learning
rate against loss right so when the
learning rates tiny it increases slowly
then it's that's where increase a bit
faster and then eventually it starts not
increasing as quickly and in fact it
starts getting worse right so clearly
here and make sure you're you want to be
familiar with this scientific notation
okay so ten to the negative one is 0.1
10 to 50 or is 1 10 to the negative 2 is
0.001 and when we write this in Python
we'll generally write it like this
rather than writing 10 to the negative 1
or 10 to the negative 2 we'll just write
1 a neg 1 or 1 e neg - okay I mean the
same thing you're going to see that all
the time and remember that equals 0.1
Oh point O one okay so don't be confused
by this text that it prints out here
this this loss here is the the final
loss at the very at the end of it's not
of any interest right so ignore this
this is only interesting when we're
doing regular trading that's not
interesting for the learning rate finder
the thing that's interesting for the
learning rate finder is this loan shed
plot and specifically we're not looking
for the point where it's the lowest back
to the point where it's the lowest it's
actually not getting better anymore so
that's to higher learning rate so I
generally look to see like where is it
the lowest and then I go back like one
for magnitude so one enoch two would be
a pretty good choice yeah okay so that's
why you saw when we ran our fit here we
picked 0.01 right which is one a neg two
so important point to make here is like
this this is the one key number that
we've learnt to adjust and if you just
adjust this number at nothing else most
of the time you're going to be able to
get pretty good results and this is like
a very different message to what you
would hear or see in any textbook or any
video or any course because up until now
there's been like dozens and dozens of
these they're called hyper parameters
dozens and dozens of hyper parameters to
set and they've been thought of as
highly sensitive and difficult to set so
inside the first AI library we kind of
do all that stuff for you as much as we
can and during the course we're going to
learn that there are some more we can
quake to get slightly better results but
it's kind of like it's kind of in a
funny situation here because for those
of you that haven't done anything
learning before is kind of like oh this
is that's all there is to it this is
very easy and then when you talk to
people outside this class they'll be
like deep learning so difficult as
someone to say it's a real art form and
so that's why there's this as is
difference right and so that the truth
is that the learning rate really is the
key thing to set and this ability to use
this
to figure out how to set it well though
the paper is now probably 18 months old
almost nobody knows about this paper it
was from a guy who's not from a famous
research labs so most people kind of
ignored it and in fact even this
particular technique was one subpart of
a paper that was about something else
so again this idea of like this is how
you can set the learning rate really
nobody outside this classroom just about
knows about it obviously the guy who
wrote it Leslie Smith knows about it
yeah so it's a good thing to tell your
colleagues about is like here is
actually a great way to set the learning
rate and there's even been papers caught
like one of the famous papers is called
no more pesky learning rates which
actually is a less effective technique
than this one but this idea that like
setting learning rates is is very
difficult and thirdly is has been true
for most of the kind of deep learning
history so here's the trick right go
look at this plot find kind of the
lowest to go back about a multiple of
ten and try that all right and if that
doesn't quite work you can always try
you know going back another multiple ten
but this is always worked for me so far
once why does this learning rate this
method work versus something else like
momentum base or what's like the
advantages a disadvantage with just
learning rate rate like technique we're
just feels that's a great question so
we're going to learn during this course
about a number of ways of improving
gradient percent like you mentioned
momentum and atom and so forth this is
orthogonal in fact so one of the things
the faster a library tries to do is
figure out the right gradient descent
version and in fact behind the scenes
this is actually using something called
atom and so this technique is telling us
this is the best learning rate to use
given what I thought other tweaks you're
using in this case the atom optimizer so
it's not that there's some compromise
between this and some other approaches
who sits on top of those approaches and
you still have to set the learning rate
when you use with other approaches so
we're trying to
find the best kind of optimizer to use
for a problem that you still have to set
the learning rate and this is how we can
do it and in fact this idea of using
this technique on top of more advanced
optimizers like Adam might haven't even
seen mentioned in a paper before so I
think this is like a I mean it's not a
huge breakthrough it seems obvious but
nobody else seems to tried it so as you
can see it was well
when we use optimizers like Adam ditched
Harvick adaptive learning rate so and he
said this learning rate is Italy initial
learning rate because it changes during
the people so we're going to be learning
about things like Adam the details about
it later in the class but the basic
answer is no even with even the Adam
that there actually is a learning rate
it's just being it's being basically
divided by the the gradient the average
previous gradient and also the recent
summer Squared's of gradients so there's
still like a number called the learning
rate there there isn't a even these so
called dynamic learning rate methods
still have unlearning rate okay so the
most important thing that you can do to
make your model better and is to give it
more data so the challenge that happens
is that these models have hundreds of
millions of parameters and if you train
them for a while they start to do what's
called overfitting and so overfitting
means that they're going to start to see
like the specific details of the images
you're giving them rather than the more
general learning that can transfer
across to the validation set so the best
thing we can do to avoid overfitting is
to find more data now obviously one way
to do that would just be to collect more
data from where you're getting it from
or label more data but a really easy way
that we should always do is to use
something called data augmentation so
they don't open tuition is one of these
things that's key in many courses it's
not even mentioned at all or if it is
it's kind of like an advanced topic
right at the end but actually it's like
the most important thing that you can do
to make a better model okay and so it's
built into the faster you library to
make it very easy to do and so we're
going to look at the details of the code
shortly but the basic idea is that
as in our initial code we had a line
that said image classified data from
parts and we passed in the path to our
data and for transforms we passed in
basically the sizing the architecture
we'll look at this in more detail
shortly we just add one more parameter
which is what kind of data augmentation
do you want to do and so to understand
data augmentation it's may be easiest to
look at some pictures of data
augmentation so what I've done here
again we'll look at the code in more
detail later but the basic idea is oh
I've run I've built a data class like
multiple times I'm going to do it six
times and each time I'm going to plot
the same catch and you can see that what
happens is that this cap here is further
over to the left this one here is
further over to the right and this one
here is fit horizontally and so forth so
data augmentation different types of
image you're going to want different
types of data augmentation right so for
example if you were trying to recognize
letters and digits you wouldn't want to
flip horizontally because like it's
actually has a different meaning whereas
on the other hand if you're looking at
photos of cats and dogs you probably
don't want to fit vertically because
cats aren't generally upside down all
right where else if you're looking at
there's a current Cargill competition
which is recognizing icebergs in
satellite images you probably do want to
fit them upside down because it's really
matter which area around the iceberg or
the satellite was right so one of the
examples of the transform sets we have
is transforms sidon so in other words if
you have photos that are like generally
taken from the side which generally
means you want to be able to flip them
horizontally but not vertically this is
going to give you all the transforms you
need for that so it'll flip them
sideways rotate them by small amounts
but not too much and slightly bury their
contrast and brightness and slightly
zoom in and out a little bit and move
them around a little
so each time it's a slightly different
fight billionaires we're getting a
couple of questions from people about
you explaining in the reason why you
don't think the minimum of the loss
curve yeah but it's like the higher rate
so yeah and also could you people
understand if this works for every CNN
for CNN every minute there's a running
right fine done yeah exactly yeah okay
great
um could you put your hand up if there's
a spare seat next to you so there was a
question about the learning rate finder
about why do we use the learning rate
that's less than the lowest point and so
the reason why is to understand what's
going on with this learning rate finder
so let's go back to our picture here
like how do we figure out what learning
rate to use right and so what we're
going to do is we're going to take steps
and each time we're going to double the
learning rate so kind of double the
amount by which we multiply the grander
gradient so in other words would go tiny
step slightly bigger slightly bigger
slightly bigger slightly bigger slightly
bigger slightly bigger okay and so the
question is of the purpose of this is
not to find the minimum the purpose of
this is to figure out what learning rate
is allowing us to decrease quickly right
so the point at which the loss was
lowest here is actually there right but
that learning rate actually looks like
it's probably too high it's going to
just jump like probably backwards and
forwards okay so instead what we do is
we go back to the point where the
learning rates quickly are giving us a
quick increase in the loss so here is so
here is the actual learning rate
increasing every single time we look at
a new mini batch
so mini-batch reiteration versus
learning right and then here is learning
rate versus loss so here's that point at
the bottom where is now already too high
okay and so here's the point where we go
back a little bit and it's increasing
nice and quickly we're going to learn
about something called stochastic
gradient descent with restarts shortly
where we're going to see like in a sense
you might want to go back to 1 enoch 3
where it's actually even steeper still
and maybe we would actually find this
book actually learn even quicker you
could try it but we're going to see
later why actually using a higher number
is going to give us better
generalization so for now let's put that
aside do you mean higher learning rate
when you say I know I mean higher
letting retina say higher
yeah yeah I mean I am learning rate so
as we increase the iterations from the
learning rate finder the learning rate
is going up this is iterations versus
learning ready okay so as we do that as
the learning rate increases and we plot
it here the loss Goes Down and here we
get to the point where the learning rate
is too high and at that point the most
is now getting worse because I asked the
question because you were just
indicating that you know even though the
minimum was at 10 to the minus 1 you
were gonna you suggest that we should
choose 10 to the minus 2 but now you're
saying I mean we should go back the
other way higher so I didn't mean to say
that I'm sorry if I said something
backwards I want to go back down to the
lower learning rate so possibly I said a
higher when I meant higher into this
lower OS do you know I'm learning right
okay thanks yep
last class is said that the local all
the local minima are the same and this
graph also shows the same is that is
this something that was observed or is
the logic theory behind it that's not
what this graph is showing this graph is
simply showing that there's a point
where if we increase the learning rate
more then it stops getting better than
actually starts getting worse the idea
that all local minima are the same is a
totally separate issue and it's actually
something else we'll see a picture of
shortly so let's come back to that
Jeremy do we have to find the base
learning rate every time we are going to
run a poke third time we're running on a
poke and a pop so how many times should
I run this like let me write find my
training that's a great question unit um
I certainly run it once when I start
later on in this class we're going to
learn about unfreezing layers and after
I unfreeze layers I sometimes run it
again if I do something to like change
the thing I'm training or change the way
I'm training it you may want to run it
again basically or you know if you
particularly if you've changed something
about how you train like unfreezing
layers which we're gonna soon learn
about and you're finding the other
training is unstable or too slow
well again you can run it again there's
never any harm
in running it it doesn't take very long
that's great question okay so back to
data augmentation so if we add to a when
we run this little transforms from model
function we pass in orientation
transforms we can pass in the main to a
transform side on or transforms top down
later on we'll learn about creating your
own custom transform lists as well but
for now because we're taking pictures
from the side cats and dogs will say
transform side on and now each time we
look at an image it's going to be zoomed
in or out a little bit moved around a
little bit
rotated a little bit possibly flipped
okay and so what this does is it's not
exactly creating new data but as far as
the convolutional neural net is
concerned it's a different way of
looking at this thing and it actually
therefore allows it to learn how to
recognize cats or dogs from somewhat
different angles right so when we do
data orientation we're basically trying
to say based on our domain knowledge
here here are different ways that we can
mess with this image that we know still
make it the same image you know and that
we could expect that you might actually
see that kind of image in the real world
so what we can do now is when we call
this from parts function which we'll
learn more about shortly we can now pass
in this set of transforms which actually
have these augmentations in now
so that's going to we're going to start
from scratch here we do a fit and
initially the augmentations actually
don't do anything and the reason
initially they don't do anything is
because we've got here something that
says precompute equals true we're going
to come back to these lots of times but
basically what this is doing is do you
remember this picture we saw where we
learn each different layer has these
activations that basically look for it
or anything from the middle of flowers
to eyeballs of birds or whatever right
and so literally what happens is that
the the later layers of this
convolutional neural network have these
things called activations and activation
literally it's a number an activation is
a number that says this feature like
eyeball of bird is in this location with
this level of confidence with its
probability right and so we're going to
see a lot of this later but what we can
do is we can say all right well in this
we've got a pre trained network remember
and a pre trained network is one where
it's already learned to recognize
certain things in this case it's learnt
to recognize the one and a half million
images in the imagenet dataset and so
what we could do is we could take the
the second last layer so the one which
is like got all of the information
necessary to figure out what kind of
thing a thing is and we can save those
activations so basically saving things
saying you know there's this level of
eyeball nurse here in this level of dogs
facing us here or in this level of
fluffy ear there and so forth and so we
save for every image these activations
and that we call them the pre computed
activations and so the idea is now that
when we want to create a new classifier
which can basically take advantage of
these pre computed applications we can
just very quickly train when all the
details there shortly we can very
quickly train a simple linear model
based on those
and so that's what happens when we say
pre-compute equals true and that's why
you may have noticed this week the first
time that you run a model a new model it
takes a minute or two where else you saw
when I ran it it took like five or ten
seconds took you a minute or two and
that's because it had to pre-compute
these activations and just has to do
that once if you're using like your own
computer or AWS it just has to do it
once ever if you're using Kressel it
actually has to do it once every single
time you rerun press all because press
or uses are just for these pre computed
activations it uses a special that all
had a scratch space that disappears each
time you restart your press or instance
so other than the special case of cresol
generally speak he does have to run at
once
ever for a data set okay so the issue
with that is that since we pre computed
for each image you know how much does it
have an EI here and how much does it
have a lizard's eyeball there and so
forth that means that data augmentations
don't work right in other words even
though we're trying to show at a
different version of the cat each time
we've pre computed the activations for a
particular version of that cat so in
order to use data augmentation we just
have to go and learn pre compute equals
false okay and then we can run a few
more APIs right and so you can see here
that as we run more a Potts the accuracy
isn't particularly getting better that's
the bad news
the good news is that you can see that
the train loss practices like the way of
measuring the error of this model
although that's getting better the
errors going down the validation error
isn't going down and but we're not
overfitting and overfitting would mean
that the training loss is much lower
than the validation loss and we're going
to talk about that a lot during this
course but the general idea here is if
you're doing much better job on the
training set then you are on the
validation set that means your models
not generalize
so we're not at that point which is good
but we're not really improving so we're
going to have to figure out how to deal
with that before we do I want to show
you one other cool trick I've added here
cycle length equals one and this is
another really interesting idea here's
the basic idea
cycle length equals one enables a recent
fairly recent discovery and deep
learning called stochastic gradient
descent with restarts and the basic idea
is this as you as you get closer and
closer as you get closer and closer to
the right spot right now getting closer
and closer I may want to start to
decrease my learning rate right because
as I get closer I'm kind of like oh I'm
pretty close down so let's let's slow
down my steps to try to get executive
the right spot right and so as we do
more iterations
our learning rate perhaps should
actually go down right because as we go
along we're getting closer and closer to
where we want to be and we want to like
get exactly to the right spot okay so
the idea of decreasing the learning rate
as you train is called
learning rate annealing and it's it's
very very common very very popular
everybody uses it basically all the time
the most common kind of learning rate
annealing is really horrendously hacky
it's basically that researchers like
pick a learning rate that seems to work
for a while and then when it stops
learning well they drop it down by about
10 times and then they keep learning a
bit more until it doesn't seem to be
improving and they drop it down by
another ten times that's what most
academic research papers and most people
in industry do so this would be like
stepwise annealing very manual very
annoying a better approach is simply to
pick some kind of functional form like a
line it turns out that a really good
functional form is one half of the
cosine curve
right and the reason why is that for a
while when you're not very close you
kind of have a really high learning rate
and that is you do get close you kind of
quickly drop down and do a few
iterations with a really low learning
rate and so this is called cosine
annealing so to those of you who haven't
done trigonometry for a while
cosine basically looks something like
this right so we've picked one little
half piece okay so we're going to use
cosine annealing but here's the thing
when you're in a very high dimensional
space right near we're only able to show
three dimensions right but in reality
we've got hundreds of millions of
dimensions we've got lots of different
fairly flat points there no not the
actual local minima but they're fairly
flat points all of which are pretty good
right but they might differ in a really
interesting way which is that some of
those flat points let me show you
let's imagine we've got a surface that
looks something like this
right now imagine that where you kind of
random guest started here and our
initial therefore kind of learning rate
annealing schedule got us down to here
now indeed that's a pretty nice low
error right but it probably doesn't
generalize very well which is to say if
we use a different data set where things
are just kind of slightly different in
one of these directions suddenly is a
terrible solution right where else over
here is basically equally good in terms
of loss right but it rather suggests
that if you move if you have slightly
different data sets that are slightly
moved in different directions it's still
going to be good right so in other words
we would expect this solution here is
probably going to generalize better than
this by key one so here's what we do is
we've got like a bunch of different low
bits right then our standard loading
rate annealing approach will start of go
down here or downhill downhill downhill
downhill to one spot right but what we
could do instead is use a learning rate
schedule that looks like this which is
to say we do a cosign annealing and then
suddenly jump up again into a cosign
annealing and then jump up again
and so each time we jump up it means
that if they're going to spiky bit and
then we subtly increase the learning
rate and it jumps now all the way over
to here and so then we kind of learning
right in your learning right near death
down to here and then we jump up again
to a high learning rate oh and it stays
here right so in other words each time
we jump up the learning rate that means
that if it's in a nasty spiky part of
the surface it's going to hop out of the
spiky part and hopefully if we do that
enough times it'll eventually find a
nice smooth Bowl
could you get the same effect by running
multiple iterations through the
different ground of my starting point so
that eventually you explore all possible
minimize yeah so in fact that that's a
great question and before this approach
which is called stochastic gradient
descent with restarts was was created
that's exactly what people used to do
they used to create these things called
ensembles where they would basically
relearn a whole new model ten times in
the hope that one of them's like but it
ended up being better and so the cool
thing about this decosta gradient
descent with restarts is that the model
once we're in a reasonably good spot
each time we jump up the learning rate
it doesn't restart it actually hangs out
in this nice part part of the space and
then keeps getting better so
interestingly it turns out that this
approach where we do this a bunch of
separate cosine annealing steps we end
up with a better result as then if we
just randomly try it a few different
starting points so it's a super neat
trick and it's a fairly recent
development but and again almost
nobody's heard of it but I found like
it's now like my superpower like using
this along with the learning rate finder
like I can get better results than
nearly anybody like in a casual
competition you know in the first week
or two I can like jump in it's been an
arrow to and back I've got a
fantastically good result and so this is
why I didn't pick the point where it's
got the steepest slope I actually trying
to pick something kind of aggressively
high it's still getting down but maybe
like getting to the point where it's
nearly too high not because I want to
make sure because that's because when we
do this stochastic gradient descent with
restarts this ten to the negative two
represents the
a highest number that it uses so it goes
up to ten to the negative two and then
goes down and then up to ten negative
two and down so if I use to lower
learning rate it's not going to jump to
a different part of the function so I
have a few questions but the first one
is how many times do you change your
learning rate you want to work we don't
change the learning rate all three how
many times - okay so in terms of this
part here where it's going down we
change the learning rate every single
mini - all right and then the number of
times we reset it is set by the cycle
length parameter and so 1 means reset it
up to every epoch so if I had to there
it would reset it up to every to epochs
and interestingly this this point that
when we do the learning rate and
kneeling that we actually change it
every single batch it turns out to be
really critical to making this work and
it again is very different to what
nearly everybody in industry in academia
has done before
what do you get a chance could you
explain recompute it was true because
it's still yeah we're going to come back
to that multiple times in this course so
the way this course has been a work is
we're going to like do a really
high-level version of each thing and
then we're going to like come back to it
in two or three lessons and then come
back to it at the end of the course and
each time we're going to see like more
of the math more of the code and get a
deeper view okay and we can talk about
it also in the forums during the week
our main goal is to generalize and we
don't want to get those like narrow
demas yeah that's a it's a very short
summary this method are we keeping track
off to minimize and averaging them ah
that's that's another level of
sophistication and indeed you can see
there's something here called snapshot
ensemble so we're not doing it in the
code right now but yes if you wanted to
make us generalize even better you can
save the weights here and here and here
and then take the average
ishes but for now we're just going to
pick the last one if you want to skip
ahead if you want to skip ahead there's
a parameter called cycle safe name which
you can add as well as cycle them and
that will save a set of weights at the
end of every learning rate cycle and
then you can ensemble them ok so we've
got a pretty decent model here ninety
nine point three percent accuracy and
we've gone through of you know a few
steps that is taken you know a minute or
two to run and so from time to time I
tend to save my weight so if you go
learn dot save and then pass in a file
name it's going to go ahead and save
that for you later on if you go learn
load you'll be straight back to where
you came from okay so it's a good idea
to do that from time to time this is a
good time to mention what happens when
you do this when you go learn dot save
when you create precomputed activations
another thing we learn about soon when
you create resized images these are all
creating various temporary files okay
and so what happens is if we go to data
and we go to dogs cats this is my data
folder and you'll see there's a folder
here called TMP or - and so this is
automatically created and all of my pre
computed activations end up in here I
mention this because if if things are if
you're getting weird errors that might
be because you've got some Oh pre
computed activations like we're only
half completed or are in some way
incompatible with what you're doing so
you can always go ahead and just delete
this TMP this temporary directory and
see if that causes your error to go away
this is the faster I equivalent of
turning it off and then on again
you'll also see there's a directory
called models and that's where all of
these when you say dot save with a model
that's where that's going to go actually
it reminds me when the stochastic
gradient descent with restarts paper
came out I saw a tweet that was somebody
was like Oh to make your deep learning
work better turn it off and then on
again question it so if I want to see I
want to retrain my model fuselage again
do I just do everything the 10 folder if
you want if you want to train your model
from scratch there's generally no reason
to delete the pre computed activations
because the pre computed activations are
without any training that's what the pre
trained model created with the with the
weights that you downloaded off the
internet the only yeah I mean the only
reason you want to delete the pre
computed activations is that there was
some error caused by like half creating
them and crashing or some something like
that as you change the size of your
import change different architectures
and so forth they all create different
sets of activations with different file
names so you don't generally you
shouldn't have to worry about it if you
want to start training again from
scratch all you have to do is create a
new learn object so each time you go
like conch learner dot pre-trained that
creates a new object with with new sets
of weights fever train from okay so
before our break we'll finish off by
talking about about fine-tuning and
differential learning rates and so so
far everything we've done has not
changed any of these free trained
filters right so we've used a pre
trained model that already knows how to
find at the early stages edges
ingredients and then corners and curves
and then repeating patterns and bits of
text
and eventually eyeballs right we have
not retrained any of those activations
any of those features well specifically
any of those weights in the
convolutional kernels all we've done is
we've learnt some new layers that we've
added on top of these things we've
learned how to mix and match these
pre-trained features now obviously it
may turn out that your pictures have you
know different kinds of eyeballs or
faces or if you're using different kinds
of images like satellite images totally
different kinds of features altogether
right so if you're like training to
recognize icebergs you'll probably want
to go all the way back and learn you
know all the way back to kind of
different combinations of these simple
gradients and edges in our cases dogs
vs. cats we're going to have some minor
differences but we still may find it's
helpful to slightly tune some of these
later layers as well so to tell the
learner that we now want to start
actually changing the convolutional
filters themselves we simply say
unfreeze okay so a frozen layer is a
layer which is not trained is not
updated okay so unfreeze unfreezes all
of the layers now when you think about
it it's pretty obvious that layer one
right which is like a diagonal edge or a
gradient probably doesn't need to change
by much if at all right from the 1 and a
half million images on image net it
probably already is figured out pretty
well how to find like edges of gradients
it probably already knows also like
which kind of corners to look for and
how to find which kinds of curves and so
forth so in other words these early
layers probably need little if any
learning where else these later ones are
much more likely to need more learning
and this is universally true regardless
of whether you're looking for satellite
images of rainforests or icebergs or
whether you're looking for cats versus
dogs right
so what we do is we create an array of
learning rates where we say okay these
are the learning rates to use for our
additional layers that we've added on
top these are the learning rates to use
in the middle few layers and these are
the learning rates to use for the first
few layers so these are the ones for the
layers that represent like very basic
geometric features these are the ones
that are used to for the more complex
kind of sophisticated convolutional
features and these are the ones that are
used for the features that we've added
and went from stretch right so you can
create a array of learning rates and
then when we called up fit and pass an
array of learning rates it's now going
to use those different learning rates
for different parts of the model this is
not something that we've like invented
but I'd also say it's like it's so not
that common that it doesn't even have a
name as far as I know so we're going to
call it differential learning rates if
it actually has a name or indeed if
somebody's actually written a paper
specifically talking about it I don't
know there's a great researcher called
Jason your Sinskey who who did write a
paper about the kind of the idea that
you might want different learning rates
and showing why but I don't think any
other libraries support it and yeah I
don't know of a name for it having said
that though this ability to like
unfreeze and then use these differential
learning rates I found it's like the
secret to taking a pretty good model and
putting it into an awesome model so just
to clarify so you have three numbers
there okay three hyper parameters the
first one is the photo late model so the
mall that are late layers the so with
the it's your answer is many many right
and they're kind of in groups and we're
going to learn about the architecture
this is called a ResNet for residual
network
it kind of has ResNet blocks and so what
we're doing is we're grouping the blocks
into three groups and so this one is
actually this first number is for the
earliest layers yeah they're ones
closest to the pixels that represent
like corners and edges and gradients but
why why do you well I thought those
layers are frozen at first so yeah right
so we just said unfreeze the streets
also we so yeah I'm freezing them
because you have kind of partially
trained although lately we've trained
we've trained our added layers yes now
you are we training the Oh step exactly
obviously so it waits and the learning
rate is particularly small for the early
layers that's right because you just
find a want to find food yeah yeah we
probably don't want to change them at
all but you know if it does need to then
it can thanks no problem so using the
differential in rates a little different
from like grid search there's no
similarity to grid search so grid search
is where we're trying to find the best
hyper parameter for something so for
example you could kind of think of the
learning rate finder as a really
sophisticated grid search which is like
trying lots and lots of learning rates
to find which one is best
but this has nothing to do with that
this is actually for the entire training
from now on it's actually going to use a
different learning rate for each layer
and so I was wondering so you give a pre
train model then you have to use the
same input dimensions right because I
was thinking okay let's say you have
this big they use like big machines to
train these things and you want to take
advantage of it how would you go about
you know you have like images that are
like bigger than the ones that they used
or we're going to be talking about sizes
later but the short answer is that with
this library and the modern
architectures were using we can use any
size we like so did I mean do we need
can we at least just a specific layer we
can we're not doing it yet but if you
wanted to you can learn dot freeze
underscore two and pass into layer
number much to my surprise or at least
initial my surprise it turns out I
almost never need to do that I almost
never find it helpful and I think it's
because we're using differential
learning rates the the optimizer can
kind of learn just as much as it needs
to so yeah it's a little data like very
little data yeah it still doesn't seem
to help the one place I have found it
helpful is if I'm using like a really
big memory intensive model and I'm like
running out of GPU crazy having the the
less layers you unfreeze the less memory
it takes and the less time it takes so
there's that kind of practical aspect so
to me she'll say I asked the question
right can I just like unfreezes specific
layer no you you can only unfreeze
layers from layer n onwards you could
probably delve inside the library in
phase one phase one layer but I don't
know why you would
okay so I'm really excited to be showing
you guys this stuff because it's like
it's something we've been kind of
researching all year it's figuring out
how to train state of the art models and
we've kind of found these like tiny
number of tricks and so once we do that
we now go learn about fit right and you
can see look at this we get right up to
that 99.5% accuracy which is crazy
there's one other trick you might see
here that as well as using stochastic
gradient descent with restarts a cycle
length equals one we've done three
cycles so earlier on I lied to you I
said this is this is the number of
epochs it's actually the number of
cyclists right so if you said cycle
length equals two it would do three
cycles of each of two epochs or do six
because so here I've said two three
cycles yet somehow it's done seven
epochs and the reason why is I've got
one last trick to show you which is
cycle mult equals two and to tell you
what that does I'm simply going to draw
you a picture you the picture if I go
learn Dutch share top plot learning rate
there it is
now you can see what cycle mode equals
to is doing okay it's it's doubling the
length of the cycle after each cycle and
so in the paper that introduced this
stochastic gradient descent with
restarts
the researcher kind of said hey this is
something that seems to sometimes work
pretty well and I've certainly found
that often to be the case so basically
intuitively speaking if your cycle
length is too short right then it's kind
of starts going down to find a good spot
and then it pops out and it goes to a
try and photographs button pops out it
never actually gets to find a good spot
right so earlier on you want it to do
that because it's trying to find the bit
that's like smoother but then later on
you want it to fight do more exploring
and then more exploring right so that's
why this cycle mole equals two thing
often seems to be a pretty good approach
right so suddenly we're introducing more
and more hyper parameters having told
you that there aren't that many but
the reason is that like you can really
get away with just taking a good
learning rate but then adding these
extra tweaks really helps get that extra
level up without any effort right and so
in practice I find this kind of three
cycles starting at 1 mode equals 2 works
very very often to get a pretty decent
model if it does doesn't then often I'll
just do 3 cycles of length 2 with no
molt
okay there's kind of like two things
that seem to work a lot and there's not
too much fiddling I find necessary and
as I say even even if you just if you
use this line every time I'd be
surprised if you didn't get a reasonable
result so a question here why does a
smoother services correlate to more
generalize networks so it's kind of this
some this intuitive explanation I try to
just kill the whole thing I try to give
back here which is that if you've got
something spiky right and so what this
what this x-axis is showing is like how
how good is this at recognizing dogs
versus cats as you change this
particular parameter right and so so
something to be generalizable that means
that we wanted to work when we give it
when we give it a slightly different
data set and so a slightly different
data set may have a slightly different
relationship between this parameter and
how caddy versus dog it is it may
instead look a little bit like this
right so in other words if we end up at
this point right then it's not going to
do a good job on this slightly different
data set for else if we end up on this
point it's still going to do a good job
on this data set
okay so that's what psychomotor equals
doing okay so we've got one last thing
before we going to take a break which is
we're now going to take this model which
has 99.5 percent accuracy and we're
going to try and make it better still
and what we're going to do is we're not
actually going to change the model at
all right but instead we're going to
look back at the original virtual
visualization we did where we looked at
some of our incorrect pictures now what
I've done is I've printed out the whole
of these incorrect pictures but the key
thing to realize is that particularly in
fact when we do the the validation set
all of our inputs to our model all the
time have to be square right and the
reason for that is it's kind of a minor
technical detail but basically the GPU
doesn't go very quickly if you have like
different dimensions for different
images because it needs seems to be
consistent so that every part of the GPU
can do the same thing and I think this
is probably fixable but it now that's
the state of the technology we have so
our validation set when we actually say
for this particular thing is it's a dog
what we actually do to make it square as
we just pick out the square in the
middle right so we would take off its
two edges and so we take the whole
height and then as much of the middle as
we can and so you can see in this case
we wouldn't actually see this dog's head
right so I think the reason this was
actually not correctly classified was
because the validation set only got to
see the body and the body doesn't look
particularly doglike or cat-like it's
not at all punctual what it is so what
we're going to do when we calculate the
predictions for our validation set is
we're going to use something called test
time augmentation and what this means is
that every time we decide is this cat or
a dog not in the training but after
we've trained the model is we're going
to actually take four random data
augmentations and remember the data
augmentations move around
and zoom in and out and flip okay
so we're going to take four of them at
random and we're going to take the
original and augmented sent a cropped
image and we're going to do a prediction
for all of those and then we're going to
take the average of those predictions so
I'm going to say is this a cat is this a
cat is this a cat is this a cat but and
so hopefully in one of those random ones
we actually make sure that the face is
there zoomed in by a similar amount to
other dogs faces at sea and it's rotated
by the amount that it expects to see it
and so forth and so do that all we have
to do is just call tt8
TTA stands for Test time augmentation
this term of like what a what do we call
up when we're making predictions from up
from a model we've trained sometimes
it's called inference time sometimes
it's called test time everybody since
have a different name so TTA and so when
we do that we go learn TTA check the
accuracy and lo and behold
we're now at ninety nine point six five
percent which is kind of crazy where's
our green box but for every park we are
only showing one type of augmentation or
for particular image right so when we
are training back here we're not doing
any TTA right so TTA is not like you
could and sometimes like I've written
libraries where after a cheap up I run
TTA to see how well it's going but
that's not what's happening here I
trained the whole thing with training
time organization which doesn't have a
special name because that's what we mean
when we say data augmentation we need
training time augmentation so here every
time we showed a picture
we were randomly changing it a little
bit so each epoch each of these seven
epochs it was seen slightly different
versions of the picture having done that
we now have a fully trained model we
then said okay let's look at the
validation set so TTA by default uses
the validation set and said okay what
are your predictions of which ones are
cats and which ones are dogs and it did
4 predictions with different random
orientations plus one on the organ under
Augmented version average them all
together and that's what we got and
that's what we can't clear the accurate
so is there a high probability of having
sample in TTA that was not shown in
doing trained yeah actually every data
augmented for image is is unique because
the rotation could be like point zero
three four degrees and zoom could be 1.0
one sixty five so every time it's
slightly different no problem
was behind you what's your might not use
white padding or something like that
just one of your white padding like just
you know put like a white water around
oh padding's not yes so like there's
lots of different types of a better
orientation you can do and so one of the
things you can do is to add a border
around it basically adding a border
around it in my experiments doesn't
doesn't help it doesn't make it any less
cat-like it's not the convolutional
neural network doesn't seem to find it
very interesting basically something
that I do do we'll see later is I do
something called reflection padding
which is where I add some borders that
are the outside just reflected it's a
way to kind of make some bigger images
works well with satellite imagery in
particular but yeah in general I don't
do I have a lot of padding instead I do
a bit of zooming
it's kind of follow-up to that last one
but rather than cropping just at white
space because when you crop you lose the
dog's face but if you added white space
you wouldn't yeah so that's that's where
the kind of the reflection padding or
the zooming or whatever can help so
there are ways in the faster you know
library when you do custom transforms of
of making that happen I find that it
kind of depends on the image size you
know but generally speaking it seems
that using TTA plus data augmentation
the best thing to do is to try to use
this larger image as possible and so if
you kind of crop the thing down and put
white borders on top and bottom it's now
quite a lot smaller and so to make it as
big as it was before you now have to use
more GPU and if you're going to use more
that multi figure you could have zoomed
in and used a bigger image so in my
playing around that doesn't seem to be
generally as successful there is a
little interest on the topic of how do
the domain tation in older than images
indeed at least not images um yeah um no
one seems to know I actually um I asked
some of my friends in the natural
language processing community about this
we'll get to natural language processing
in a couple of lessons you know it seems
like it'd be really helpful there's been
a few example I carry very few number
examples of people where papers would
like try replacing synonyms for instance
but on the whole and understanding of
like appropriate data augmentation for
non image domains is under-researched in
under under developed the question was
could couldn't we just use a sliding
window to generate on the images so in
that dog thank you couldn't we generate
three parts of it wouldn't that be
better
yeah PTI you mean just just in general
when you're creating your so
training time I would say no that
wouldn't be better because we're not
gonna get as much variation you know we
want to have it like like one degree off
five you know five degrees off ten
pixels up like lots of slightly
different versions and so if you just
have three standard ways then you're not
giving it as many different ways of
looking at the data for testing
augmentation having fixed cropped
locations I think probably would be
better and I just haven't gotten around
to writing that yet I have a version in
an old library I think having fixed
cropped locations plus random contrast
brightness rotation changes might be
better
the reason I've got around to it yet is
because in my testing it didn't seem to
help him practice very much and it made
the code a lot more complicated so you
know it's kind of it's an interesting
question
I just wanted all of this last AI api's
that you are using is it yeah that's a
great question
so the faster you go libraries open
source and let's talk about it a bit
more generally because you know it's
like the fact that the fact that we're
using this library is kind of
interesting and unusual and it sits on
top of something called a torch right so
pi torch is a fairly recent development
and it's kind of I've noticed all the
researchers that I respect pretty much
are now using high torch I found in part
two of last year's course that a lot of
the cutting-edge stuff I wanted to teach
I couldn't do it in chaos and tensorflow
which is what we used to teach with and
so I had to switch the course to pay
torch halfway through part two the
problem was that PI torch isn't very
easy to use you have to write your own
training loop from scratch I basically
write everything from scratch or the
stuff you see inside the class they are
library we would have had to written it
you know to learn and so it really makes
it very hard to learn deep learning when
you have to write hundreds of lines of
code to do anything so so we decided to
create a library on top of Pi torch
because we you know this our mission is
to teach world class big morning so we
wanted to show you like here's how you
can be the best in the world at doing it
and we found that a lot of the world
class stuff we needed to show really
needed PI torch or at least with PI
torch it was far easier and but then PI
thought itself just wasn't suitable as a
first thing to teach with for new for
new deep learning practitioners so we
built this library on up of PI torch
initially heavily influenced by chaos
which is what we taught last year and
but then we realized we could actually
make things much much much easier than
care us so in care us if you look back
at last year's course notes you'll find
that all of the code is two to three
times longer and there's lots more
opportunities for
stakes because there's just a lot of
things you have to get right so we ended
up kind of building this this this
library in order to make it easier to
get into deep learning but also easier
to get state-of-the-art results and then
over the last year as we started
developing on top of that we started
discovering that by using this library
it made us so much more productive that
we actually started kind of developing
you state-of-the-art results and new
methods ourselves and we started
realizing that there's a whole bunch of
like papers that have kind of been
ignored or lost which when you use them
it could like automate or semi-automated
stuff like learning read finder that's
not in any other library so so it kind
of got to the point where now not only
is kind of fast AI lets us do things
easier much easier than any other
approach but at the same time it
actually has a lot more kind of
sophisticated stuff behind the scenes
than anything else so so it's kind of an
interesting mix so yeah so we've
released this library like at this stage
it's like very early version and so
through this course by the end of this
course I hope as a group you know we
will all a lot of people are already
helping have developed it into something
that's you know really pretty stable and
rock-solid and yeah anybody can then can
use it to build your own models under an
open-source license as you can see it's
available on github behind the scenes
it's it's creating play torch models and
so apply torch models can then be
exported into various different formats
having said that like a lot of folks
like issue if you want to do something
on a mobile phone for example you're
probably going to need to use tensorflow
and so later on in this course we're
going to show like how some of the
things that we're doing in the past AI
library you can do in chaos and cancel
flow so you can going to get a sense of
what the different libraries look like
and generally speaking the simple stuff
is like it'll take you a small number of
days
to learn to do it and care us in
tensorflow versus fast AI and high torch
and the more complex stuff often this
won't be possible so that like if you
needed to be intensive flow you're just
kind of simplify it off in a little bit
but you know I think the more important
thing to realize is every year the kind
of the libraries that are available and
which ones are the best totally changes
so like the main thing I hope that you
get out of this course is an
understanding of the concepts like
here's how you find a learning rate
here's why differential learning rates
are important is they do learn where the
kneeling you know here's what stochastic
gradient a second's restarts does so on
and so forth because you know by the
time we do this course again next year
you know the library situations and the
difference the king that's a question of
that I was wondering if you've had an
opinion on pyro which is ubers new
release I haven't looked at it no I'm
very interested in probabilistic
programming and it's really cool that's
built on top of paper so one of the
things we'll learn about in this course
is we'll see that PI torch is much more
than just a deep learning library it
actually lets us write arbitrary
gpu-accelerated algorithms from scratch
which we're actually going to do and
pyro is a great example of what people
are now doing with might watch outside
of the deep level great ok let's take a
eight-minute break and we'll come back
at 7:55 so ninety nine point six five
percent accuracy what does that mean so
in classification when we do
classification and machine learning the
really simple way to look at the result
of a classification is what's called the
confusion matrix this is not just deep
learning but in any kind of classifier
machine learning where we say okay what
was the actual truth there were
thousand cats and a thousand dogs out of
the thousand actual cats how many did we
predict were cats this is obviously in
the validation step this is the images
that we didn't use to train with it
turns out there were nine hundred
ninety-eight cats that we actually
predicted as cats and two that we got
wrong
okay and then for dogs there were nine
hundred ninety-five that we predicted
were dogs and then five that we got
wrong and so often these confusion
matrices can be helpful particularly if
you've got like four or five classes
you're trying to predict to see like
which group you having the most trouble
with and you can see it uses color
coding to tell you you know to highlight
the large the large bits you've got to
hope that the diagonal is the
highlighted section so now that we've
retrained the model it can be quite
helpful now that's better to actually
look back and see like okay which ones
in particular were incorrect and we can
see here there were actually only two
incorrect cats it prints out four by
default so you can actually see these
two actually less than 0.5 so they
weren't they weren't wrong okay so it's
actually these two were wrong cats and
this one isn't obviously a cat at all
this one is but it looks like it's got a
lot of weird artifacts and you can't see
its eyeballs at all so and then here are
the how many dogs where they're all
wrong there were five wrong dogs here
are four of them that's not obviously a
dog that looks like a mistake that looks
like a mistake that one I guess doesn't
have enough information that I guess
it's a mistake so so we've done a pretty
good job here of creating a good
classifier I would based on entering a
lot of capital competitions and
comparing results I've done two various
research papers I can tell you it's a
state of the art classifier it's it's
right up there with the best in the
world we're going to make it a little
bit better in a moment but here in the
basic steps right so if you want to
create a world-class image classifier
the steps that we just went through was
that we started our week's term data
augmentation on by saying oil transforms
equals and you either say sidon or
top-down depending on what you're doing
start with pre compute equals true find
a decent learning
eight we then train just like it one or
two epochs which that takes a few
seconds as we got through compute equals
true then we turn off pre compute which
allows us to use data augmentation to do
another two or three epochs generally
with cycle length equals one then I
unfreeze all them as I then set the
earlier layers to be like either
somewhere between a 3 times 2 10 times
mobile learning rate in the previous so
in this case I did 10 times right so
it's like this was my learning rate that
I found from the learning rate finer
than I went 10 times smaller and then 10
times smaller as a rule of thumb like
knowing that you're starting with a pre
trained imagenet model if you know if
you can see that the things that you're
now trying to classify a pretty similar
the kinds of things in imagenet ie
pictures of normal objects in normal
environments
you probably want about a 10x difference
because you want those earlier layers
like you think that the earlier layers
are probably very good already but also
if you're doing something like satellite
imagery or medical imaging which is not
at all like image net then you probably
want to be training those earlier layers
a lot more so you might have like oh
just a 3/8 difference all right so
that's like one change that I make is to
try to make it out of 10x or 3x yes so
then after unfreezing you can now call
LR find again but at Nike didn't in this
case but like once you've unfrozen all
the layers you've turned on differential
learning rates you can then call a lot
of fine again right and so you can then
check like oh does it still look like
the same point I had last time is about
right something to note is that if you
call LR find having set differential
learning rates the thing that's actually
going to print out is the learning rate
of the last layers right because you've
got three different learning rates so
it's actually showing you the last layer
so then yeah then I trained the full
network with cycle more equals two and
it'll either it starts with the fitting
or I run out of time right so like let
me show you all right so let's do this
again
a totally different data set so this
morning I noticed that some of you on
the forums were playing around with this
playground Kegel competition very
similar called dog breed identification
so the dog breed identification cat will
challenge is one where you don't
actually have to decide which ones are
cats and which ones the dogs they're all
dogs but you have to decide what kind of
dog it is but there are 120 different
breeds of dogs okay
so you know obviously this could be like
different types of cells and pathology
slides it could be different kinds of
cancers in CT scans it could be
different kinds of icebergs and
satellite images whatever right as long
as you've got some kind of labeled
images so I want to show you what I did
this morning so it took me about an hour
basically to go in to end from something
I'd never seen before so I downloaded
the data from kaggle and I'll show you
how to do that shortly but the short
answer is there's something called cable
CLI which is a github project you can
search for and if you read the docs to
basically run cagey download provide the
competition name and it will grab all
the data for you to your crystal or
Amazon or whatever instance I put in my
data folder and I then went LS and I saw
that it's a little bit different to our
previous data set it's not that there's
a train folder which has a separate
folder for each kind of dog but instead
of tonette there was a CSV file and the
CSV file I read it in with pandas so
pandas is the thing we use in python to
do structured data analysis like csv
files so he picked pandas we called pd
that's pretty much universal PDR htsb
reads in the csv file we can then take a
look at it and you can see that
basically it had like some kind of
identifier and then the debris right so
this is like a different way this is the
second main way that people kind of give
you image labels one is to put different
images into different folders
the second is generally to give you as
some kind of file like a CSV file to
tell you here's the image name and
here's the label okay so what I then did
was I used pandas again to create a
pivot table which basically groups it up
just to see how many of each breed there
were and I sorted them and so I saw okay
they've got like about a hundred some of
the more common breeds and some of the
less common breeds they've got like 60
or so okay altogether there are 120 rows
and I've been 120 different breeds
represented okay so I'm going to go
through the steps right so enable data
augmentation so to enable data
augmentation when we call this
transforms from model you just pass in
and all transformers in this case I
chose side on again these are pictures
of dots and stuff so this side on photos
I we're talking about maqsuum as more
detail later but maximum basically says
when you do the data augmentation we
like zoom into it by up to one point one
times okay so but randomly between one
the original image size and one point
one points so it's not always cropping
out in the middle or an edge but it
could be cropping out a smaller part
okay so having done that the key step
now is to graphically going from paths
so previously we went from paths and
that tells it that the the names of the
folders are the names of the labels we
go from CSV and we pass in the CSV file
that contains the letters so we're
passing in the path that contains all of
the data the name of the folder that
contains the training data the CSV that
contains the labels we need to also tell
it where the test set is if you want to
submit to cattle later talk more about
that next week now this time the
previous data set we had had actually
separated a validation set out into a
separate folder right but in this case
you'll see that there is not a separate
folder called validation right so we
want to be able to track how good our
performance is low
so we're going to have to separate some
of the images out to put it into a
validation set okay so I do that at
random and so up here you can see how it
basically opened up the CSV file turned
it into a list of rows and then taken
the length of that minus one because
there's a header at the top right and so
that's the number of rows in the CSV
file which must be the number of images
that we have and then this is a fast AI
thing get cross-validation indexes now
we'll talk about cross-validation later
but basically if you call this and pass
in a number it's going to return to you
by default a random twenty percent of
the rows who uses your validation set
and you can pass in parameters to get
different amounts right so this is now
going to grab twenty percent of the data
and say all right this is the this is
the indexes the numbers of the files
which we're going to use as a validation
set
okay so now that we've got that in fact
let's kind of run this so you can see
what that looks like so well indexes is
just a big bunch of numbers okay and so
an is
10,000 right and so we have about twenty
percent of those is going to be in a
validation set
so when we call from CSV we can pass in
a parameter which is talent which
indexes to treat us a validation set and
so that's passed in those indexes one
thing that's a little bit tricky here is
that the file names actually have I
checked they actually have a dot jpg on
the end and these obviously don't have a
dot jpg so you can pass in when you call
from CSV you can pass in a suffix it
says that the labels don't actually
contain the full file names you need to
add this to them okay so that's
basically all I need to do to set up my
data and as a lot of Europe noticed
during the week inside that data object
you can actually get access to the data
set like what the training data set by
same train yes and inside train des is a
whole bunch of things including the file
names
okay so train desktop file names
contains all of the file names of
everything in the training set and so
here's like one file name
okay so here's an example of one file
name so I can now go ahead and open that
file and take a look at it that's the
next thing I did was to try and
understand what my file my dataset looks
like and it found an adorable puppy so
that was very nice
so feeling good about this I also want
to know like how big of these files
right like how big are the images
because that's a key issue if they're
huge and then I have to think really
carefully about how to deal with huge
images that's really challenging if
they're tiny well that's also
challenging most of imagenet models are
trained on either 224 by 224 or 299 by
299 images so anytime you have images in
that kind of range that's that's really
hopeful you're probably not going to
have to do too much different in this
case the first image I looked at was
about the right size so I'm thinking of
pretty hopeful so what I did then is I
created a dictionary comprehension now
if you don't know about list
comprehensions and dictionary
comprehensions in Python go study them
they're the most useful thing super
handy you can see the basic idea here is
that are going through all of the files
and then putting a dictionary that map's
the name of the file to the size of that
file again this is a handy little Python
feature which I'll let you think learn
about during the week if you don't know
about it which is zip and using a
special star notation is never to take
this dictionary and turn it into the
rows and the columns and so I can now
turn those into num pay arrays and like
okay here are the first five rows sizes
for each of my images and then
matplotlib is something you want to be
very familiar with if you do any kind of
data science or machine learning in
python matplotlib we always refer to as
PLT as if this is a histogram and so I
got a histogram of the how high how many
rows there are in each image so you can
see here I'm kind of getting a sense
before I start doing any modeling I kind
of need to know what I'm modeling with
and I can see some of the images are
going to be like 2500 3000 pixels high
but most of them seem to be around 500
so given it so few of them were bigger
than a thousand I use standard numpy
slicing to just grab those at a smaller
than a thousand and histogram that just
to zoom in a little bit and I can see
here all right it looks like yet the
vast majority are around 500 and so this
actually also prints out the histogram
so I can actually go through and I can
see here for four thousand five hundred
of them are about 450 okay so I get
about that seems about anywhere so
generally how many images should we get
in the validation set is always a 20%
so the size of the validation set like
using 20% is fine unless you kind of
feeling like my data is my data sets
really small I'm not sure that's enough
you know like if you've got basically
think of it this way if you train like
the same model multiple times and you're
getting very different validation set
results and your validation sets kind of
small but smaller than a thousand or so
then it's going to be quite hard to
interpret how well you're doing now this
is particularly true like if you're like
if you care about the third decimal
place of accuracy and you've got like a
thousand things in your validation set
then you bring about like a single image
changing class is changing you know it's
what you're looking at so it's it really
depends on my cow accurate you have much
difference you care about I would say in
general like at the point where you care
about difference between like out of
0.01 and 0.02 like the second decimal
place you want that to represent like 10
or 20 roads you know like changing the
class of that 10 or 20 rows then that's
something you can be pretty confident of
so like most of the time you know give
them the data sizes we normally have 20
percent seems to work fine but yeah it's
it's it's kind of a it depends a lot on
specifically what you're doing and what
you care about and it's not it's not a
deep learning specific question either
you know so those who are interested in
this kind of thing we're going to look
into it a lot more detail in our machine
learning course which will also be
available online ok so I did the same
thing for the columns just to make sure
that these aren't like super wide and
I've got similar results and checked in
and again found they're kind of like 4
or 500 seem to be about the average size
so based on all of that I kind of
thought ok this looks like a pretty
normal kind of image data set that I can
probably use pretty normal kinds of
models on I was also particularly
encouraged to see that when I looked at
the
that the dog like takes up most of the
frame right so I'm not too worried about
like cropping problems you know if the
if the dog was just like a tiny little
piece of one little corner that I'd be
thinking about doing different you know
maybe zooming in a lot more or something
like a medical imaging that happens a
lot like often the tumor or the cell
whatever is like one tiny piece and
there's much more complex so yeah based
on all that and this morning I kind of
thought like okay this looks pretty
standard so I I went ahead and created a
little function called get data that
basically had my normal two lines of
code in it but I made it so I could
passed in a size and a batch size the
reason for this is that when I start
working with new data set I want
everything to go super fast and so if I
use small images it's going to go super
fast so I actually started out with size
equals 64 just to create some super
small images that just go like a second
to run through and see how it later on I
started using some big images and some
and some also some bigger architectures
at which point I started running out of
GPU memory so I started getting these
errors saying CUDA out of memory error
when you get a CUDA out of memory error
the first thing you need to do is to go
kernel restart once you get a code an
out of memory error on your GPU you
can't really recover from it right
doesn't matter what you do you know you
have to go restart and once I've
restarted I then just changed my batch
size to something smaller so when you
call create your data object you can
pass in a batch size parameter okay and
like i normally use 64 until i hit
something that says out of memory and
then i'll just have it and if i still
get out of memory I was hobbit again
okay so that's where I created this to
allow me to like start making my size as
bigger as I looked into it more and you
know as I started running out of memory
to decrease my batch size so at this
point you know I went through this a
couple of iterations but I basically
found everything was working fine so
once it's working fine
set size 2 to 24 and I created my you
know pre-compute equals true first time
I did that it took a minute to create
the precomputed activations and then it
ran through this in about 4 or 5 seconds
and you can see I was getting
eighty-three percent accuracy
now remember accuracy means it's it's
exactly right and so it's predicting out
of a hundred and twenty categories it's
predicting exactly right so when you see
something with two classes is you know
80% accurate versus something with 120
classes is 80% accurate they're very
different levels you know so when I saw
like eighty-three percent accuracy with
just a pre computed classify and OData
augmentation though I'm freezing
anything else
across 120 classes of the oh this looks
good right so um then I just kind of
kept going throughout at all standard
process right so then I turn precompute
off okay and cycle length equals one and
I started doing a few more cycles few
more epochs so remember an epoch is one
pass through the data and a cycle is
however many epochs you said is in a
cycle it's one it's the learning rate
going from the top that you asked for
all the way down so since here cycle
length equals one a cycle in an epoch at
the same okay so I did I tried a few
epochs I did actually do the learning
rate finder and I found one in a two
again looked fine it often looks fine
and I found it kind of kept improving so
I tried five epochs and I found my
accuracy getting better so then I saved
that and I tried something which we
haven't looked at before but it's kind
of cool if you train something on a
smaller size you can then actually call
learned set data and pass in a larger
size data set and that's gonna take your
model however it's trained so far and
it's going to let you can
in you to train on on larger images and
I tell you something amazing
this actually is another way you can get
state-of-the-art results and I've never
seen this written in any paper or
discussed anywhere as far as I know this
is a new insight basically I've got a
pre trained model which in this case
I've trained a few epochs with the size
of 224 by 224 and I'm now going to do a
few more air pops with the size of 299
by 299 now I've gotten very little data
cut out by deep learning standards only
about 10,000 images right so with a 224
by 224 I kind of built this these final
layers to try to find things that work
well to 24 but to 24 but I go to 299 by
299 I basically if I over fit before I'm
definitely not going to over fit now
might have changed the size of my images
they're kind of like totally different
but like conceptually they're still
picked the same kinds of pictures are
the same kinds of things so I found this
trick of like starting training on small
images for a few a box and then
switching to bigger images and
continuing training is an amazingly
effective way to avoid overfitting and
it's like it's so easy and so obvious I
don't understand why it's never been
written about before maybe it's in some
paper somewhere and I haven't found it
but it's I haven't seen it would it be
possible to do the same thing on using
let's take a resort our disposal to feed
a different size yeah I think so like as
long as you use one of these more modern
architectures what we call fully
convolutional architectures which means
not vgg and you'll see we don't use vgg
in this course because it doesn't have
this property but most of the
architectures developed in the last
couple of years can handle pretty much
arbitrary sizes yeah be worth trying
yeah I think it ought to work okay so I
call get data again remember get data is
the just a little function that I
created back up here right get data is
just this little function that's oh I
just passed a different size to it and
so I call freeze just to make sure that
but everything so the last layer is
frozen I mean it actually already was at
its point that really doing a thing
and
you can see now with free compute off
I've now got that data augmentation
working so I kind of run a few more a
pox and what I notice here is that the
loss to my training set and the loss of
my validation set my validation set loss
is a lot lower than my training set this
is still just training the last layer so
what this is telling me is I'm under
fitting right and so from under fitting
it means this cycle length equals one is
too short it means it's like finding
something better popped with popping out
and it's like never getting a chance to
zoom in properly so then I'd set cycle
mod equals two to give it more time so
like the first time is one epoch the
second one is two epochs
the third one is for epochs and you can
see now the validation train and
training are about the same okay so
that's kind of thinking yeah this is
this is about the right track and so
then I tried using test time
augmentation to see if that gets any
better still didn't actually help a hell
of a lot just a tiny bit and just kind
of at this point I think here this is
nearly done so I just did it like you
know one more cycle of two to see if it
got any better and it did get a little
bit better and then I'm like okay that
looks pretty good
I've got a validation set lost 0.199
and so your Lotus here actually you
haven't tried unfreezing the reason why
I was going to try to unfreezing and
training more it didn't get any better
and so the reason for this clearly is
that this data set is so similar the
image net that the training that
convolutional layers actually doesn't
help in the slightest and actually when
I loaded up into it it turns out that
this competition is actually using a
subset of improve image net so that's
okay so that if we check this out point
one nine nine against the leaderboard
this is only a playground competition so
it's not like the best of here but you
know it's still interesting it gets us
somewhere around ten thrillers okay and
in fact we're competing against I
noticed other
the first AI student this is a first AI
student these people up here I know they
actually posted that they cheated they
actually went you downloaded the
original images and train to that so and
this is why this is a playground
competition they call it it's not it's
not real right you know it's just to
allow us to try things out but you can
basically see out of two hundred and
something people where you know we're
getting some very good results without
doing anything remotely interesting or
clever and we haven't even used the
whole data set you're going to use to
eighty percent of it like to get a
better result I would go back and remove
that validation set and just rerun the
same steps and then submit that exact
let's just use it under percent of the
data I have three questions the first
one is like that class in this case is
very it's not balanced
instead unbalanced like it's not totally
balanced but it's not bad right it's
like between sixty and a hundred like
it's it's it's it's not unbalanced
enough that I would give it a second
thought
okay yeah let's get to that later in
this course and don't let me forget
right the short answer is that there was
a recent list the paper came out about
two or three weeks ago on this and it
said the best way to deal with very
unbalanced data sets is to basically
make copies of the rare cases yeah my
second question is I want to pin down a
difference between creation he read was
and so you have these two options right
so when you beginning I did an
optimization use that pre computed it
was true by not using layers right right
so it's not only they frozen their pre
computed so the data augmentation
doesn't do anything at that point
right before you outcries everything
what as examples you and IV only you
only on freeze
so we're going to learn more about the
details as we look into the the math and
stuff in coming lessons but basically
what happened was we started with a pre
trained network right which was kind of
finding activations that had these kind
of rich features and we were adding then
we add a couple of layers on the end of
it which which start out random and so
with fries equals with with everything
frozen and indeed with pre compute
equals true all we're learning is told
is those couple of layers that we've
added and so with pre compute equals
true we actually pretty calculate like
how much does this image have something
that looks like this a ball one looks
like this face and so forth and
therefore data augmentation doesn't do
anything with pre compute equals true
because you know we're actually showing
exactly the same activations each time
we can then set pre compute equals false
which means it's still only training
those last two layers that we added it's
still frozen but data augmentations now
working because it's actually going
through and recalculating all of the
activations from scratch and then
finally when we unfreeze that's actually
saying okay now you can go ahead and
change all of these earlier
convolutional filters so well you just
so the only reason to have pre compute
equals true is it's just much faster so
it's like it is it's about you know ten
or more times faster so particularly if
you're working with like quite a large
data set you know it can save quite a
bit of time but it's never there's no
like companies like accuracy reason ever
to use pre computed calls true it's just
a it's just a shortcut it's also like
quite handy if you're like throwing
together a quick model you know it can
take a few seconds to create
my last question which I think you
answer is I don't like your suggestions
to build a model you have this aged yeah
what if would you like we just wanted
one initial setting without these like
checking after each I mean if you want
it like if your question is like is
there some shorter version of this
that's like a bit quicker and easier I
could like to lead a few things here
okay I think this is a kind of a minimal
version to get you a very good result
which is like don't worry about pre
compute equals true because that's just
saving a little bit of time you know so
so I still suggest use LR find at the
start to find a good learning rate by
default everything is frozen from the
start so then you can just go ahead and
run two or three epochs or cyclic
Nichols one unfreeze and then train the
rest of the network with differential
learning rates so it's basically three
steps learning rate finder trained
frozen network with cycle methods one
and then trained unfrozen network with
differential learning rates and cycle
molecules too so like that's something
you could turn into I guess five or six
lines of code at all I think it's a
question provide your own mix book by
reusing the batch size does the only at
better speed of training yeah pretty
much so each batch and again we're going
to see like all this stuff about
precomputing batch sizes we dig into the
details of the algorithms it's going to
make a lot more sense intuitively but
basically if you're showing it less
images each time then it's calculating
the gradient with less images which
means it's less accurate which means
like knowing which direction to go and
how far to go in that direction is less
accurate so as you make the batch size
smaller
you're basically making it kind of more
volatile it's
kind of like it kind of impacts the
optimal learning rate that you would
need to use but in practice where only
you know I generally find only dividing
with the batch size by like 2 or 4 it
doesn't seem to change things very much
should I reveals the learning rate of
quality me if you if you change the
batch size by much you can rerun the
learning rate finder to see if it's
changed if I match but it it I was in
for only generally looking at like a
power of 10 it probably is not going to
change the it's not that you can't
because plus back there
this is sort of a conceptual basic
questions we're going back to the
previous night where you should put in
the thought behind sorry yeah this is
well one for conceptual so a basic
question we've actually really slide
where you should what the different
layers were doing yes from this slide I
understand right the meaning of sync the
third column relative to the fourth
column is that what you're interpreting
what the layer is doing based on what
the image is actually yeah so we're
going to look at this in more detail so
these these gray ones basically say this
is kind of what the filter looks like so
on the first layer you can see exactly
what the filter looks like because the
input to it of pixels right so you can
absolutely say and remember we looked at
what a convolutional kernel was like was
that three by three thing so this look
like there's seven by seven kernels you
can say this is actually what it looks
like but later on it's combined you know
the the the input to it are themselves
activations which are combinations of
activations relation to activations so
you can't draw it but there's clever
technique that I learned focus created
which allowed them to say this is kind
of what the filters tended to look like
on average alright so this is kind of
what the photos look like and then here
is specific examples of patches of image
which activated that filter highly so
yet the pictures are the ones that I
kind of find more useful because it
tells you this kernel is kind of a mini
cycle we all find right how do we know
that's it well we'll come back well we
may come back to that if not in this
part in the next part that probably a
part two actually because this paper
this paper uses to create these things
this paper uses something called a
deconvolution which I'm pretty sure we
won't do in this part but we will do it
in part two so if you're interested
check out the paper it's it's in the
notebook has a link to it xyler in
Fergus it's a very clever technique and
not terribly intuitive
um right so so you mentioned that it was
good that the dog took up the full
picture and it would have been a problem
if it was kind of like off in one of the
corners in really tiny well what would
you what would you technique have been
to try to make that work something that
we'll learn about in part two but
basically there's a technique that
allows you to to kind of figure out
roughly which parts of an image and most
likely to have the interesting things in
them and then you can like crop out
those bits if you're interested in
learning about it we did cover it
briefly in lesson seven of part one but
I'm going to actually do it properly in
part two of this course because I didn't
really cover it thoroughly enough maybe
we'll find time to have a quick look at
it but we'll see I know your Nets
written some of the code that we need
already
ah
so once I have something like this
notebook that's basically working I can
immediately make it better by doing two
things assuming that the size image I
was using is smaller than the average
size of the image that we've been given
I can increase the size and as I showed
before with the dog breeds you can
actually increase it during training the
other thing I can do is to create is to
use a better architecture now an
architect we're going to talk a lot in
this course about architectures but
basically there are different ways of
putting together like what size
convolutional filters and how are they
connected to each other and so forth and
different architectures have different
like numbers of layers and sizes of
kernels and number of filters and so
forth and so there are some the one that
we've been using ResNet 34 is a great
starting point and often a good
finishing point because it's like it's
pretty it doesn't have too many
parameters often it works pretty well
with small amounts of data as we've seen
and so forth but there's actually an
architecture that I really like called
not res net but res next which was
actually the second-place winner in last
year's image net competition and like
ResNet you can put a number after the
res next to say like how big it is and
like my next step after resume 34 is
always res next 50 now you'll find res
next 50 takes like can take like twice
as long as ResNet 34 that can take like
2 to 4 times as much memory as retina 34
so what I wanted to do was I wanted to
rerun that previous notebook with res
next and increasing the image size to
turn on a node so here I just said
architecture equals res next 50 size
equals 299 and then I found that I had
to take the batch size all the way back
to 28 to get it to fit my GPU is 11 gig
if you're using AWS or cresol I think
they're like 12 gigs they might be
a bit higher but this is what I found I
had to do so then I this is literally a
copy of the previous notebook so you can
actually go file make a copy right and
then rerun it with with these different
parameters and so I deleted some of the
pros and some of the expiratory stuff to
see you know basically I said everything
else is the same all the same steps as
before there's my in fact you can kind
of see what this minimum service desk
looks like I didn't need to worry about
learning rate finder so I just left it
as is so transforms data equals loan
equals bit pre computed false feet with
cycle integrals one and freeze
differential learning rates bits and
more and you can see here I didn't do
the cycle mop thing because I found like
now that I'm using a bigger architecture
it's got more parameters it was
overfitting pretty quickly so rather
than like cycle length equals one never
finding the right spot it actually did
find the right spot and if I used longer
cycle legs I found that my validation
error was higher than my training error
it was over there so check us out though
by using these you know three steps
I got plus TTA 99.75
so what does that mean that means I have
one incorrect dog for incorrect cats and
when we look at the pictures of them my
incorrect dog has a cat now this one is
not a either this one is not either so
I've actually got one mistake and then
my incorrect dog is teeth right so like
we're at a point where we're now able to
train a classifier that's so good that
it has like basically one's dead right
and so when people say like we have
superhuman image performance now this is
kind of what they're talking about right
so did you actually when I looked at the
dog breed one I did this morning I was
like it was it was getting the dog
breeds much better than I ever could
so like hits this this is what we can
get to if you use a really modern
architect
like redneck and this suddenly took out
a tall way and remember don't like 20
minutes to Train so that's kind of where
we're up to so if you want to do
satellite imagery
instead right then it's the same thing
and in fact the the planet satellite
data sets already oh and Chris or if
you're using Chris or you can jump
straight there right and I just went
into this data stash planet and I can do
exactly the same thing right I can image
classifier from CSV right and you can
see these three lines are actually
exactly the same as my dog breed lines
you know how big how many lines are in
the file grab my validation indexes this
get data as you can see it's identical
except I've changed side on to top down
the satellite images about top down so I
can fit them vertically and they still
make sense right and so you can see here
I'm doing this trick round back to size
equals 64 and train a little bit first
learning rate find on right and
interestingly in this case you can see
it I want really high learning rates I
don't know what it is about this
particular data set this is true but
it's clearly I can use super high
learning rate so I use a lot here at a
point too and so I've trained for a
while
differential learning rates right and so
remember I said like if the data sets
very different to image net I probably
want to train those middle layers a lot
more so I'm using divided by three
rather than divided by ten all right the
other than that is the same thing cycle
Nauticals - all right and then I just
kind of keep an eye on it so you can
actually plot the loss if you go and
learned up shared a plot loss you can
see here that here's the first cycle is
the second cycle is the third cycle
right so you can see it gets better pops
out gets better pops out if better pops
out and each time it finds something
better than the last time
then set the size up to 128 and just
repeat exactly the last few steps and
then set up to 256
repeat the last two steps and then do
TTA and if you submit this and this gets
about 30th place in this competition so
these basic steps work super well this
this thing where I went all the way back
to a size of 64 I wouldn't do that if I
was doing like dogs and cats or dog
breeds because like this is so small
that if if the thing I was working on is
very similar to imagenet I would kind of
destroy those imagenet weights like 64
by 64 is so small but in this case the
satellite imagery data it's so different
to imagenet um you know I really found
that it worked pretty well
start right back to these tiny images it
really helped me to avoid overfitting
and interestingly using this kind of
approach I actually found that even with
using only 128 by 128 I was getting like
much better cackled results than really
everybody on the leader board
and when I say 30th place this is a very
recent competition right and so I find
like in the last year like a lot of
people have got a lot better at computer
vision and so the people in the top 50
in this competition were generally
ensemble in dozens of models lots of
people on a team lots of pre-processing
specific satellite data and so forth so
like to be able to get xxx using this
totally standard technique is pretty
cool
alright so now that we've got to this
point right we've got through two
lessons if you're still here then
hopefully you're thinking okay this is
actually pretty useful I want to do more
in which case Kressel might not be where
you want to stay the issues with Kressel
I mean it's it's it's pretty handy it's
pretty cheap and something we haven't
talked about much is paper space is
another great choice by the way paper
space are short they're going to be
releasing kress or like instant Drupal
notebooks unfortunately they're not
ready quite yet but they do have an
ability to basically they have the best
price performance relationship right now
and they you can SSH into them and use
them so they're also a great choice and
probably by the time this
the MOOC will probably have a separate
lesson showing you how to set up set up
paper space because there they're likely
to be a great option but at some point
you're probably going to want to look at
AWS a couple of reasons why the first is
as you all know by now amazon have been
kind enough to donate about $200,000
worth of compute time to this course so
I want to say thank you very much to
Amazon we've all been given credit so
everybody this year so thanks very much
hey don't worry we're so sorry you're
sure in the MOOC we didn't get it for
you but everybody here is like AWS
credits for everybody so um but you can
get even if you're not here in person
you can get AWS credits from lots of
places github has a student pack Google
for github student pack that's like 150
bucks worth of credits AWS educate can
get credits these our office students so
there's lots of places you can get
started on AWS pretty much everybody
everybody a lot of the people that you
might work with will be using AWS
because it's like super flexible right
now AWS has the fastest available GPUs
you can get in the cloud they're p3s
they're kind of expensive at three bucks
an hour but if you've got like a model
where you've done all the steps before
you're thinking this is looking pretty
good you know for 6 bucks you could get
a p3 for 2 hours and run turbo speed
right um we didn't start with AWS
because well hey it's like twice as
expensive as Chris Hall for the cheapest
GPU and being a Texan setup right but I
wanted to kind of go through and show
you how to get your AWS setup and so
we're going to be going slightly over
time to do that but I want to show you a
very quick place I feel prettier if you
have to but I want to show you very
quickly how you can get your AWS setup
right from scratch so basically you have
to go to consult on AWS but amazon.com
and it'll take you to the console right
and so you can follow along on the video
with this
quickly from here you have to go to AC -
this is where you set up your instances
and so from ec2 you need to do what's
called launching an instance so
launching an instance means you're
basically creating a computer right now
creating a computer on Amazon so I say
launch instance and what we've done is
we've created a fast AI it's got an amo
and ami is like a template for how your
computer's going to begin so if you've
got a community a Mis and type in fast
AI you'll see that there's one there
called fast AI part 1 version 2 for the
p2 ok so I'm going to select that and
then we need to say what kind of
computer do you want and so I can say I
want a GPU compute computer and then I
can say I want a p2 x large this is the
cheapest reasonably effective for deep
learning instance type they have and
then I can say launch and then I can say
launch and so at this point they asked
you to choose a key pair right now
if you don't have a key pair you have to
create one right so to create a key pair
you need to open your terminal if you
don't have a terminal if you've got a
Mac or Linux box you've definitely got
one if you've got Windows hopefully
you've got Ubuntu if you don't already
have Ubuntu setup you can go to the
Windows Store and click on Ubuntu right
we'll get it from the Windows Store so
from there you basically go SSH
- caged in and that will create like a
special password for your computer to be
able to log in to Amazon and then you
just hit enter three times okay and
that's going to create for you your key
you can use to get into Amazon alright
so then what I do is I copy that key
somewhere that I know where it is so
it'll be in the dot SSH folder
it's called IDRs a dub and so I'm going
to copy it to my hard drive so if you're
in a macro and Linux it'll already be in
an easy to find place it'll be in your
SSH folder that in documents so from
there back in AWS you have to tell it
that you've created this key so you can
go to key pairs and you say import key
pair and you just browse to that file
that you just created there it is
I say import okay so if you've ever used
SSH before you've already got the key
pair you don't have to do those depths
if you've used AWS before you've already
imported it you don't have to do that
step maybe haven't done any of those
things you have to do both steps so now
I can go ahead and launch my instance
community I am eyes search last day I
select launch and so now it asks me
what's where's your key pair and I can
choose that one that I just grabbed okay
so this is going to go ahead and create
a new computer for me to log into and
you can see here it says the following
have been initiated and so if I click on
that it'll show me this new computer
that I've created okay so it'll be able
to log into it
I need to know its IP address so here it
is the IP address there okay so I can
copy that and that's the IP address of
my computer so to get to this computer I
need to SSH to it so SSH into a computer
means connecting to that computer so
that it's like you're typing in that
computer so I type SSH and they username
for this instance is always Ubuntu right
and then I can paste in that IP address
and then there's one more thing I have
to do which is I have to connect up the
jupiter notebook on that instance to the
jupiter notebook on my machine and so to
do that there's just a particular flag
that i said okay we can talk about it on
the forums as to exactly what it does
but you just type - l.a today date
localhost 8 8 8 8 ok so like once you've
done it once you can like save that as
an alias and type in the same thing
every time
so we can check here we can see it says
that it's running so we should be able
to now hit enter first time ever which
sit reconnect to it it does checks this
is okay I'll say yes and then that goes
ahead and SSH is in so this ami is all
set up for you alright so you'll find
that the very first time you log in it
takes a few extra seconds because it
just kind of is getting everything set
up but once it's logged in you'll see
there that there's a directory called
fast AI and the fast AI directory
contains our fast AI repo that contains
all the notebooks or the code etc so I
can just go CD faster all right first
thing you do when you get in is to make
sure it's updated so you just go git
pull right and that updates to make sure
that your repo is the same as the most
recent video and so as you can see there
we go
let's make sure it's got all the most
recent code the second thing you should
do is type Condor and update you can
just do this maybe once a month or so
and that makes sure that the libraries
there are all the most recent libraries
I'm not going to run that so it takes a
couple of minutes okay
and then the last step is to type
particular notebook okay
so this is going to go ahead and launch
the triplet notebook server on this
machine again the first time I do it the
first time you do everything on AWS
it just takes like a minute or two and
then once you've done it in the future
we just as fast as running it locally
basically okay so you can see it's going
ahead and firing out the notebook and so
what's going to happen is that because
when we SSH into it we said to both
connect our notebook port to the remote
notebook port we're just going to be
able to use this locally so I see he
says here copy paste this URL so I'm
going to grab that URL and I'm going to
paste it into my browser and that's it
okay so this notebook is now actually
not running on my machine it's actually
running on AWS okay using the AWS GPU
it's got a lot of memory it's not the
fastest around but it's not terrible
you can always fire up a p3 if you want
something that's super fast this is
costing me ninety cents a minute okay so
when you're finished please don't forget
to shut it down right so to shut it down
you can right-click on it and say
instance date stop okay we've got five
hundred bucks of credit assuming that
you put your code down in the
spreadsheet one thing I forgot to do the
first time I showed you this by the way
I said make sure you choose a p2 the
second time I went through I didn't
choose p2 by mistake so just don't
forget choose gpq compute P - do you
have a question
my Bernice it's an hour thank you
90 cents an hour it also costs like I
don't know three or four bucks a month
for the storage as well thanks for
checking that all right see you next
week sorry we're a bit over