so yeah this week obviously quite a big
quite a bit just to get get set up to
get results from this week in terms of
meeting and all of imagenet and that
kind of thing getting all that working
though I know that a lot of you are
working through that I didn't want to
mention a couple of reminders just that
I've noticed and one is that in general
we have that a thing on the wiki about
like how to use the log books and we
really strongly advise that you don't
open up the notebook we give you and
like click shift enter through it again
and again you're not really going to
learn much from that but go back to that
wiki page is that the first thing as
mentioned in the first paragraph of the
home page for wiki is like how to use
the notebook basically the idea is try
to start with a fresh notebook think
about to think you need to do first try
and do that thing if you have no idea
then you can go to the existing notebook
take a peek
close it again primary implement what to
the store as much as possible we don't
really don't just shift enter through
the notebooks and I know you've covered
you're doing it because there are
threads on the forum saying oh is it
shift entry for the notebook and this
thing didn't work and somebody's like
well could that things about to find it
so consider yourself busted all right
and the other thing to remind you about
is that the goal of part two is to kind
of get you to a point where you can read
papers and the reason for that is
because you kind of know the best
practices now so anytime you want to do
something beyond what we've learned
you're going to be kind of implementing
things in papers so probably going
beyond that and implementing new things
um reading a new paper and in areas that
you haven't looked at before is a needs
to me somewhat terrifying on the other
hand reading a paper for the thing that
we already studied last week hopefully
isn't terrifying at all because you've
already know what the paper says so I
always have that many assignments each
week is like read the paper for the
thing you just learned about
and like go back over it and please not
from a forums if there's a bit of
notation or anything that you don't
understand or if there's something we
heard in class that you can't see in the
paper or literally interesting you see
something in the paper that you don't
think we're interested in class so
that's the reason that I really
encourage you to read the papers that
we've studied in you know the work for
the topics we studied in class I think
it's for those of you like me who don't
have a technical academic background
it's really great way to familiarize
familiarize yourself with notation and
I'm really really looking forward but
some of you asking about location on the
forum so I can explain a number to you
like there's a few key things that and I
keep coming up in notation like
probability distributions and stuff like
that so please feel free and if you're
watching this later in the book again
feel free to ask them inform anything
that's not clear um I was kind of
interested in following up on some of
last week's experiments myself and the
thing that kind of I think we all were a
bit shocked about was was putting this
guy into the device model and getting
out more pictures of similar-looking
fish in in there and I was kind of
curious about
you know how that is working and how
well that was working and I then
completely broke things by training it
for a few more eight bucks and after
doing that I then did an image
similarity search again and I got these
three guys who are longer in men's so
I'm not quite sure what's going on here
and the other thing I mentioned is when
I trained it where my starting point was
what we looked at in class which was
just before the final bottleneck layer I
didn't get very good results from this
thing but when I trained it from that
low starting point of just after the
bottleneck layer I got the good results
that that you saw and again I don't know
why that is and I don't think this has
been studied as far as I'm aware so
there's lots of open questions here but
I'll show you something I did then do
with it well that's interesting I think
what's happened here is that it's focus
it when you train it for longer it knows
that the important thing is the fish not
the net and it seems to be now focusing
on giving us the same kind of fish like
these are clearly the exact same at the
fish I guess so anyway so I started
wondering how could we force it to
combine but I tried the most obvious
possible thing I want to get more fish
in there and I typed words of ethics
pinch the kind of fish plus words of X
dicks
net / to get the average of the two work
vectors and give me the nearest neighbor
and that's what I got and then just
prove it wasn't the flukes I tried the
same on tench + rod and there's my
nearest neighbor now after you know
what's really freaky about this if you
google for image net categories you'll
get a list - 4000 image net categories
if you search through them movin
national right appear at all like I
can't begin to imagine why this works
but it does so this device model is
clearly doing some pretty deep magic in
terms of the understanding of these
objects in the relationships that not
only are we able to combine things like
this
but we're able to combine it with
categories that is literally ever seen
before it's never seen a rod
we've never taught at what a rod looks
like and get over a net and I tried
quite a few of these combinations and
they just kept working like another one
I tried was now I understand why this
works which is I tried searching for
boat now both doesn't have here an image
- but there's lots of kinds of bugs that
appear in the Internet so not
surprisingly they figured out generally
thinking had at my boat so I didn't I
didn't expect that and then I tried boat
plus engine and I got better pictures of
our boats and then I tried both plus
paddle and I'd like that pictures of
rowing boats so this whole lot going on
here and I think there's lots of
opportunities for you to explore and
experiment based on the inspirations and
experiments that I've done and what a
point you have to create some
interesting and valuable tools you know
like I would have thought at all to do a
kind of an image search to say show me
all the images that contain these kinds
of objects or better still maybe you can
start training with things that I just
now but also adjectives that like search
for you know pictures of crying babies
or flaming houses or whatever I mean did
I think there's all kind of stuff you
could do with is it really interesting
whether it be in your in a narrow
organizational setting or to create
something you start up for the open
source project or whatever so anyway
lots of things to try
I lost stuff this week actually miss
difficulty this week I was thrilled to
see that um one of our students has
written this fantastic median plus
linear algebra cheat sheet I think I
missed it because it was posted not to
the plat two or maybe to the main form
this is really cool
brendan has gone through and really
explained I think all the stuff that I
would have wanted to learn about linear
algebra before I got started and
particularly I really appreciate that is
and of taking a code first approach so
like how do you actually do this in non
hi and talking about broadcasting so you
guys will all be very familiar this
already but your friends who are
wondering how to get started in deep
learning you know what's the minimal
things you so it's probably the chain
rule ones and winning in algebra I think
this covers a lot of any linear algebra
pretty effectively
so thank you Brendan
so other things from last week Andrea
from who who wrote that devised paper I
actually emailed her and asked her what
she thought I what else I should look at
and she suggested this paper zero shot
learning by a convex combination of
semantic and Eddings which is only a
later author on but she says it's kind
of in some ways a you know a more
powerful version of dividing day it's
actually quite different and I haven't
implemented it myself but it opens is
that it solves some similar problems
anybody who's interested in exploring
this multimodal images and text space
might be interested in this and we'll
put this some on the lesson wiki of
course and then one more involving the
same author in a similar area a little
bit later we're looking at some
attention for fine-grained
categorization so a lot of these things
but it's the way I think Andrea Framm
was casting it was about fine grained
categorization which is you know how do
we build something that can find like
very specific kinds of birds or very
specific kinds of dogs I think these
kinds of models have very very wider
crucial their applicability
[Music]
okay
so um I mentioned would kind of wrap up
some final topics around kind of
computer vision he stuff this week
before we started looking at some more
NLP related stuff one of the things I
wanted to dip through with the paper
which I think some of you might enjoy
systematic evaluation of CN n advances
on the image then data set and I've
pulled out what I thought was some of
some of the key insights for some of
these the things we haven't really
looked at before one key insight which
is very much the kind of thing I
appreciate is that they compared what's
the difference between the kind of
original cafe necklace Alex net versus
Google map versus EG g net on two
different sized images training on the
original 227 or 128 and what this chart
shows is that the relative difference
between these different architectures is
almost exactly the same regardless of
what size image you're looking at and
this really reminds me of like in part
one when we look at data augmentation
and we said hey you can understand which
types of data augmentation to use and
how much on a small sample of the data
right and on the whole dataset and what
this paper saying is something similar
which is you can look at different
architectures on small sized images
rather than full size images and so they
then use this insight to do all of their
experiments from then on using a smaller
128 by 128 image net model which says
that was ten times faster so that was
the kind of thing which not have
academic edges do like what are the what
are the hacky shortcuts we can get away
with so they tried lots of different
activation functions it does look like
max pooling is way better so this is the
gain compared to earlier but this one
actually has twice the complexity so it
doesn't quite say that what it really
says is that something we haven't looked
at which is Leu which is as you can did
very simple if X is greater than or
equal zero
swipers X otherwise it's e to the X
minus one so Lu basically is just like a
rail you except it's smooth
earlier looks like
man
um
yeah your looks exactly the same here
then here it goes like that
kind of a nice smooth version but
there's one thing you might want to try
using another thing they tried which is
interesting with using elu for the
convolutional layers and
now so I'm trying to say max out for the
fully connected letters I guess nowadays
which I've use fully connected layers
very much so you know maybe that's not
it interesting so main in training
testing thing here I think is the Euro
elu activation function to patatas point
that's quite a big difference there
looks a different loading rate annealing
approaches and you can use care us to
automatically do learning rather dealing
and what they showed is that linear
annealing seems to work best they try
something else which was like what about
different colour transformations you
know and they found that amongst some
normal approaches to think about color
RGB actually seems to work the best but
then they trade something I haven't seen
before which is they added to one by one
convolutions at the very start of the
network so each of those one by one
convolutions basically doing a linear
that's the kind of linear combination
with the channels and were they
non-linearity then in between and they
found that there actually have gotten
quite a big improvement and that should
be pretty much zero cost so there's
another thing which I haven't really
seen written about elsewhere but it's a
good trick they looked at the impact of
batch norm so here is a the impact of
batch norm positive or negative
actually adding Bastion onto Google net
didn't help that you made it worse for
thin seeds like really complex carefully
tuned architectures you're going to be
pretty careful we're all sort of simple
Network it helps a lot and the amount of
Health sort though depends on someone
which activation function use so that's
norm I think we kind of know that now be
careful when you use it sometimes it's
fantastically helpful sometimes it's
like the onion form
question is there any advantage
musically connected layers turn
yeah I mean I think there is like a
terribly out of fashion
[Music]
but I think for transfer learning they
still seem to be the best in terms of
the kind of you know the fully connected
layers the superfast train and you seem
to get a lot of flexibility there so I
don't think we know one way or another
yet but I do think that PGG still has a
lot to give us in terms of you know but
the last carefully tuned thing with
political players and that really since
they'd be great for a transfer learning
and then there was that a comment saying
that Elias advantage is not just smooth
but it's that it goes a little below
zero dimensions that is actually being
money yeah yeah that's a great point
thank you for adding that
yeah and anytime you hear me say
something slightly stupid please feel
free to jump in because otherwise on the
video forever
so on the other hand it does give you an
improvement in accuracy if you remove
the final mass cooling layer replace all
of the convolutional layers sorry fully
connected layers with convolutional
layers and stick a Everage pulling at
the end and so basically what this is
doing so as I've seen there's definitely
an upside to political emotional
networks in terms of accuracy but there
may be a downside in terms of
flexibility around down transfer
learning a slit lamp layers tool I
thought this was an interesting picture
I hadn't quite seen before let me
explain the picture what this shows is
these are different batch sizes along
the bottom and then we've got accuracy
and what it's showing is with a learning
rate of 0.01 this is what happens to
accuracy so as you go above 256 batch
size it plummets on the other hand if
you use a learning rate 0.01 times batch
size over 256 it's pretty flat so what
this suggests to me is that anytime you
change the batch size it's basically
telling you to change the learning rate
by a proportional amount which I think a
lot of us have realized through
experiment but I don't think I've seen
it explicitly mentioned before
I think this is very helpful to
understand as well as the removing data
just has a kind of a nonlinear effect on
accuracy so here's the screen line here
is what happens when you remove images
okay so with image net down to about
half the size of image net there isn't a
huge impact on accuracy so maybe if you
want to really speed things up you go
128 by one from the a size images and
use just 600,000 of them or even maybe
400,000 but then beneath that it started
to plummet
so I think that's the interesting
insight another interesting insight
although I'm going to add something to
this in a moment is that rather than
removing images if you instead it flip
the labels to make them incorrect that
has a worse effect than not having the
data at all but there are things we can
do to try and improve things there and
specifically I want to bring your
attention to this paper training fifth
gear all networks on loyalty levels with
bootstrapping and what this show is a
very simple approach a very simple tweak
you can add to any training method which
dramatically improves their ability to
handle handle noisy levels so this year
here is showing the if you add noise
varying from 0.3 0.5 to endless so half
of it the bass lines are doing nothing
at all
it really collapses the accuracy but if
you use their approach to bootstrapping
you can actually go up to nearly ah the
images being intentionally changing
their label that still works nearly as
well I think this is really important
paper to mention in this like stuff that
most of you will find important and
useful area because most real-world data
sets have noise in them so maybe this is
something you should consider adding to
everything that you've trained whether
it be Apple data sets or your own data
sets or whatever
particularly because you don't
necessarily know and have no idea the
labels are
[Music]
you
so noise labels moods incorrect yeah
noisy just maintain correct
okay so what's threatened yeah this is
this particular paper describes a
particular technique which you can read
during the waitress register
so interestingly they find that if you
take of heg and then add all of these
things together a loser all at once you
can actually get a pretty big
performance like it looks in fact like
vgg becomes more accurate in google map
you make all these changes so that's an
interesting point
although vgg is very very slow and big
there's lots of stuff that a lot if they
didn't look at they didn't look at data
augmentation different approaches to
zooming and cropping adding skip
connections like in res mesh or
engineers or our networks different
initialization methods different amount
of debt and me the most important is the
effect on transfer learning for these to
me or you know are all open questions as
far as I know
and so maybe one of you would like to
create the successor to this you know
the more observations on training cnn's
there's another interesting paper
although the main interesting thing
about this paper is this particular
picture so feel free to check it out is
pretty short and simple but this paper
is looking at the accuracy versus the
size and the speed of different networks
so the size of a bubble is how big is
the network's how many parameters to
that so you can see vgg 16 and vgg 19 as
I far the biggest of any of these
networks interestingly the second
biggest are the very old basic Alex near
so interestingly newer networks tend to
have a lot less parameters which is a
concern then on this axis we have a
basically how long does it take to Train
so again vgg is big and slow and without
at least some tweaks not to every
accurate so again you know there's
definitely reasons not to use vgg even
if they'll easier so transfer learning
or we don't necessarily know how to do a
great job of transfer learning on ResNet
or inception but as you can see the more
recent resident and inception based
approaches are basically more accurate
and faster and smaller so this is I
think why you know I was looking last
week trying to do transfer learning on
top of ResNet is this really good reason
to want to do that
I think this is a great feature and you
know these two papers really show us
that that academic papers are not always
just his some highly theoretical wacky
results he told from time to time people
write these great Sarah you know
analyses of like best practices and
everything that's going on so there's
some really great stuff out there
one other paper to mention in this kind
of broad ideas about things that you
might find helpful as a paper by
somebody named Leslie Smith's who I
think is going to be just about the most
unlock to researcher lytic Smith there's
a lot of really great papers which I
really like this particular paper came
up with a list of 14 design patents
which seem to be generally associated
with with better CNS and this is a great
paper to read is so it's a really easy
read you guys won't have any trouble
with it at all I don't think that's very
short and but I really looked through
all these I just kind of thought yeah
these all make a lot of sense and so as
you if you're doing something a bit
different in a bit new and you have to
design a new architecture this would be
a great list of patterns who look
through one more Leslie Smith paper to
mention and there's crazy that this is
not more well-known something incredibly
simple which is a different approach to
learning rates rather than just having
your learning rate gradually decrease
I'm sure a lot of you have noticed that
sometimes if you have suddenly increase
the learning rate for a bit and then
suddenly decrease it again forget it
kind of goes into a better little area
so what this paper suggests doing is try
actually continually increasing your
learning rate and then decreasing it
increasing and decreasing it increasing
and decreasing it something that they
call lexical learning rooms and check
out the implant compared to non flexible
approaches it is way way faster
and much and it gets at it's going to
fire at every point it's much better and
this is something which you could easily
add and I haven't seen this added to any
library so like if you created the psych
circle learning rate annealing class for
Kara you know many people would thank
you
well actually many people would have no
idea what you're talking about to throw
out the blog post explain why would and
show them this picture and they're
exempt you
children quickly as it clears with lots
of callbacks that they issue do
something yeah exactly great look was a
bunch of called branch and a dog and if
I was doing this and care us what I
would do would be I would start with the
existing learning rate and healing code
that's there and you don't make small
changes until it starts working this is
already sir it was already code but does
pretty much everything you want and the
other cool thing about this paper is
that they suggest a fairly automated
approach to picking what the minimum and
maximum bound should be and again this
idea of like roughly watchin our
learning rate B is something which we
tend to use a lot of trial and error for
but check out this paper for a
suggestion about how to do it somewhat
automatically okay so there's a whole
bunch of things that I've zipped over
normally I would have dug into each of
those explained darshan shown examples
and notebooks and stuff but this is like
a you know you guys hopefully now have
enough knowledge to take this
information and play with it and what
I'm hoping is that different people will
play with different parts and come back
and tell us what you find and you know
hopefully we'll get some good new
contributions to care us or high-torque
shorts and blog posts or sand papers or
so forth so maybe that divides our
seasons and new applications
so the next thing high water to look at
and again somewhat briefly is the data
Science Bowl
and the reason I particularly wanted to
think into the data Science Bowl is with
a couple reasons one one there's a
million reasons it's a million dollar
prize and there are 23 days to go the
second is it's it's an extension for
everything that you guys have learned so
far about computer vision it uses all
the techniques you've learned but then
time so rather than 2d images they're
going to be 3d volumes rather than being
kind of 300 by 300 or 500 by 500 they're
going to be 512 by 512 by 200 so like a
couple of hundred times but bigger than
fucking joke was before the stuff we
learnt in lesson seven about like where
are the fish you're going to be needing
to use a lot of that so I think it's a
really interesting problem to solve and
then I personally care a lot about this
because my previous startup Kemetic was
the first organization to use tech
learning to example this exact problem
which is trying to find one cancer in CT
scans the reason I made that and look at
the first problem with mainly because I
learned that if you can find one cancer
earlier the probability of survival is
10 times higher so here is something
where you can have a real impact in are
both buggering as well which is not to
say that a million dollars in the big
impact as well so let me tell you a
little bit about about this problem
here is
here is a lung
and it is in a dykon viewer back on the
I see om is the standard that is used
for sharing most kinds of medical
imaging certainly think again it is a
format which contains two main things
one is a second images and another is
some metadata so that metadata will be
things like how much of radiation were
those at by and how far away from the
chest with machine and what brand of
machine wasn't so simple so you can the
most died computers to choose your
scroll wheel to lit through them and so
all this is doing is like going from
from top to bottom or from bottom to top
and so kind of see what's going on
yes I'm rich I'm okay if you want to
order or en sleep
yeah so you can you can well actually
what I might do I think is more
interesting is to say well let's
actually focus on a bit that's going to
matter to you which is the inside of the
lung is that area here and these little
white dots what's called the vasculature
so all the little vessels and start
going through the lines and as I scroll
through please have a look at this sort
of dot you'll see that it seems to move
okay see how it's moving and the reason
it's moving is because it's not a dot
it's actually a vessel going through
space so it actually looks like this
okay and so if you take a slice through
that it looks like lots of dots and so
as you go through those slices
it looks like they're okay and then
eventually we get to the top of the line
and that's why you see eventually it
kind of all goes to white right so I put
the edge basically is the organ and so
you can see there are edges on each side
and then it's also bone so
some of you have been looking at this
already over the last few weeks and have
often asked Peter how to deal with like
multiple images and what I said each
time is don't think of it as multiple
images think of it in the way your
daikon viewer can if you have a 3d
button like this one does
that's actually what we're looking at
and so it's not a bunch of flat images
it's a 3d volume but it just so happens
at the default way that most icon
viewers show thing is by a bunch of flat
images but it's really important that
you think of it as a 3d volume because
you're looking in this space okay now
what are you looking for in this space
but what you're looking for in order is
you're looking for somebody who has
munching and what something has lung
cancer looks like is that somewhere in
this space there is a blob act like a
could be roughly spherical blob it could
be pretty small around five mil five
millimeters is where people start to get
particularly concerned about a block and
so what that means is that for a
radiologist as they flick through a scan
like this is that they're looking for a
dot which doesn't move but which appears
gets bigger and then disappears that's
what a blog looks like okay so you can
see why radiologists very very very
often miss nodules loss in lines because
in all of this area you know you've got
to have extraordinary vision to be able
to see every little blob of here and
then disappear again and remember the
sooner you catch it you get a 10s
improved chance of survival
and generally speaking when a
radiologist looks at one of these scans
they're not looking for nodules they are
looking for something else because lung
cancer at least in the earlier stages is
a symptomatic doesn't cause you to feel
different right so it's like something
that every radiologist has to be
thinking about and it looking for
pneumonia or or whatever else so that's
the basic idea is that we're going to
try and come up with in the next hour or
so
so some idea about how would you find
these blocks how do you find these
nodules so each of these things
generally is about 512 by 512 by capital
100 and and each of those and the
affirmative a pixel in 3d space is
called a bottle and so Vauxhall simply
means a pixel in 3d space so this
here is rendering a bunch of bottle
each voxel in a CT scan is a 12-bit it's
chip
memory serves me correctly and a
computer screen can only show age bits
of greyscale and furthermore your eyes
can't necessarily distinguish between
all those grades fell perfectly anyway
so what every dykes on view provides is
something called a windowing adjustment
so a windowing adjustment come here is
the default window which is designed to
basically map some subset of that 12 bit
space through to the screen so that it's
highlighted 17 and so the units CT scans
you use according some field units and
different certain ranges of Hounsfield
units tell you that something in some
particular part of the body and so you
can see here that the bone is being with
us so we've selected an image window
which is designed to allow us to see the
bone chilling so what I did when I open
this without switched it to CTS chest
which is some kind person has already
figured out what the best window is
a message
ah
and there's also a city lunch to figured
out what's the best window to see the
modules and best butchering well now are
you working in with deep learning you
don't have to care about that because of
course to take learning algorithm can
see 12 is perfectly well so nothing
really to worry about
so one of the challenges dealing with
this zone data science called data is
that there's a lot of people assessing
to do but the good news is that there's
a couple of fantastic tutorials so
hopefully you found out by now that I'm
Carol if you click on the colonel's
button you basically get to see people
by hiding their books where they show
you how to do certain things for this
case this guy has got a full
pre-processing tutorial showing how to
load backbone convert civilian to
Hounsfield units and so forth and i'll
show you some of these pieces so DICOM
you will load with with some library
probably with pie diagram and so pie
diagram is a library that's kind of a
bit like killer pillow or Gopa or you
know an image to open like a Ticonderoga
and end up with a 3d file and of course
the metadata you can see here using the
metadata image position lights location
okay so the metadata comes through with
just attributes of the Python object and
this person is very kindly provided to
you a list of the Hounsfield unit arts
is coming from wikipedia Hounsfield
units for each of the different
substances okay so
[Music]
shows how to translate stuff into that
range and so it's great to draw lots of
pictures so here is a histogram for this
particular picture alright so you can
see that most of it is air and then you
can some bone in someone at position
flex
so then the next thing to think about is
the the books really boxful spacing
which is as you move across one bit of
x-axis or one bit of y-axis or from
slice - slice out far and like the real
world
are you moving and one of your annoying
things about edible imaging is two
different kinds of scanners at different
distances between those licensed places
or the slice thickness and different the
different meanings of the x and y-axes
luckily that stuff's all of the
blacktron metadata so the resampling
process means taking that those lists of
slices and turning it into something
where every step in the x direction or
the Y direction or the Z direction
equals one millimeter in the real world
and so it'd be very annoying for your
deep learning network if your different
line images was squished by different
amounts especially if you can look at
the metadata about how much was being
squished so that's what reads sampling
does as you can see it's using the slice
thickness and the pixel spacing and to
make it really nice and even
so there are various ways to do 3d pots
and it's always a good idea to do that
and then something else that people tend
to do is segmentation and depending on
time we may or may not get around to
looking more at segmentation in this
part of the course but effectively a
segmentation is just another generative
model at the generative model where you
know hopefully somebody's given you some
things saying this is London's air and
then you build a model that does predict
for something else
what line was there unfortunately for
London CT scans we don't generally have
that kind of ground truth of knowledge
bits on which is air so generally
speaking medical imaging people use a
whole lot of heuristics approaches so
kind of a key rule based approaches and
in particular some applications of
region growing and morphological
operations and I find this kind of the
boring part of medical imaging because
like it's so clearly a dumb way to do
things but you know deep learning and
start seeing you in this area yet to
kind of develop the data sets that we
need to do this properly but the good
news is that
as a button which I don't think many
people know this exists it's called
tutorial on the mainly design or page
where these folks from Brazil and
Hamilton actually show you a complete
segmentation approach now it's
interesting that they pick unit
segmentation this is definitely the
thing about segmentation I would be
teaching you guys if we have time unit
is one of these things that outside of
the cattle world I don't think that many
people are familiar with but inside the
capital world we know that anytime
segmentation cross up unit wins
alone it's the best more recently
there's actually been something called
dense net segmentation which takes unit
even a little bit further and maybe that
would be the new winner the new external
competitions when they happen but the
basic idea here of things like you net
and dense net is that we have a model
where maybe a controller
you know when we do generative models we
I think about doing a style transfers we
generally start with this kind of large
image and then we do some down sampling
operations because a small image and
then we do some computation and then we
make a bigger again as these up sampling
operations
what happens in you net is that there
are additional neural network
connections made directly from here to
here and directly from here to here and
get it here and get it here and both
connections basically allow it to almost
through like a kind of a residual
learning approach like it can figure out
the key pieces you know kind of semantic
pieces at the very low resolution but
then is it up scaled it it can learn
well what was special about the
difference between the down sampled
image and the original image here they
can kind of learn to add that additional
detail at each point so unit and depth
net
or segmentation
really interesting and I hope we find
some time to get back to them in this
part of the course but if we don't you
can get started by looking at this
tutorial in which these folks basically
show you from scratch and what they try
to do in this tutorial is something very
specific which is the detection part so
what happens in this kind of like think
about the fisheries competition
we've pretty much decided that in the
fisheries competition if you wanted to
do really well you would first of all
find the fish and then you would zoom
into the fish and then you would figure
out what kind of fish it is certainly in
the right way or competition earlier
that would tell that was fun
but this competition is even more
clearly going to be the approach because
these images are just far too big to a
normal convolutional neural network when
is one set is going to find the module
and then the second step that's going to
zoom in to a possible module and figure
out is this a malignant tumor or
something else the false positives
the bad news is that the data Science
Bowl data set does not give you any
information at all about for the
training set where are the cancerous
nodules which actually wrote a post in
the cable forums about this I just think
this is a terrible terrible idea because
you know they're not like set that
information actually exists that the
data set they got the trauma is
something called the National lung
screening trial which actually has that
information but something pretty close
to it
so the fact they didn't provide it is I
just think it's horrible you know for a
competition which which can save lives
and a comic information the good news
though is that there is a data set which
does have this information the original
data set was called libc
entry ID III interestingly that data set
was recently used for another
competition on cable competition called
Luna Oh DNA that competition is now
finished and one of the tracks in that
competition was actually a specifically
a false positive detection track so and
then the other track was a find a nodule
track basically so you can actually go
back and look at the papers written by
the winners and they're generally
ridiculously short many of them are
single sentence saying commercial
confidentiality agreement we can't do
anything but some of them including the
winner of the false positive track is a
film they actually provided not
surprisingly though you're using wording
and so what you could do is that I think
what you have to do to do well in this
competition is download the lunar data
set use that to build a nodule detection
algorithm so the lunar data set includes
you know files saying this lung has
nodules here here here and here and so
do not your protection based on that and
then run that nodule detection algorithm
on the cattle data set find the nodules
and then use that do some
location you there are some tricky
things with that the biggest tricky
thing is that most of the CT scans in
the lunar data set are what's called
contrast studies a contrast scan means
that the patient had a radioactive dye
injected into them so that the things
that they're looking for idea dizzy the
filter for the National lung screening
trial which is what these mechanical
data set none of them is contrast and
the reason why is that what we really
want to be able to do is to take anybody
who's like over 65 and it's been smoking
more than a pack a day for more than 20
years and give them all a CT scan and
find out which ones of cancer but in the
process we don't want to be shooting
them up with radioactive dye and giving
them cancer so that's why we try to make
sure that when we're doing these kind of
asymptomatic scans that they're as low
radiation dose as possible so that means
that you're going to have to think about
transfer learning issues that the the
contrast in your image is going to be
different between the thing you build on
the lunar data set the natural
protection and the goggle competition
that is there but you know it's it's a
when I looked at it I didn't find that
that terribly difficult problem I'm sure
you won't find it impossible by any
means
I
[Music]
so to finalize this discussion I want to
refer to this paper which I'm guessing
not that many people are red yet it's a
medical imaging paper and what it is is
a non deep learning approach to trying
to find nodules so that's where they use
you know this thing here sorry
natural segmentation that's Ridgemont
give that correction from our
radiologist program saying that dye is
not radioactive it's just dead
I still use 70 your eye disease
there's a reason we don't inject people
with the contrast on issues our
contrasted propath surgically
yeah that's what I do know though that
the analyst T again radiologist correct
me the NLF t studies use a lower amount
of radioactivity than I think the
learner ones do so not a difference okay
so this is a interesting idea of like
how can you find nodules using more of a
heuristic approach and the heuristic
approach they suggest here is to do
clustering and we haven't really done
any clattering in class yet so we're
going to dig into this in some detail
because I think this is a great idea for
the kind of heuristics you can add on
top of deep learning to make deep
learning work in in different areas the
basic idea here is to as you can see
they call it a five dimensional mean
they're going to try and find groups of
boxes which are similar and they're
going to cluster them together and
hopefully we're going to particularly
cluster together thing to look like
nodules so the idea is at the end of
this segmentation then there will be one
cluster for the whole lung boundary one
cluster for the whole vasculature and
then one cluster therapy nodule so the
five dimensions are x y&z the
straightforward intensity so is number
of counts field units and then the fifth
one is volumetric shape index and this
is the one tricky one the basic idea
here is going to be a combination of the
different curvatures of a voxel based on
the Gaussian and main curvatures now
what the paper goes on to explain is
that you can use for these the first and
second derivatives of the image now all
that basically means is you subtract one
voxel from it's never right and then you
take that whole thing and subtract one
box full version of that we get Slater
you get the first and second
derivatives I kind of just help you the
direction of the change is image
intensity at that point so by getting
these first and second derivatives of
the image and then you put it into this
formula it comes out with something
which basically tells you how fear like
this voxels seems to be part of that
sort of house to fear like a construct
and so so that's great right if we can
basically take for the voxels and
combine the one for the nearby at the
similar number of pounds for your units
and seem to be a similar kind of shapes
we're going to get what we want so I'm
not going to worry about this bit here
the trans-pacific medical imaging
anybody who's interested in doing this
feel free to talk on the forum about
what this books like in Python but what
I did want to talk about was the
moonship clustering which subtly
approach to clustering which they talk
about
it isn't received a comment that the
voice from the other mic breaks up hard
understand another
okay if that's being this like yeah okay
Rachel when you said to me again
fostering is something which for a long
time I've been kind of an anti fan of it
belongs to this it's a group of
unsupervised learning algorithms which
always tend to be kind of looking for a
problem to solve but I realized recently
there are some specific problems that
can be solved well with them and I'm
going to be showing you a couple one
today and when I'm less important
clustering algorithms are perhaps the
best it is to describe by what they do
by generating some data to show them
against and generated data but I'm going
to create two clusters and for each
cluster of 250 samples
so I'm going to basically say okay let's
create a bunch of centroids by creating
two random numbers so six pairs of
random numbers and centroids and then
I'll grab a bunch of random numbers
around each of those centroids and
combine them all together and then plot
them and so here you can see each of
these X is representative centroid
okay so attempt Reuters just like the
average point for a cluster of data and
each color represents one cluster
so imagine if this was showing you
clusterings of different kinds of lung
tissue you know ideally you had some
voxels that were colored one thing for
nodule and a bunch of that thing look at
color a different color for vasculature
and so forth
we can only show this easily in two
dimensions but there's no reason to not
be able to imagine doing this in
certainly five dimensions
so the goal of clustering will be to
undo this right given the data but not
the answers how can you figure out where
the exes were right so basically and
then it's pretty straightforward once
you know where the exes are to then find
the closest points to that to assign
every data point to a cluster
the most popular approach to clustering
is called a means hang mean is an
approach where you have to decide
upfront how many clusters are there and
what it basically does is there's two
steps the first one is to guess as to
where those clusters might be a really
simple way to do that is just to some
wonderful pictures and on the simple way
to do that is basically to randomly pick
a point and then start randomly picking
points which are as far away as possible
from all the previous ones okay so if a
literal where the first one so if I
started here right then probably the
farthest away point would be down here
but this would be like our starting
point for cluster one I would say okay
what point is furthest away from that
that's probably this one here at the VLA
in 2022 okay what's the furthest point
away from both of these probably what
this one over here and so forth so you
keep doing that to get your initial
point and then you just iteratively move
every point so basically then say okay
which these are the clusters that the
two massive clusters which cluster
delivery point belong to and they need
to iteratively move the points to
different classes and a bunch of times
now k-means it's a shame it's so popular
because it kind of sucks right so sucky
thing number one is that we have to
decide how many classes there are and
like the whole points they don't know
how many modules there are right and
then fucking thing number two is without
some changes to do thing called kernel
k-means it only works if the things are
the same shape you know they're all kind
of nicely
gasping shit so we're going to talk
about something way cooler which only
we're kind of came across someone
recently
much Westphal known which is called mean
shift classroom
now Lynch if clustering is one of these
things which seems to spend some all of
its time in them
and a serious mathematician land like
whatever I try to kind of look up
something about me and ship clustering
excited that seeing this kind of thing
and this is like the first tutorial or
not in the PDF that I could find so okay
so this is one way to think about engine
clustering and other way is a code first
approach which is that this is the
entire algorithm so let's talk about
what's going on here what are we doing
at a high level we're going to do a
bunch of loops all right so we're going
to be five steps it would be better if I
didn't do five steps that I kept doing
this until it was stable but for now I'm
going to do both this and each step I'm
going to go through so our data is X
right I'm going to go through the
numerator to our data
and what I'm going to do is I'm going to
find okay so a small X is the current
data point I'm looking at okay now what
I'm going to do is find out how far away
is this data point from every other data
plant but I'm going to create a vector
of distances and I'm going to do that
with the magic of broadcasting okay so
small X is a vector of size two just is
two coordinates and big X is a blank of
site as a matrix of size n by 2 where n
is the request and thanks to what we've
now learned about broadcasting we know
that we could subtract a matrix from a
vector and that vector will be broadcast
across the axis of the matrix and so
this is going to subtract every element
of big apps from little air and so if we
then go ahead and square that and then
sum it up and then take the square root
this is going to return a vector of
distances of small X to every element of
B X ok and with the thought the sum here
is just summing up for two coordinates
okay so that's step one so we now know
for this particular data point how far
away is it from all of the other data
points now the next thing we want to do
is to the fight walk let's go to the
final step the final step will be to
take a weighted average right so we
basically can add in the final step
we're going to say what cluster do you
belong to
let's draw this
okay so got a whole bunch of data points
and we're currently looking at this one
and
and what we've done is we've now got a
list of how far is away from or the
other data points
and the basic idea is now what we want
to do is take the weighted average of
all of those data points weighted by the
inverse of that distance so the things
that are a long way away we want to wait
very small and the things that are very
close we want to work very big right so
I think this is probably the closest and
this is about the second closest and
this is about the third closest so
achieving this but most of the weight
the average is going to be somewhere
about here okay and so by doing that
every point we're going to move every
point both fit aware its friends up
folks it aware the nearby thing but and
so if we keep doing it again and again
everything's going to move and show us
right next to it friends so how do we
take something
initially is a distance and make it so
that the larger distances have smaller
ways and the answer is we probably want
to shape
like that in other words
calcium
this is by no means the only shape you
could choose right it would be equally
valid to choose
this shape
it's just triangle
problem
in general though look that if we're
going to multiply every point by one of
these things and add them all together
it'd be nice if all of our weights added
to one right because then we're going to
end up with something that's of the same
scale that we start with so when you
create one of these curves where it all
adds up to one generally speaking
we call that a kernel
and I mention this because you will see
kernels everywhere if you haven't
already now that you see that you'll see
them everywhere in fact kernel methods
it's a whole area of machine learning
that in the late 90s basically took over
because it was so theoretically pure and
if you want to get published in
conference proceedings it's much more
important to be theoretically pure than
actually accurate so for a long time
kernel methods one out and neural
networks in particular disappeared
eventually people realize that accuracy
was important as well and more recent
times kernel methods are largely
disappearing but you still see the idea
of a kernel coming up very often because
they're super useful tools to have
they're basically something that lets
you take a number or in this case a
distance and turn it into some other
number where you can weight everything
by the other number and add them
together to get a nice little weighted
average so in our case we're going to
use a Gaussian kernel the particular
formula for a Gaussian doesn't matter I
remember learning this formula in grade
10 and it was by far the most terrifying
mathematical formula ever seen but it
doesn't really matter right that's for
those of you that remember or seen the
Gaussian formula you'll recognize it
those of you that haven't it doesn't
matter but this is the function that
draws that curve ok so if we take every
one of our distances and put it through
the calcium we will then get back a
bunch of weights that add to 1 ok so
then in the final step we can multiply
every one of our data points by that
weight ok add them up and divide by the
sum of the weights in other words like
weighted average you'll notice that I
had to be a bit careful about
broadcasting here because I
needed to add a beautiful accent at the
end of my dimensions not at the start so
by default it adds to unit axes the
beginning and you do broadcasting
that's where has to expand in if you're
not clear on why this is then that's a
sign you definitely need to do some more
playing around with broadcasting so have
a fiddle with that during the week feel
free to ask if you're not clear after
you the experimenters but it is just a
way to done and so this is just doing
some of weights times eggs but base on
of quest
importantly the nice little thing that
we can pass to a gaussian which is the
thing that decides does it look like the
thing I just drew or does it look like
this
look like this
and all of those things add up to one
they all have the same area underneath
but they're very different shapes if we
make it look like this then what that's
going to do is it's going to create a
lot more clusters but because things
that are really close to it they're
going to have really high weights and
everything else is going to have a tiny
web and be meaningless or else if we use
something like this we're going to have
much fewer classes because even stuff
it's further away going to have a higher
weight and when fun so the choice that
you use for the it's called the kernel
rips as a logical names you can use we
actually prepare up these BW being
banned reads that number there's
actually some cool ways to choose it one
simple way to choose it is to find out
which size of bandwidth covers say one
third of the data in your database I
think that's the approach that on
scikit-learn users so anyway there are
some ways that you can automatically
figure out a band ribs I just want to
look pretty nice things that I mentioned
okay so we just go through a bunch of
time five times in each time we replace
every point with its weighted average
weighted by the this Gaussian kernel and
so when we run this five times it takes
the second
and
as a result I've upset everything by one
just so that we can see it right
otherwise it'd be right on property X
you can see that for nearly all of them
is it exactly the right spot
where else for this cluster let's just
remind ourselves a metatarsal on there
but if these two clusters this
particular band fits is decided to
create one cluster for them rather than
two
okay so this is kind of an example where
else if we decreased our band width it
would create two classes and I just know
one right answer is there should be one
or two so one challenge for this is that
it's kind of slow right so I thought
let's try and accelerate it to the GPU
okay and because then shifts not very
cool nobody seems to implement the TPU
yet or maybe this a little bit here so I
thought oh geez PI torch and the reason
why you'd play torch is because it
really feels like writing PI talks just
feels like writing 9 pi everything
happens straight away so I really hoped
that I could take my original code and
make it almost the same and indeed here
is the entirety of main shift in
Patchogue so that's pretty cool you can
see rather than you know anywhere they
used to have NP and numbers torch NP dot
array is now forged off flow tensor
and video square root is torture square
root
everything else is almost the same and
one issue is that torch doesn't support
broadcasting so we'll talk more about
this shortly in a couple of weeks but
basically I decided that smell okay so I
wrote my own broadcasting library
package so this rather than saying X
little X minus big X I use subs for the
tract
that's the subtract from my broadcasting
library if you're curious and check out
for two tools as you can see my
broadcasting operations there but
basically if you use those you can see
saves the multiplication it'll do all
the broadcasting point
[Music]
okay so as you can see this box
basically identical to the previous code
fire takes longer
so that's not ideal one problem here is
that I'm not using Kudo okay so I could
easily fix that by adding CUDA my ex but
that made it slower still and the reason
why is that other works being done in is
for loop and height which doesn't
accelerate for loops by each run through
a for loop in pi torch is basically
doing is basically calling a new CUDA
kernel each time you're going through
and it takes a certain amount of time to
even launched a CUDA kernel this is
rather annoying sorry when I was in CUDA
kernel this is a different history of
work kernel in CUDA kernel refers to a
little piece of code that runs on the
GPU so it's launching a little GPU
process every time through the for loop
is takes quite a time and it's also
having to copy they don't all over the
place so but I guess the right result
sounds good
so what I then tried to
was to make it faster the trick is to do
it by mini-batch okay so each time
through the loop we want to don't want
to do just one big data but a mini batch
of data so here's the changes I mean the
main one was that my fly now jump
through one batch size at a time okay so
I'm going to go not not 1 2 3 but not
1632 ok so I now need to create a slice
which is from i to i plus batch size and
let me contrast the end of the data
which case is justified then ok so this
is going to refer to the slice of data
that we're interested in so what we can
now do is say X with that slaves to crap
back all of the data in this mini bash
and so then I had to create a special
version of I can't say subtract anymore
I need to think carefully about the
broadcasting operations here having a
return of matrix that lets say batch
size of 32 are going to have 32 rows
okay and then let's say n is a thousand
will be a thousand columns that shows me
how far away each thing in my batch is
from every piece of data so when we do
things a batch of the time you're
basically adding another access to all
of your senses certainly now you have a
batch asses all the sounds and we've
been doing deep learning that's been
like something I think we've got pretty
used to write the first access and all
of our tenses or has been a batch
shatters but now we're writing our own
gpu-accelerated algorithm now can you
believe how crazy this is like two years
ago writing a GT like if you google for
like k-means food or payment GPU you get
back like research done but if iraq keen
turns about how to put these algorithms
you can use because like it was hard and
here's a page of code the dozen so like
this is crazy this is possible where we
are we have built a a batch by batch
gpu-accelerated been shipped algorithm
so the basic distance formula is exactly
the same i just have to be careful about
where I added unsquare as the same as
expand in in vampire so let's be careful
about where I add my univac these add up
to the first axis of one bit and the
second axis of the other dish that's
going to do like a subtract every one of
the each and every one of them's
paternal matrix again this is like a
really good time to look at this and I
think why does this Broadcasting work
because this is getting more and more
complex broadcasting and hopefully you
can now see the value of broadcasting
right not only did I get to avoid
writing a pair of nested for-loops here
but I also got to do this all on the GPU
in
operation so I've made this south of the
time about that some so here is a single
operation which does that entire matrix
in subjection this ritual is just going
to suggest that we take a break to
depend too late
so so that's our batch wise distance
function we then check that into a
Gaussian and because this is just
element wise the Gaussian function
hasn't changed at all
that's nice and then I've got my
weighted sum and then divide that by the
sum of weights so that's basically the
algorithm so previously for my numpy
version it took a second
now it's 48 milliseconds so we've just
set it up at 28 yes very John there's a
question I get how batching helps with
locality in cash but I do not quite
follow how it helps otherwise especially
with respect to accelerating the
for-loop yes so
in pi torch the for loop is not run on
the GPU the for loop is run on your CPU
and your CPU goes through each step of
the for loop and calls the GPU as they
do this thing do this thing do this
thing but so this is not to say you
can't accelerate this intensive flow you
know in a similar way like intensive
flow there's a TS dot wile and stuff
like that we've next to do GPU based
loops even still if you do it entirely
in a liquid paper it's going to be
pretty difficult to get his performance
but particularly in PI torch important
remember in PI torch your loops are not
optimized it's what you do inside each
which is optimized
another question some of the math
functions are coming from torch and
others are coming from the mask Python
library
what is the difference when you use the
Python mask library does that mean the
GPU is not being used
yeah so you'll see that I use that
master pi is a constant and then math
dot square root of two times pi is a
constant so I don't need to use the GPU
to have a better constant obviously so
yeah we only use a torch for things that
are running on a vector or a matrix or a
tensor if they don't okay so let's have
a break we'll come back in 10 minutes Oh
that'd be too fast H and we'll talk
about some ideas I have for improving
mean shift which maybe you guys will
want to try out during the week
so basically the idea here is
we we figure that there are two two
steps we need to figure out whether
nodules are good rare whether nodules
are in something like this if any step
number one is to find the things that
maybe kind of nodule ish zoom into them
and create a little cropped version and
then step two would be where your deep
learning particularly comes in which is
to figure out is that cancerous or not
the once you've found a nodule ish thing
the the cancerous ones actually buy
farther but far the biggest driver of
whether or not something is a moment
cancer is how big it is okay so like
it's that it's actually pretty
straightforward
the other thing particularly important
is like how kind of spider II it looks
if it looks like it's kind of evilly
going out to capture more territory
that's probably a bad client as well so
the kind of size in the shape for the
two things that you got to be wanting to
try and find obviously that's a pretty
good theme for a neural net to be able
to do you probably don't need that an
example diversion when you get to that
point those obviously question about you
know how to deal with the 3d aspect here
and we can just create a 3d
convolutional neural net so if you had
like a
ten by ten by ten space that's opposite
em and I'm gonna be too big and 20 by 20
by 20 you might be okay and you know
kind of think about how big a volume can
you create and there's plenty of papers
around on 3d convolutions although I'm
not sure if you even need one because
it's just a convolution in 3d the other
approach that you might find interesting
to think about is something called try
planar what try planar means is that you
take a slice through the X and the y and
they're a seed and so you basically end
up with three images one is this box XY
is that and then you can go treat those
as different channels if you like even
and probably use pretty standard here on
that library that expect your channels
so there's a couple of ideas
how you can do on the 3d there's others
the I think using this Luna that have
said as much as possible is going to be
good idea because you really want
something that's pretty good at
detecting modules before you start
putting it on to the capital data second
the other problem with the Cobra dataset
is it's ridiculously small and again
there's no reason for us
okay run far more cases in NL s cheese
and they provide us a cattle so I can't
begin to imagine why they went to all
this trouble and a million dollars of
money for something which is not being
set up to succeed anyway that's not our
problem it makes it all the more
interesting thing to play with but you
know after the competition's finished if
you get interested in it you'll probably
want to go and download the hole in
Illinois C data set or as much as
possible and do it properly
initially there are two questions that
oat that I wanted to read one is a
one-inch system for the audio stream
there are occasional max volume pops
that are really hard on the ears for
remote listeners this might not be
solvable right now but something to look
into
okay and and then someone asked last
class you mentioned that you would
explain when and why to use Karros
versus I torch if you only have bright
and space for one in the same way
someone we have brain space for VI or
Emacs which would you pick okay so I
just reduced the volume a little bit so
let us know that help
I would um I would pick tight watch my
field play kind of ties everything
carrots does but gives you the
flexibility to really play around a lot
more
yeah I'm sure you fucking Facebook
so question you mentioned there are
other data sets of cancerous images that
felt like labels and proper marks yes I
kind of like the way the singham that
yes when transferred that was my
suggestion or so and that's what the
tutorial shows how to
yeah there's the whole thing Colonel on
cattle called enter degeneration and
learn and 16th on incoming which shows
how to use the lunar to build a module
finder
and this is one of the highest-rated
term
petals we've now used Colonel and three
totally different ways in this lesson
if we can come up with a fourth apple
kernels CUDA kernels and kernel methods
yeah so this is a
in fact no story familiar doesn't it so
here's a Karass approach to finding one
modules based on winner
um so
such things like vision 3d like written
examination setup attack angles like
tubes yeah saying about three days and
yeah why not yeah
[Music]
but I mentioned an opportunity to
improve this mentorship algorithm and
the opportunity for improvement when you
think about it's pretty obvious the
actual amount of data is huge right
you've got data points all over the
place the ones that are a long way away
like the weight is going to be so close
to zero that we may as well just ignore
them so the question is how do we
quickly find the ones to assure a long
way away and we know the answer to that
remember its approximate nearest
neighbors so what if we added an extra
step here which rather than using
[Music]
let's get a distance to every data point
when they're choosing a proper use
across mysterious neighbors to grab it
on the closest one the only you know the
ones that actually are going to matter
so that would basically turn this linear
time paste into a logarithmic time
please
which would be pretty fantastic so we
learnt very briefly about a particular
approach which is locality-sensitive
hashing I think I mentioned also there's
another approach which I'm really fond
of of bill trees
I really really want us as a team to
take this algorithm and add
approximately proximal nearest neighbors
to it and release it to the community as
you know the first ever super fast GPU
accelerated the proximate neural net
nearest neighbor accelerated engine
clustering algorithm I think that'd be a
really big deal so if anybody is
interested in doing that I believe
you're going to have to implement
something like elevate your skill trees
in base and once you've done that it
should be totally trivial to add the
steps that then uses that here so if you
do that then you know if you're
interested I would invite you to team up
with me and that we would then release
this piece of software together and
author a paper or a postage together so
that's my hope is that one of you or the
group of you will make that happen that
would be super exciting because I think
this would be great you know like it if
you're showing people something pretty
cool about the idea of writing GPU
algorithms today the fact I found just
during the bridge is a whole paper about
Adam Wright k-means with CUDA is you
know it used to be so much work this is
without even including any kind of
approximate nearest neighbor speeds or
whatever so I think it's be great
so hopefully that will happen okay
and look at get the right answer about
that I get to do it properly we should
also be replacing the Gaussian kernel
and Ritz with something that we figure
out dynamically rather than have a
hard-coded
all right so big change we're going to
learn about chatbots so we're going to
start here with slate Facebook thinks it
has found the secret to making BOTS less
down
ah
[Music]
okay so this talks about a youth in
court memory Network it sure is
demonstrated by Facebook you can feed it
sentences that conveyed key plot points
and Lord of the Rings and then ask
various questions published in your
paper on archives that generalizes the
approach there was another one article
about some couple of science in which
they described as early progress towards
a truly intelligent AI now the coin is
excited about working a memory Network
giving the ability to retain information
you can help the network of story and
how to answer questions and so it even
has this little if the Churchill okay so
in the article they've got this little
example showing reading the story of
Lord of the Rings and then asking
various questions about all of the Rings
and it all looks very impressive so
we're going to implement this paper and
the paper is called end to end memory
networks
the pimple is actually not shown on a
lot of the rims but was actually shown
on something called Abby had an ax Bobby
or maybe I never quite sure which one it
is it was a paper describing a synthetic
dataset towards AI complete question
entry instead of pre rested for tasks I
saw a cute tweet last week which is kind
of explaining the meaning of various
different types of titles of papers and
basically saying towards means we've
actually made no progress whatsoever so
we'll take this with a grain of salt as
though these introduced to Bobby tasks
and the batting tasks are probably best
described by showing an example
here's an example so each task is
basically a story a story contains a
list of sentences assessments contains
wizard words at the end of the story is
a query to which there is an answer so
the sentences are ordered in time so
where is Daniel we have to go backwards
it says where John is this is where
Daniel is Daniel going to the bathroom
okay - Daniel is in the bathroom so this
is what the very task lovely there's a
number of kind of different structures
this is called a one supporting set
structure which is to say you only have
to go back and find one sentence in the
story figure out the answer we're also
going to look at two supporting bet
stories which is one where you're going
to have to look twice
so the breeding ends of the datasets is
not remotely interesting this is a text
file we can pass them out
so it's various different text files for
the various different tasks and if
you're interested in the various
different tasks you can check out the
paper we're going to be looking at
single supporting fact and true
supporting facts they have some with
10,000 examples and some with 1,000
examples and the goal is to be able to
solve every one of their challenges with
just a bad example
and this paper is not successful that
goal but it yes some movement towards it
so basically we're going to put that
into a bunch of different lists of lists
of stories along with their queries and
we can start off by having a look at
some statistics about them so the first
is for each story what's the maximum
number of sentences in a story and the
answer is n so what are the rings that
age and in fact if you go back and you
look at the gift but it says read story
Lord of the Rings that's the whole world
of the Rings okay
[Music]
righto journey to mountain photo drop
the room there okay
the total number of different words in
this teen is 32
the maximum lengths of any sentence in
the story is 8
the maximum number of words in any query
is 4 so okay we are immediately thinking
what the hell right because this was
presented by the press as being the
secret to making BOTS quest Sun and
showed us that they took a story and
summarize a lot of the range of major
plot points and ask various questions
and clearly that's not entirely true
like what they did like if you look at
even the stories the first word is
always somebody's now the second word
here is always some synonym for move
there's been a bunch of prepositions and
then the last word those players so like
these toy tasks a very very very toys so
immediately we're kind of thinking maybe
this is not the set to making BOTS left
arm or whatever they've said here truly
intelligent iron that is towards it
surely intelligently okay so to get Nick
into chaos
we need to turn it into a tensor in
which everything is the same size so we
use Patsey concerns for that like we did
in the last part of the course which
will add zeros to make sure that
everything is the same size so the other
thing we'll do is we will create a
dictionary from words to integers to
turn every word into an index so we're
going to turn every word into an index
and then Pat them so that they're all
the same length and then that's going to
give us input strain 10,000 stories each
one of ten sentences each one of eight
words and anything that's not ten tenten
Islam is going to get sentences such as
zeros any tensions is not eight words
long we get some zeros appended to that
and you'd over the text we're just going
to thousand
okay so
how do we do this
not surprisingly we're going to use
embeddings
now we have to we've ever done this
before
we have to turn a sentence into anime
it's not just a word infinite bearing
so there's lots of interesting ways of
turning attention gentlemen betting but
when you're just doing towards
intelligent AI you don't do any of them
you insert just at the embeddings up and
that's what happened in this paper okay
and if you look at like the way it was
set up you can see why you can just add
the embeddings up marry John and Sandra
like they only ever appear in one place
they're always the object of this you
know the verb is always the same thing
that prepositions are always meaningless
and the last word is always placed right
so you know to figure out what a whole
sentence says you can just add up the
work concepts the order of them doesn't
make any difference there's no not
there's nothing that makes language
there might be complicated or
interesting so what we're going to do is
we're going to create an input for our
stories with number of sentences and the
length of each one we're going to take
each word and put it through an
embedding so that's what time
distributed is doing here okay it's
putting each word through a separate
embedding and then we do a lambda layer
through ESMA
okay so here is a very sophisticated
approach to creating sentence and
visions so we do that for our story so
we end up with something which rather
than being 10 by H ie 10 sentences like
Edwards is now 10 by 20 that is 10
sentences by length 20 and B each one of
our 10 sentences has been turned into a
length 20 inventing and we're just
starting with a random and then we're
not going to use word to that for
anything because there's nothing we
don't need the complexity of that but
every model
we're going to do exactly the same thing
for the query okay we don't do to you
time distributed this time so we can
just take the query because this time we
have just one query so we can do the
embedding of it up and then we use
reshape to add a unit access to the
front so that it's now the same basic
rank right we now have one question of
better to link 20 okay so we have 10
sentences of the story and one theory
okay so what is the memory network or
will specifically the more advanced
end-to-end memory network and the answer
is it is this okay as per usual when you
get down to it it's less than a page of
code these are these things let's draw
this
before we look at the code
okay so we have
sentences
Institute's fall sentences for now
so each sentence contains a bunch of
words and we took each word and returned
them into
and in bedding
okay and then we thumbed all of those
embeddings up to get an embedding
for that sentence
but for each sentence
when embedding
and they were length 20 foot
um okay and then we took the theory
there's none of that here but this is my
story
is my query
and the idea bunch of words you
embeddings for and we added them up
again inventing for our question
okay so to do a memory Network what
we're going to do is we're going to take
each of these
barring
- h1
[Music]
with the question or query and we're
just going to take a dot product
and so and draw this
you
product
but product
okay so we're going to end up with four
products from each sentence of the story
science the query alright so like what
are the dot product do it basically says
health similar to things are when one
thing big is the other things big things
small things small things both make the
dot product again okay so these
basically are going to be four vectors
describing out similar each of our four
sentences for the query okay so let's
check one step two is to stick them
through the softmax
okay
before come again right so remember dot
product is which of the scaler all right
so we now have four scales
and they add up to one and they each are
basically related to how similar is the
query to each of the four sentences
okay we're now going to create a totally
separate embedding our vectors or
sentences that are in our story by
creating a totally separate embedding
for each word so we're basically just
going to create a new random embedding
matrix for each word to start with some
them all together and that's going to
give us a new
betting this one Nicole see I believe
and all we're going to do is we're going
to multiply
each one of days Pamela
each one of these embeddings we're going
to multiply by the
um equivalent softmax at the wedding and
then just add them all together okay so
we're just going to have physical s 1 2
3 4 going to be C 1 times s 1 plus B 2
and s 2 and then divided by you mean yes
actually don't need to divide by K as a
one okay and so that's going to be
our final result which is going to be a
blink 20 back so this thing is a vector
of length 20 and then we're going to
take that letter put put it through a
single day slap
get back the anthem
and that whole thing is the memory
it's incredibly simple you know there's
no there's nothing deep in terms of deep
learning there's almost no
nonlinearities so you know it doesn't
seem like it's likely together do very
much but I guess we haven't given it
very much to do so let's take a look at
the the code version yes
so Joan
so in the last step you said the answer
was that really like the embedding of
the answer and then it has to get a
reverse lookup it's yeah it's the
softmax at the end stuff and then you
have to an automatic okay
um so here it is right we've got
we've got the story times the theory of
the embedding of the story times
embedding the query the dot product we
do a softmax softmax works from the last
dimension so I just have to reshape to
get rid of the unit axis and then I
reach it again weather unit access back
on again
but you know the reshapes aren't doing
anything interesting
let's just stop product followed by soft
necks okay and that gives us the weights
each weight and multiply it by the
second set of embeddings is our second
setting the villain can get antsy and or
do this I just use the dot product again
but because of the fact that you
forgiving access there this is actually
just doing a very simple web damage and
again reshape together to the unit axis
so that we can stick it through a dense
layer with a soft mass and that gives us
our final result so what this is
effectively doing is it's basically
saying okay how similar is the query
through each one of the sentences in the
story use that to create a bunch of
weights and then these things here are
basically the answers right it's like if
story number 1 was where the answer was
then we're going to use this one story
for two three and four right because
there's a single you know single linear
layer at the very end so it doesn't
really gets too much computation so
these it versa care to learn what the
answers represent like each story is and
again this is lucky because the
original
from the original data set the answer to
every question is the last word of the
sentence I where is Frodo's ring order
right so that's why we just can't have
this incredibly simple file piece
so we you know this is an interesting
use of cars right with we've created a
model which is in no possible way
declining right but it's you know a
bunch of tensors and layers that have
stuck together and so it has some inputs
it has an output so we can call it a
model we can compile it with an
optimizer and the life okay and then we
can fit it so it's kind of interesting
how you can use character things which
you know don't really use any other
normal players and in a normal way and
as you can see it works and for what
it's worth
okay we've solved this problem and the
particular problem we've solved here is
the one supporting that problem and in
fact it works in less than one o'clock
more interesting is to supporting that
actually before I do that I was point
out something interesting which is we
could create another model now this is
already trained which is to return not
the final answer but the value of the
the weight okay and so we can now go
back and say okay for a particular story
what are the weights so let's do s
docketed rather than and stop dude
so for this story where is Sandra Daniel
Mary Sandra Sandra went to the bathroom
whereas Sandra bathroom right so for
this particular story
the waves are here right and you can see
the wait for Simpsons number two is 0.98
so we can actually look inside the
femoral and find out you know what what
sentence isn't using to enter this
question we have a question would it not
make more sense to contact the
embeddings rather than some of them
um not the best particular problem
because because of the way the
vocabulary is structured on the
sentences and strategies you would also
have to deal with the variable length
yeah well as the briefly he's patting
tomato in the same way
yeah but if you wanted to use this in
real life
you would need to come up with a better
sentence abating it's presumably might
be an RN or something like that
as you need to deal with things learn
not and the location of subject object
and so forth one thing to point out is
that the order of the sentences matters
and so what I actually did was when I
pre-processed took what they added a
zero call in one call and whatever to
start of each sentence right so that it
would actually be able to learn the time
order of sentences so this is like
another token that I add because you're
wondering what that was so something
that I had in the pre presidency okay so
one nice thing is every networks we can
kind of look and see if they're not
working in six or why they don't work
okay so multi hot so let's now look at
an example of a to support fast story
it's mildly more interesting we still
only have one type of verb with very
synonyms and a small number of subjects
and smaller objects but basically the
same but now
to answer your question we have to go
down through hops so where is the milk
okay let's fly in the milk then you'll
lift the milk there okay where is Daniel
then you'll travel to the whole way okay
where is the milk all where all right so
that's what we have to going to do this
time and so what kind of two is exactly
the same thing as we did before
but we're going to take it our home at
all a whole little model alright so
you're the embedding reshape dot reshape
softmax reshape dot reshape
but it's a dense layer thumb and we're
going to call this one hot so this whole
picture is going to become one hot and
what we're going to do
is we're going to take this and go back
and replace the query
with our new output that's what it's
step h-hot we're going to replace the
query without with the result of our
memory Network and so that way the
memory Network and learn to recognize
that okay the first thing I need is the
milk search back find milk okay
I now have the milk now you need to
update the query to where is Daniel
okay now go back I'm Daniel right so the
memory networks in multi hot mode
basically does his whole thing again and
again and again replacing the query H
son right so that's why this took the
whole set of steps and checked it into a
single function and so then I just go
okay response comma story is one hop
response summer story is one hop on that
and you can keep repeating that again
and again and again
and then at the end get an output
but the model pyro it
I had real trouble getting this to pitch
nicely I had to play around a lot with
learning rates and batch sizes and
whatever else that I did eventually get
a two point nine nine nine equity
ah
so this is kind of an unusual part for
me to be teaching because I particularly
compared to part one whereas like best
practices know clearly this is anything
but I'm kind of showing you something
which was like maybe the most popular
request with like teachers about chat
box and they let's be honest to who has
ever used a chat pod that's not terrible
and the reason that ones do this Chapel
is not terrible is that the current
state of the art is terrible
so chat pods have their place and indeed
from one of the students class has
written really interesting kind of
analysis of this particularly she'll
share on the forum but that place is
really kind of lots of sure is big and
you know carefully set up vocabularies
and selecting from small sets of answers
and so forth it's not kind of general
purpose here's a story ask anything you
like about it here are some answers it's
not to say we won't get there I sure
hope we will but they're kind of
incredible hike we had around your
curing machines and memory network and
into it and we network is clinic as you
can see when you actually even we just
look at the data set what their work
plan is kind of crazy
so that is not quite the final
conclusion of this though because um
yesterday a paper came out which showed
how to identify buffer overruns in
computer source code using memory
networks and so it kind of brought my
whole narrative that somebody seems to
have actually used this technology for
something effectively and I guess when
you think about it it makes some sense
right so because you don't know what a
buffer overrun is
like if you're writing in an unsafe
language properly see you allocate some
memory is going to store some results or
some input and you try to put into that
memory something bigger than the analogy
allocated to basically build Elliott and
in the best case it crashes in the worst
case somebody figured out how to get
exactly the right closest sellout and
protected right place and then by taking
over your own machine the buffer
overruns are horrible things and the
idea of being able to find them if I can
actually see it does look like a memory
Network you kind of have to see like oh
where was that variable kind of set and
then whether things are set from search
and those original being allocated it's
kind of like just going back through the
source code and the vocabulary is pretty
straightforward you notice the variable
to be defined so you know that's kind of
interesting I haven't had a chance to
really study the paper yet but yeah it's
no chatbot but maybe there is a room for
memory networks already after all if
they're way to visualize what the neural
network has learned for the text there
is no dural Network okay if you're
mainly embedding I mean yeah I mean you
can look at the embeddings easily enough
I mean the whole thing is so simple very
easy to look at every embedding and as I
mentioned we looked at visualizing the
weights that will care how the softmax
but I mean we don't even need to look at
it in order to figure out what it
learned right like based on the fact
that this is just another small number
of simple linear steps we know that it
basically has to learn what the what
each sentence answer can be an object is
another three and ends will always be
milking a bore example avoid be four-way
or whatever and then the thirst of a
theme going to be and then the
conveyance of the weights are going to
have
basically learned how to come up with a
that's going to be probably a similar
embedding to the query we can even make
them same fitting so that these dot
products basically gives you something
that gives you similarity scores so this
is really a very simple largely linear
model it doesn't require too much visual
learning
[Music]
so having settled that none of this is
to say that memory networks are useless
right I mean they'll created by very
smart people with the impressive
pedigree and deep learning
they're just necessary early right and
this tends to happen in in a popular
press that kind of get overexcited about
things although in this case they don't
think we can play the press I think we
have the brain Facebook for creating a
ridiculous demo like this I mean it was
clearly created if you're people wrong
idea which I find very surprising from
people like Yammer Cohen who normally is
do the opposite of that kind of thing
so not this is dr. depressive spot in
this case but this may well turn out to
be a critical component in queueing
systems and whatever else and but we're
not there yet I had a good chat to
student merridy the other day who's a
researcher a prospective Lutton also
somebody I liked who I asked him what he
thought was kind of the most exciting
research in this direction at the moment
and he mentioned something that I was
also very excited about which is called
recurrent entity Network
and the recurrent density Network paper
is the first to solve all of the all of
the body parts with a hundred percent
accuracy now you know take it out what
you will I don't know how much that
means it synthetic tasks one of the
things that they merrily actually point
out in a blog post is that they are you
know even the basic kind of coding of
how their friend is pretty bad they have
lots of replicas and just like the whole
thing's going to mess but anyway um
nonetheless this is a interesting
approach so if you're interested in
memory networks there is certainly
something you can look at and I do think
this is yeah you know it's likely been
important direction having said all that
one of the key reasons I wanted to look
at these memory networks is not only
because it was the largest request I
think from the forums that is part of
the course but also because it
introduces something can be critical the
next couple of lessons
which is the concept of attention
attention or attentional models
models where we have to do exactly what
we just looked at which is basically
find out at each time you know which
part you know of a story to look at in
or which part of an image from a better
part of the sentence volcanoes
and so the task that we're going to be
trying to get get out over the next
lesson or two is going to be to
translate
French into English
okay so this is clearly not a toy task
right this is a very challenging task
and one of the challenges is that in a
particular French tension sentence which
is got some bunch of words it's likely
to turn into an English sentence with
some different bunch of words and maybe
these particular words here might be
this translation here and this one might
be this one and this one might be this
one and so as you go through you need
some way of saying like Oh which words
weather pattern next all right so that's
going to be the attentional model and so
what we're going to do is we're going to
be trying to come up with a proper irony
in on proper irony like an LS TM or a
guru or whatever where we're going to
change it so that inside the RNN it's
going to actually have some way of
figuring out which part of the input to
look at next
so that's the basic idea of attentional
model and so interestingly during this
time that memory networks and your
recurring machines and stuff we're
getting all this huge amount of press
attention very quietly in the background
of exactly the same same attentional
models were appearing as well and it's
the attentional model for language that
have really turned out to be critical so
you're probably seeing all of the press
about Google's new your translation
system and that really is everything but
it's planned to be like it really is
basically one giant neural network that
can translate any pair of languages the
accuracy of those translations is far
beyond anything that's happened before
and the basic structure of that neural
net is as we going to learn is
you know not that different what we've
already learned I'm just going to have
this one extra step which is some
attention and kind of depending on
you know how interested you guys are the
details of this New York translation
system that turned out that they're also
lot such a tall bricks you know the
tweets are kind of around like okay
you've got a really big vocabulary some
of the words appear very rarely you know
how do you build a system that can
understand how to translate those really
rare words for example and also just
kind of things like how do you deal with
the memory issues around having huge
embedding their sensors 102 the atom
words and stuff like that so there's
like lots of details and the nice thing
is that because again actually because
Google would ended up putting this be in
production all of these little details
kind of advances now and those answers
are already interesting there aren't
really on the whole great examples of
kind of all of those things put together
so you know what I think interesting
here will be that you'll have
opportunities to kind of do that
generally speaking the blog posts about
the kind of New York translation systems
tend to be kind of at a pretty high
level it has spread like roughly how
these kind of approaches work that
Google's complete neuro translation
system is not out there you know
download version see the code so you
know we'll see how we go but we're kind
of doers
if buddies
here so
yeah I guess one other thing to mention
about the memory network is the carrot
actually comes with a end to end memory
Network example in the in the Clarisse
github which weirdly enough when I
actually doctored it it turns out
doesn't implement this at all and so
even on the single putting that thing it
takes many many generations and doesn't
get to understand accuracy and I found
this quite surprising to discover this
you know once you start getting to some
of these more recent advances or kind of
non you know not not just a standard CNN
whatever it's just less and less common
that you actually find code that's
correct in the works and so this memory
network example was one of them so if
you actually go into the chaos that
could happen with an examples and go and
have a look and download the memory
Network you'll find that you don't get
resolved anything like this if you look
at the code you'll see that it doesn't
it really doesn't do this at all
so I just kind of wanted to mention that
as a bit of a warning that you're kind
of at the point now where I'm going to
take with a grain of salt but posts you
reads like or even some places if you
read well worth experimenting with them
and assuming you know we should start
the assumption that you can do it better
and maybe even start the assumption that
you can't necessarily trust all of the
conclusions that you've read because the
vast majority to client in my experience
between together this part of the course
the bartender at a time the stuff out
there is wrong even in fact it's late in
the a deeply respect care us authors
material sauce covert even napkins this
is just wrong so I think that's
important important point to be aware of
okay I think we're done so I think we're
going to finish five minutes early for a
change let me because it's never
happened before so thanks everybody and
so this week yeah hopefully we can have
a look at the data science Bowl make a
million dollars create a new plate or
approximate nearest neighbor algorithm
and then when you're done maybe figure
out the next stage for a memory Network
okay thanks everybody