hi everybody welcome to practical deep
learning for coders this is part one of
our two-part course I'm presenting this
from the data Institute in San Francisco
will be doing seven lessons in this part
of the course most of them will be about
a couple of hours long
this first one may be a little bit
shorter practical deep learning for
coders is all about getting you up and
running with deep learning in practice
getting world-class results and it's a
really coding focused approach as the
name suggests but we're not going to
dumb it down by the end of the course
you all have learned all of the theory
in details that are necessary to rebuild
all of the world-class results we're
learning about from scratch
now I should mention that our videos are
hosted on YouTube that we strongly
recommend watching them via our website
at course fast a I although they're
exactly the same videos the important
thing about watching them through our
website is that you'll get all of the
information you need about kind of
updates to libraries my own locations
further information frequently asked
questions and so forth so if you're
currently on YouTube watching this why
don't you switch over to crosstalk fast
at AI now and start watching through
there and make sure you read all of the
material on the page before you start
just to make sure that you've got
everything you need the other thing to
mention is that there is a really great
strong community at forums faster I from
time to time you will find that you get
stuck you may get stuck very early on
you may not get stuck for quite a while
but at some point you might get stuck
with understanding why something works
the way it does or there may be some
computer problem that you have or so
forth on forums don't fast at AI there
are thousands of other learners talking
about every lesson and lots of other
topics besides it's the most active deep
learning community on the internet by
far so definitely register there
and start getting involved you'll get a
lot more out of this course if you do
that so we're going to start by doing
some coding this is an approach we're
going to be talking about in the moment
called the top-down approach to study
but let's learn it by doing it so let's
go ahead and try and actually train a
neural network now in order to train a
neural network you almost certainly want
a GPU GPU of is a graphics processing a
graphics processing unit it's the things
that companies use to help you play
games better they let your computer
render the game much more quickly than
your CPU okay we'll be talking about
them more shortly but for now I'm going
to show you how you can get access to a
GPU specifically you're going to need an
NVIDIA GPU because only NVIDIA GPUs
support something called cooter cooter
is the language and framework that
nearly all deep learning libraries and
practitioners use to do their work
obviously it's not ideal that we're
stuck with one particular vendors cards
and over time we hope to see more
competition in this base but for now we
do need an NVIDIA GPU your laptop almost
certainly doesn't have one unless you
specifically went out of your way to buy
like a gaming laptop so almost certainly
you will need to rent one and the good
news is that renting access paying by
the second or a GPU based computer is
pretty easy and pretty cheap I'm going
to show you a couple of options the
first option I'll show you which is
probably the easiest is called Kressel
if you go to kress allcom and click on
sign up or if you've been there before
sign-in you will find yourself at this
screen which has a big button that says
start jupiter and another switch called
enable GP
you so if we make sure that is set to
true the Nabal GPU is on and we click
start Jupiter and we click start Jupiter
it's going to launch us into something
called Jupiter notebook
Jupiter notebook in a recent survey of
tens of thousands of data scientists was
rated as the third most important tool
in the data scientist toolbox it's
really important that you get to learn
it well and all of our courses will be
run through Jupiter yes Rachel you have
a question or a comment I just wanted to
point out that you get I believe 10 3
hours so if you wanted to tricresyl out
yeah he might have changed that recently
to less hours but you can check the FAQ
or the pricing but you certainly get
some three hours the pricing varies
because this is actually runs on top of
Amazon Web Services so at the moment
it's 60 cents an hour the nice thing is
though that you can always turn it turn
it on you know start your Jupiter
without the CP without the GPU running
and pay you a tenth of that price which
is pretty cool
so Jupiter notebook is something we'll
be doing all of this course in and so to
get started here we're going to find our
particular course so we're go to courses
and would go to fast a o2 and there they
are things have been moving around a
little bit so it may be in a different
spot for you when you look at this and
we'll make sure all the information
current information is on the website
now having said that that's you know the
crystal approach is you know as you can
see it's basically instant and and easy
but if you've got you know an extra hour
or so to get going and even better
option is something called paper space
paper space unlike Chris or doesn't run
on top of Amazon they have their own
machines
and if I click on so here's here's paper
space and so if I click on new machine I
can pick which one of the three data
centers to use so pick that one closest
to you so I'll say a West Coast and then
I'll say Linux and I'll say Ubuntu 16
and then it says choose machine and you
can see there's various different
machines I can choose from and
pay-by-the-hour so this is pretty cool
for 40 cents an hour so it's cheaper
than cresol I get a machine that's
actually going to be much faster than
Crescent 67 our machine or for 65 cents
an hour way way way faster all right so
I'm going to actually show you how to
get started with the paper space
approach because that actually is going
to do everything from scratch you may
find if you trailers
do the 65 cents an hour one that it may
require you to contact paper space to
say like why do you want it and it's
just an anti fraud the thing so if you
say faster AI there then they'll quickly
get you up and running so I'm going to
use the cheapest one here 40 cents an
hour you can pick how much draw it you
want and note that you pay for a month
of storage as soon as you start the
machine up alright so don't start and
stop lots of machines because each time
you pay for that month of storage
I think the 250 gig $7 a month option is
pretty good but you only need 50 gig so
if you're trying to minimize the price
you can go there the only other thing
you need to do is turn on public IP so
that we can actually log into this and
we can turn off auto snapshot to save
the money or not having backups
all right so if you then click on create
your paper space about a minute later
you will find that your machine will pop
up here is my Ubuntu 1604 machine if you
check your email you will find that they
have emailed you a password so you can
copy that
and you can go to your machine and enter
your password now to paste the password
you would press ctrl shift V or on Mac
against Apple shift V so it's slightly
different to normal pasting or of course
you can just type it in and here we are
now we can make a little bit more room
here by clicking on those little arrows
there can zoom in a little bit and so as
you can see we've got like a terminal
that's sitting inside our browser it's
just kind of quite a handy way to do it
so now we need to configure this further
course and so the way you can figure it
for the course is you type curl HTTP
colon slash slash files dot fast ai
slash setup slash paper space type -
okay
and so that's then going to run a script
which is going to set up all of the
crudo drivers special Python Reaper
Python distribution we use called
anaconda all of the libraries or other
courses and the data we use for the
first part of the course ok so that
takes an hour or so and when it's
finished running you'll need to reboot
your computer so to reboot not your own
computer but your pages paste computer
and so to do that you can just click on
this little circular restart machine
button ok and when it comes back up
you'll be ready to go so what you'll
find is if you've now got an anaconda
three directory that's where your python
is you've got a data directory which
contains the data for
the first part of this course first
lesson which is their dogs and cats and
you've got a fast AI directory and that
contains everything for this course so
what you should do is CD fast AI and
from time to time you should go get Paul
and that will just make sure that all of
your fast AI stuff is up-to-date and
also from time to time you might want to
just check that your Python libraries
are up-to-date and so you can type
Condor and update to do that alright so
make sure that you've CD into fast AI
and then you can type Jupiter notebook
all right there it is
so we now have a Jupiter notebook
servant running and we want to connect
to that and so you can see here it says
copy paste this URL into your browser
when you connect so if you double click
on it then that will actually that will
actually copy it for you then you can go
and paste it but you need to change this
local host to be the paper space IP
address so if you click on the little
arrows to go smaller you can see the IP
addresses here so I'll just copy that
and paste it where it used to say local
host okay so it's now HTTP and then my
IP and then everything else a copied
before and so there it is so this is the
faster I get repo and our courses are
all in courses and in there the deep
learning part one is DL one and in there
you will find lesson one by Mb ipython
notebook
so here we are ready to go depending
whether you're using Kressel or paper
space or something else if you check
course it's not fast today I will keep
putting additional videos and links to
information about how to set up other
you know good Jupiter notebook providers
as well so to run a cell in Jupiter
notebook you select the cell and you
hold down shift and press Enter or if
you've got the tool bar showing you can
just click on the little Run button so
you'll notice that some cells contain
code and some contain text and some
contain pictures and some contain videos
so this environment basically has you
know it's a it's a way that we can give
you access to and a way to run
experiments and to kind of tell you
what's going on so pictures
this is why it's like a super popular
tool in data science a data science is
kind of all about running experiments
really so let's go ahead and click run
and you'll see that cell turn into a
star the one turn into a star for a
moment and then it finished running okay
so let's try the next one this time
instead of using the toolbar I'm going
to hold down shift and press ENTER and
you can see again it turn into a star
and then it said to so if I hold down
shift and keep pressing enter it just
keeps running each so right so I can put
anything I like for example one plus one
is two so what we're going to do is
we're going to yes Rachel this is just a
side note but I wanted to point out that
we're using Python 3 here yes thank you
pythons are still using Python - mmhmm
yeah um and it is important to switch to
Python 3 you know now well for Class A I
you require it but you know increasingly
a lot of libraries are removing support
for Python - thanks Rachel
now it mentions here that you can
download the data set for this lesson
from this location if you're using
crystal or the paper space script that
we just used to set up that this will
already be and made available for you
okay if you're not you'll need to W get
it as now Kressel is quite a bit slower
than paper space and also it there are
some particular things it doesn't
support that we really need and so there
are a couple of extra steps if you're
using cresol you have to run two more
cells right so you can see these are
commented out there quite hashes at the
start so if you remove the hashes from
these and run these two additional cells
that just runs the stuff that the stuff
that you only need for crystal I'm using
paper space so I'm not going to run it
ok so inside our data so we set up this
path to data slash dogs cats that's pre
set up for you and so inside there you
can see here I can use an exclamation
mark to basically say I don't want to
run Python but I want to run bash right
I want to run shell so this runs a bash
command and the bit inside the curly
brackets actually refers however to a
python variable so inserts that python
variable into the batch command so
here's the contents of our folder
there's a training set and a validation
set if you're not familiar with the idea
of training sets and validation sets it
would be a very good idea to check out
our practical machine learning course
which tells you a lot about this kind of
stuff if like yeah the basics of how to
setup and run machine learning projects
more generally would you recommend that
people take that course before this one
actually a lot of students who would you
know as they went through these as said
they'll they've liked doing them
together so you can kind of check it out
and see the machine learning course
yeah they cover with some similar stuff
but all in different directions so
people have done both seen you know say
they find it they
they each support each other I wouldn't
say it's a prerequisite but you know if
I do if I say something like hey this is
the training set and this is a
validation set and you're going I don't
know what that means
at least Google but do a quick read you
know because we're assuming that you
know the very basics of kind of what
machine learning is and does to some
extent and I have a whole blog post on
this topic as well okay and we'll make
sure that you link to that from Pastor
day night
and as we just wanted to say in general
with fasting our philosophy is to kind
of learn things on an as-needed basis
yeah exactly don't try and learn
everything that you think you might need
first otherwise you'll never get around
elite learning the stuff you actually
want to learn exactly that shows up in
deep learning I think particularly a lot
yes okay so in our validation folder
there's a cat's folder and a dog's
folder and then inside the validation
cats folder is a whole bunch of JPEGs
the reason that it's set up like this is
that this is kind of the most common
standard approach for how image
classification datasets shared and
provided and the idea is that each
folder tells you the label
so there's each of these images is
labeled cats and each of the images and
the dogs folder is labelled dogs okay
this is how chaos works as well for
example so this is a pretty standard way
to share image classification files so
we can have a look so if you go plot dot
a.m. show we can see an example of the
first of the cats if you haven't seen
this before this is a Python 3.6 format
string so you can google for that if you
haven't seen it it's a very convenient
way to do string formatting and we use
it a lot so there's no cat but we're
going to mainly be interested in the
underlying data that makes up that cat
so specifically it's an image whose
shape that is the dimensions of the
array is 198 by 1/7
9x3 is it's a three dimensional array
plus a quarter rank three tensor and
here are the first four rows and four
columns of that image so as you can see
each of those cells has three items in
it and this is the red green and blue
pixel values between naught and 255 so
here's a little subset of what a picture
actually looks like inside your computer
so that's that that's will be our idea
is to take these kinds of numbers and
use them to predict whether those kinds
of numbers represent a cat or a dog
based on looking at lots of pictures of
cats and dogs so that's a pretty hard
thing to do and at the point in time
when this this this data set actually
comes from a caracal competition the
dogs versus cats caracal competition and
when it was released in I think it was
2012 the state of the art was 80%
accuracy so computers weren't really
able to at all accurately recognize dogs
versus cats so let's go ahead and train
a model so here are the three lines of
code necessary to train a model and so
let's go ahead and run it so I'll click
on this on the cell I'll press shift
enter and then we'll wait a couple of
seconds for it to pop up and there it
goes okay and it's training and so I've
asked it to do three epochs so that
means it's going to look at every image
three times in total or look at the
entire set of images three times that's
what we mean by an epoch and as we do
it's going to print out the accuracy is
that's lasted for three numbers it
prints out on the validation set okay
the first three numbers we'll talk about
later in short they're the value of the
loss function which is in this case the
cross-entropy loss for the training set
and the validation set and then right at
the start here is the epoch number so
you can see it's getting about 90%
see and it took 17 seconds so you can
see we've come a long way since 2012 and
in fact even in the competition this
actually would have won the caracal
competition of that time the best in the
caracal competition was 98.9 and we're
getting about 99% so this play surprised
you that we're getting a you know Kaggle
winning as of 20 and of 2012 early 2013
kaggle winning image classifier in 17
seconds that and three lines of code and
I think that's because like a lot of
people assume that deep learning takes a
huge amount of time and lots of
resources and lots of data and as you'll
learn in this course that in general
rule isn't true one of the ways we've
made it much simpler is that this code
is written on top of a library we built
imaginatively called fast AI the faster
a library is basically a library which
takes all of the best practices
approaches that we can find and so each
time a paper comes out you know we that
looks interesting we test it out if it
works well for a variety of data sets
and we can figure out how to tune it we
implement it in fast AI and so faster I
kind of curates all this stuff and
packages up for you and much of the time
but most the time kind of automatically
figures out the best way to handle
things so the first day our library is
why we were able to do this in just
three lines of code and the reason that
we were able to make the faster I
library work so well is because it
interns it's on top of something called
pi torch which is a really flexible deep
learning and machine learning and GPU
computation library written by Facebook
most people are more familiar with
tensorflow
than pi torch because google markets
that pretty heavily but most of the top
researchers I know nowadays at least the
ones that are at Google have switched
across to PI torch yes Rachel
and we'll be covering some pie torts
later in the course yeah it's I mean one
of the things that hopefully you'll
really like about last AI is that it's
really flexible that you can use all
these kind of curated best practices as
much as little as you want and so really
easy to hook in at any point and write
your own data augmentation write your
own loss function write your own network
architecture whatever and so we'll do
all of those things in this course so
what does this model look like well what
we can do is we can take a look at so
what are the what is the validation set
dependent variable the Y look like and
it's just a bunch of zeros and ones okay
so the zeros if we look at data dot
classes the zeros represent cats the
ones represent dogs you'll see here
there's basically two objects I'm
working with one is an object called
data which contains the validation and
training data and another one is the
object called learn which contains the
model right so anytime you want to find
something out about the data we can look
inside data so we're going to get
predictions through our validation set
and so to do that we can call learned
predict and so you can see here the
first ten predictions and what it's
giving you as a prediction for dog and a
prediction for cat now the way PI Torche
generally works and therefore fast AI
also works is that most models return
the log of the predictions rather than
the probabilities themselves we'll learn
why that is later in the course so for
now recognize that to get your
probabilities you have to get e to the
power of you'll see here we're using
numpy NP is none play if you're not
familiar with numpy that is one of the
things that we assume that you have some
familiarity with so be sure to check out
the material on cost I passed at AI to
learn the basics of number it's the way
that - handles all of the fast numerical
programming array computation that kind
of thing
okay so we can get the probabilities
using that using MP dot X and there's a
few functions here that you can look at
yourself if you're interested that's
just some flooding functions that we'll
use and so we can now plot some random
correct images and so here are some
images that it's correct about okay and
so remember one is a dog so anything
greater than 0.5 is dog and zero is a
cat so this is what 10 to the negative 5
obviously a cat here are some which are
incorrect alright so you can see that
some of these which it thinks are
incorrect obviously are just the you
know images that shouldn't be there at
all but clearly this one which it called
a a dog is not at all a dog so there are
some obvious mistakes we can also take a
look at which cats is it the most
confident are cats which dogs are the
most doglike the most confident dogs
perhaps more interestingly we can also
see which cats is that the most
confident are actually dogs so which
ones it is it the most wrong about and
same thing for the ones the dog said it
really thinks of cats and again some of
these are just pretty weird I guess
there is a dog in there yes Rachel I see
suit you want to see more about why you
would want to look at your data yeah
sure so yeah so finally I just mentioned
the last one we've got here is to see
which ones have the probability closest
to 0.5 so these are the ones that the
model knows it doesn't really know what
to do with and some of these it's not
surprising so yeah I mean this is kind
of like always the first thing I do
after I build a model is to try to find
a way to like visualize what it's built
because if I want to make the model
better then I need to take advantage of
the things that's doing well and fix the
things that's doing badly and so in this
case and off
this is the case I've learned something
about the data set itself which is that
there are some things that are in here
that probably shouldn't be but I've also
like it's also clear that this model has
room to improve like to me that's pretty
obviously a dog but one thing I'm
suspicious about here is this image is
very kind of fat and short and as we all
learn the way these algorithms work is
it kind of grabs a square piece at a
time
so this rather makes me suspicious that
we're going to need to use something
called data augmentation that we'll
learn about learn about later to handle
this properly okay so that's it right
we've now built we've now built an image
classifier and something that you should
try now is to grab some data yourself
some pictures of two or more different
types of thing put them in different
folders and run the same three lines of
code on them okay and you'll find that
it will work for that as well as long as
that they are pictures of things like
the kinds of things that people normally
take photos of right so if their
microscope microscope pictures or
pathology pictures or CT scans or
something this won't work very well as
well learn about later there are some
other things we didn't need to do to
make that work but for things that look
like normal photos these you can run
exactly the same three lines of code and
just point your path variable somewhere
else to get your own image classifier so
for example one student took those three
lines of code downloaded for Google
Images ten examples of pictures of
people playing cricket ten examples of
people playing baseball and build a
classifier of those images which was new
perfectly correct the same student
actually also tried downloading seven
pictures of Canadian currency seven
pictures of American currency and again
in that case the model was a hundred
percent accurate so you can just go to
Google Images if you like and download a
few things of a few different classes
and see see what works and tell us on
the forum both your successes and your
failures so what we just did was to
train a neural network but we didn't
first of all tell you what a neural
network is or what training means or
anything why is that well this is the
start of our top-down approach to
learning and basically the idea is that
unlike the way math and technical
subjects I usually talk where you learn
every little element piece by piece and
you don't actually get to put them all
together and build your own image
classifier until third year of graduate
school our approach is to say from the
start hey let's show you how to train an
image classifier and you can start doing
stuff and then gradually we dig deeper
and deeper and deeper and so the idea is
that throughout the course you're going
to see like new problems that we want to
solve so for example in the next lesson
we'll look at well what if we're not
looking at normal kinds of photos but
we're looking at satellite images and
we'll see why it is that this approach
that we're learning today doesn't quite
work as well and what things do we have
to change and so we'll learn enough
about the theory to understand why that
happens and then we'll learn about the
libraries and how we can change change
things with the libraries to make that
work better and so during the course we
are gradually going to learn to solve
more and more problems as we do so we
all need to learn more and more parts of
the library more and more bits of the
theory until by the end we're actually
going to learn how to create a
world plus neural net architecture from
scratch and our own training loop from
scratch and so were actually built
everything ourselves so that's the
general approach yes Rachel and
sometimes also call this the whole game
which is inspired by harvard professor
david perkins yeah and so the idea with
the whole game is like this is more like
how you would learn baseball or music
with baseball you would get taken to a
ball game you would learn what baseball
is you would start playing it and it
would only be years later that you might
learn about the physics of how curveball
works for example well with music we put
a instrument in your hand and you start
banging the drum or hitting the
xylophone and it's not until years later
that you learn about the circle of
fifths and understand how to construct a
cadence example so yeah so that this is
kind of the approach we're using it's
very inspired by David Perkins and other
writers of Education so what that does
mean is to take advantage of this as we
peel back the layers we want you to keep
like looking under the hood yourself as
well like experiment a lot now because
this is a very code driven approach so
here's basically what happens right we
start out looking today at convolutional
neural networks for images and then in a
couple of lessons we'll start to look at
how to use neural nets to look at
structured data and then look at
language data and then look at
recommendation system data and then we
kind of then take all of those depths
and we go backwards through them in
reverse order so now you know by the end
of that fourth piece you will know by
the end of lesson four how to create a
world-class image classifier a
world-class structured data analysis
program world-class language classifier
broad class recommendation system and
then we're going to go back over all of
them again and learn in depth about like
well what exactly did it do and how to
do work and how do we change things
around and use it in different
situations for for
recommendation systems structured data
images and then finally back to language
so that's how it's going to work so what
that kind of means is that most students
find that they tend to watch the videos
two or three times but not like watch
lesson one two or three times and listen
to two or three times in verse and three
three times but like they do the whole
thing into end lessons one through seven
and then go back and start lesson one
again that's an approach which a lot of
people find when they want to go back
and understand all the details enough
that can work pretty well so I would say
you know aim to get through to the end
of lesson seven you know as as quickly
as you can rather than aiming to fully
understand every detail from this data
so basically the plan is that in today's
lesson you'll learn in as few lines of
code as possible with as few details as
possible how do you actually build an
image classifier with deep learning to
do this to in this case say hey here are
some pictures of dogs as opposed to
pictures of cats then we're going to
learn how to look at different kinds of
images and particularly we're going to
look at images of from satellites and
we're going to say for a satellite image
what kinds of things might you be seeing
in that image and there could be
multiple things that we're looking at so
a multi-label classification problem
from there we'll move to something which
is perhaps the most widely applicable
for the most people which is looking at
what we call structured data so data
about data that kind of comes from
databases or spreadsheets so we're going
to specifically look at this data set of
predicting sales the number of things
that are sold at different stores on
different dates based on different
holidays and and so on and so forth and
so we're going to be doing its sales
forecasting exercise after that we're
going to look at language and we're
going to figure out
what this person thinks about the movie
is on be given and will be able to
figure out how to create just like we
create image classifiers for any kind of
image will learn to create in NLP
classifiers to classify any kind of
language in lots of different ways then
we'll look at something called
collaborative filtering which is used
mainly for recommendation systems we're
going to be looking at this data set
that showed four different people for
different movies what rating did they
give it and here are some of the movies
and so this is maybe an easier way to
think about it is there are lots of
different users and lots of different
movies and then for each one we can look
up for each user how much they liked
that movie and the goal will be of
course to predict for user movie
combinations we haven't seen before are
they likely to enjoy that movie or not
and that's the really common approach
used for like deciding what stuff to put
on your homepage when somebody's
visiting you know what book might they
want to read or what film might they
want to see or so forth from there we
could have then dig back into language a
bit more and we're going to look at
actually we're gonna look at the
writings of Nietzsche the philosopher
and learn how to create our own
Nietzsche philosophy from scratch
character by character so this here
perhaps that every life values a blood
of intercourse when it senses there is
unscrupulous who's very right sense to
impulse love is not actually Nietzsche
that's actually like some character by
character generated text that we built
with this recurrent neural network and
then finally we're going to loop all the
way back to computer vision again we're
going to learn how not just to recognize
cats from dogs how to actually find like
where the cat is with this kind of hate
map and we're also going to learn how to
write our own architectures from scratch
so this is an example of a resonate
which is the kind of network that we are
using in today's lesson for computer
vision and so we'll actually end up
building the network and the training
loop from scratch and so they're
basically the the steps that we're going
to be taking from here
and at each step we're going to be
getting into increasing amounts of
detail about how to actually do these
things yourself so we've actually heard
that from our students of past courses
about what they've found and one of the
things that we've heard a lot of
students say is that there's been too
much time on theory and research and not
enough time running the code and even
after we tell people about this morning
where they still come to the end of the
course not and say I wish I had taken
more seriously that advice which is to
keep running code so these are actual
quotes from our forum in retrospect I
should have spent the majority of my
time on the actual code and the
notebooks see what goes in see what
comes out now this idea that you can
create world-class models in a code
first approach learning what you need as
you go is very different to a lot of the
advice you're read out there such as
this person on the forum hacker news who
claimed that the best way to become an
m/l engineer is to learn all of math and
C and C++ learn parallel programming
learn ml algorithms implement them
yourself using plain C and finally start
doing ml so we would say if you want to
become an effective practitioner do
exactly the opposite of of this yes
Rachel yeah I'm just highlighting that
this is we think this is bad advice and
this can be very discouraging for a lot
of people to come across this yeah yeah
it's it's it's it's you know we now have
thousands and more tens of thousands of
people that have done this course and
have lots and lots of examples of people
who are now running research labs or
Google brain residence or you know have
created patents based on deep learning
and so forth who have done it by doing
this course so the top-down approach
works super well
now one thing to mention is like we've
we've now already learned how you can
actually train a world-class image
classifier in 17 seconds I should
mention by the way the first time you
run that code there are two things it
has to do that take more than 17 seconds
one is that it downloads a pre trained
model from the internet so you'll see
the first time you run it it'll say
downloading model so that takes a minute
or two also the first time you run it it
pre computes and caches some of the
intermediate information that it needs
and that takes about a minute and a half
as well so if the first time you run it
it takes three or four minutes to
download and pre compute stuff that's
normal if you run it again you should
find it takes 20 seconds or so so image
classifiers
you know you may not feel like you need
to recognize cats versus dogs very often
on a computer you can probably do it
yourself pretty well but what's
interestingly interesting is that these
image classification algorithms are
really useful for lots and lots of
things for example alphago which became
which beat the go world champion the way
it worked was to use something at its
heart that looked almost exactly like
our dogs vs. cats image classification
algorithm it looked at thousands and
thousands of go boards and at for each
one there was a label saying whether
that go board ended up being the winning
or the losing player and so it learnt
basically an image classification that
was able to look at a go board and
figure out whether it was a good group
or a bad code board and that's really
the key most important step in playing
Gowell is to know which which move is
better another example is one of our
earlier students who actually got a
couple of patterns for this work looked
at anti-fraud he had lots of
all of his customers mouths movements
because they they provided kind of these
user tracking software to help avoid
fraud and so he took the the mouse paths
basically of the users on his customers
websites turn them into pictures of
where their mouse moved and how quickly
it moved and then built a image
classifier that took those images as
input and as output it was was that a
fraudulent transaction or not and turned
out to go you know really great results
for his company so image classifiers are
like much more flexible than you might
imagine
so so this is how you know some of the
ways you can use deep learning
specifically for image recognition and
it's worth understanding that deep
learning is not you know just a word
that means the same thing as machine
learning right like what is it that
we're actually doing here when we're
doing deep learning instead deep
learning is a kind of machine learning
so machine learning was invented by this
guy Arthur Samuels who was pretty
amazing
in the late 50s he got this IBM
mainframe to play checkers better than
he can and the way he did it was he
invented machine learning he got the
mainframe to play against itself lots of
times and figure out which kinds of
things led to victories and which kinds
of things didn't and use that to kind of
almost write its own program and Arthur
Arthur Samuels actually said in 1962
that he thought that one day the vast
majority of computer software would be
written using this machine learning
approach rather than written by hand by
writing the loops and so forth by hand
so I guess that hasn't happened yet but
it seems to be in the process of
happening I think one of the reasons it
didn't happen for a long time is because
traditional machine learning actually
was very difficult and very
knowledge and time intensive so for
example here's something called the
computational pathologist or C path from
backwater and II back and II back back
when he was at Stanford he's now moved
on to somewhere on the East Coast no
Harvard I think and what he did was he
took these pathology slides of breast
cancer biopsies right and he worked with
lots of pathologists to come up with
ideas about what kinds of patterns or
features might be associated with so
long-term survival versus versus dying
quickly basically and so he came up with
these ideas like well they came up with
these ideas like relationship between
epithelial nuclear neighbors
relationship between epithelial and
stromal objects and so forth and so they
came up with all of these ideas of
features these are just a few of the
hundreds that they thought of and then
lots of smart computer programmers wrote
specialist algorithms to to calculate
all these different features and then
those those features were passed into a
logistic regression to predict survival
and it ended up working very well and it
ended up that the survival predictions
were more accurate than pathologists own
survival predictions work and so machine
learning can work really well but the
point here is that this was a an
approach that took lots of domain
experts and computer experts many years
of work to actually to build this thing
right so we really want something
something better and so specifically I'm
going to show you something which rather
than being a very specific function with
all this very domain-specific feature
engineering we're going to try and
create an infinitely flexible function a
function that could solve any problem
right it would solve any problem if only
you set the parameters of that function
correctly and so then we need
or purpose way of setting the parameters
of that function and we would need that
to be fast and scalable right now if we
had something that had these three
things then you wouldn't need to do this
incredibly time and domain knowledge
intensive approach anymore instead we
can learn all of those things with this
with this algorithm so as you might have
guessed the algorithm in question which
has these three properties is called
deep learning or it's not an algorithm
then maybe we will call it a class of
algorithms let's look at each of these
three things in turn so the underlying
function that deep learning uses is
something called the neural network now
the neural network we're going to learn
all about it and implemented ourselves
from scratch later on in the course but
for now all you need to know about it is
that it consists of a number of simple
linear layers interspersed with a number
of simple nonlinear layers and when you
in dispersed these layers in this way
you get something called the universal
approximation theorem and the universal
approximation theorem says that this
kind of function can solve any given
problem to arbitrarily close accuracy as
long as you add enough parameters so
it's actually provably shown to be an
infinitely flexible function okay so now
we need some way to fit the parameters
so that this infinitely flexible neural
network solves some specific problem and
so the way we do that is using a
technique that probably most of you will
have come across before at some stage
called gradient descent and with
gradient descent we basically say okay
well for the different parameters we
have how how good are they at solving my
problem and let's figure out a slightly
better set of parameters and a slightly
better set of parameters and j6v follow
down the the surface of the loss
function downwards it's kind of like a
marble going down
find the minimum and as you can see here
depending on where you start you end up
in different places these things a court
local minima now interestingly it turns
out that for neural networks
particularly in particular there aren't
actually multiple different local minima
there's basically just there's basically
just one right or think of it another
way there are different parts of the
space which are all equally good so
gradient descent therefore turns out to
be actually an excellent way to solve
this problem of fitting parameters to
neural networks the problem is though
that we need to do it in a reasonable
amount of time
and it's really only thanks to GPUs that
that's become possible so GPUs this
shows over the last few years
how many gigaflops per second can you
get out of a GPU that's the red and
green versus a CPU that's the blue right
and this is on a log scale so you can
see that generally speaking the GPUs are
about 10 times faster than the CPUs and
what's really interesting is that
nowadays not only is the Titan X about
10 times faster than the e5 to $6.99 CPU
but the Titan X well actually better one
to look at would be the GTX 1080i GPU
costs about 700 bucks
whereas the CPU which is 10 times slower
costs over $4,000 so GPUs turn out to be
able to solve these neural network
parameter fitting problems incredibly
quickly and also incredibly cheaply so
they've been absolutely key in bringing
these three pieces together then there's
one more piece which is I mentioned that
these neural network
so you can intersperse multiple sets of
linear and then nonlinear layers in the
particular example that's drawn here
there's actually only one what we call
hidden layer one layer in the middle and
something that we learned in the last
few years is that these kinds of neural
networks although they do support the
universal approximation theorem they can
solve any given problem arbitrarily
closely they require an exponentially
increasing number of parameters to do so
so they don't actually solve the fast
and scalable for even reasonable size
problems but we've since discovered that
if you create add multiple hidden layers
then you get super linear scaling so you
can add a few more hidden layers to get
multiplicatively more accuracy 2ma
duplicative lis more complex problems
and that is where it becomes called deep
learning so deep learning means a neural
network with multiple hidden layers so
when you put all this together there's
actually really amazing what happens
Google started investing in deep
learning in 2012 they actually hired
Geoffrey Hinton who's kind of the father
of deep learning and his top student
Alex Bogusky and they started trying to
build a team that team became known as
Google brain and because things with
these three properties are so incredibly
powerful and so incredibly flexible you
can actually see over time how many
projects at Google use deep learning my
graph here only goes up through a bit
over a year ago but it's I know it's
been continuing to grow exponentially
since then as well and so what you see
now is around Google that deep learning
is used in like every part of the
business and so it's really interesting
to see how the
this kind of simple idea that we can
solve machine learning problems using a
an algorithm that has these properties
when a big company invests heavily in
actually making that happen you see this
incredible growth in how much it's used
so for example if you use the inbox by
Google software then when you receive an
email from somebody it will often tell
you here are some replies that I could
send for you and so it's actually using
deep learning here to read the original
email and to generate some suggested
replies and so like this is a really
great example of the kind of stuff that
previously just wasn't possible another
great example would be Microsoft is also
a little bit more recently invested
heavily in deep learning and so now you
can use Skype you can speaking to it in
English and ask it at the other end to
translate it in real time to Chinese or
Spanish and then when they talk back to
you in Chinese or Spanish Scott will in
real-time translated the speech in in
their language into English speech in
real-time and again this is an example
of stuff which we can only do
thanks to deep learning and something is
really interesting to think about how
deep learning can be combined with human
expertise so here's an example of low
drawing something just sketching it out
and then using a program called neural
doodle this is from a couple of years
ago - then say please take that sketch
and render it in the style of an artist
and so here's the picture that have been
created rendering it as you know
impressionist painting and I think this
is a really great example of how you can
use deep learning to help combine human
expertise and what computers are good at
so I a few years ago decided to try this
myself like what would happen if I took
think learning and tried to use it to
solve a really important problem and so
the problem I picked was diagnosing lung
cancer it turns out if you can find lung
nodules earlier there's a 10 times
higher probability of survival so it's a
really important problem to solve so I
got together with three other people
none of us had any medical background
and we grabbed a data set of CT scans we
used to compilation or neural network
much like the dogs vs. cats one we
trained at the start of today's lesson
to try and predict which CT scans had
malignant tumors in them and we ended up
after a couple of months with something
with a much lower false negative rate
and a much lower false positive rate
than a panel with four radiologists and
we went on to build this in a start-up
in just into a company called analytic
which has really become pretty
successful and since that time the idea
of using deep learning for medical
imaging has become hugely popular and is
being used all around the world so what
I've generally noticed is that you know
the vast majority of of kind of things
that people do in the world currently
aren't using deep learning and then each
time somebody says oh let's try using
deep learning to improve performance at
this thing they nearly always get
fantastic results and then suddenly
everybody in that industry starts using
it as well so there's just lots and lots
of opportunities here at this particular
time to use deep learning to help with
all kinds of different stuff so I've
jotted down a few ideas here these are
all things which I know you can use deep
learning for right now to get good
results from and you know are things
which people spend a lot of money on or
have a lot of you know important
business opportunities there's lots more
as well
that these are some examples of things
that maybe your company you could think
about applying deep learning for so
let's talk about what's actually going
on what actually happened when we
trained that deep learning model earlier
and so as I briefly mentioned the thing
we created is something called a
convolutional neural network or CNN and
the key piece of a convolutional neural
network is the convolution so here's a
great example from our website
I've got the URL up here explained
visually it's called and the explained
visually website has an example of a
convolution kind of in fact this over
here in the bottom left is a very zoomed
in picture of somebody's face and over
here on the right is an example of using
a convolution on that image you can see
here this particular thing is obviously
finding edges the edges of his head
about top and bottom edges in particular
now how is it doing that well if we look
at each of these are all three by three
areas this is moving over it's taking
each three by three area of pixels and
here are the pixel values right for each
thing in that 3x3 area and it's
multiplying each one of those 3 by 3
pixels by each one of these 3 by 3
kernel values in a convolution this
specific set of 9 values is called a
kernel it doesn't have to be 9 it could
be 4 by 4 or 5 by 5 or 3 by 2 or
whatever right in this case it's a 3 by
3 kernel and in fact a deep learning
nearly all of our kernels are 3 by 3 so
in this case the kernel is 1 - 1 / - 1 -
2 - 1 so we take each of the black
through white pixel values and we
multiply as you can see each of them by
the corresponding value in the kernel
and then we add them all together and so
if you do that for every 3x3 area you
end up with the values you see over here
on the right hand side okay so very low
values become black very high values
become white and so you can see when
we're at an edge where it's black at the
bottom and white at the top we're
obviously going to get higher numbers
over here and vice versa okay so that's
a convolution so as you can see it is a
linear operation and so based on that
definition of a neural net I described
before this can be a layer in our neural
network it is a simple linear operation
and we're going to look much more at
convolutions later including building a
little spreadsheet that implements them
ourselves
so the next thing we're going to do is
we're going to add a nonlinear layer so
a non-linearity as it's called is
something which takes an input value and
turns it into some different value in a
nonlinear way and you can see this
orange picture here is an example of a
nonlinear function specifically this is
something called a sigmoid and so a
sigmoid is something that has this kind
of S shape and this is what we used to
use as our nonlinearities in neural
networks a lot actually nowadays we're
nearly entirely use something else
called a rally or rectified linear unit
a rail u is simply take any negative
numbers and replace them with 0 and
leave any positive numbers as they are
so in other words in code that would be
y equals max X comma 0 so max X comma 0
simply says replace the negatives with 0
now regardless of whether you use a
sigmoid or a RAL you or something else
the key point about taking this
combination of a linear layer followed
by a element-wise nonlinear function is
that it allows us to create arbitrarily
complex shapes as you see in the bottom
right and the reason why is that and
this is all from Michael Nelson's
neural networks and deep learning com
really fantastic interactive book as you
change the values of your linear
functions it basically allows you to
kind of like build these arbitrarily
tall or thin blocks and then combine
those blocks together and this is
actually the essence of the universal
approximation theorem this idea that
when you have a linear layer feeding
into a non-linearity you can actually
create these arbitrarily complex shapes
so this is the key idea behind why
neural networks can solve any computable
problem so then we need a way as we
described to actually set these
parameters so it's all very well knowing
that we can move three a meters around
manually to try to create different
shapes but we have some specific shape
we want how do we get to that shape and
so as we've discussed earlier the basic
idea is to use something called gradient
descent this is an extract from a
notebook actually one of the first AI
lessons and it shows actually an example
of using gradient descent to solve a
simple linear regression problem but I
can show you the basic idea let's say
you were just you had a simple quadratic
all right and so you are trying to find
the minimum of this quadratic and so in
order to find the minimum you start out
by randomly picking some point all right
so we say okay let's pick let's pick
here and so you go up there and you
calculate the value of your quadratic
at that point so what you now want to do
is try to find a slightly better point
so what you could do is you can move a
little bit to the left and a little bit
to the right to find out which direction
is down and what you'll find out is that
moving a little bit to the left
decreases the value of the function so
that looks good right and so in other
words we're calculating the derivative
there's a function at that point right
so that tells you which way is down it's
the gradient and so now that we know
that going to the left is down we can
take a small step in that direction
to create a new point and then we can
repeat the process and say okay which
way is down now and we can now take
another step and another step and
another step another step another step
okay and each time we're getting closer
and closer so the basic approach here is
to say okay we start we're at some point
we've got some value X which is our
current guess right that's at time step
n so then our new guest at time step n
plus 1 is just equal to our previous
guess plus the derivative
right times some small number because we
want to take a small step we need to
pick a small number because if we picked
a big number right then we say okay we
know we want to go to the left let's
jump a big long way to the left we could
go all the way over here and we actually
end up worse all right and then we do it
again now we're even worse again right
so if you have too high a step size you
can actually end up with divergence
rather than convergence so this number
here we're going to be talking about it
a lot during this course and we're going
to be writing all this stuff out in code
from scratch ourselves but this number
here is called the learning rate okay so
you can see here this is an example of
basically starting out with some random
line and then using gradient descent to
gradually make the line better and
better and better
so what happens when you combine these
ideas right the convolution the
non-linearity and gradient descent
because they're all tiny small simple
little things it doesn't sound that
exciting but if you have enough of these
kernels right with enough layers
something really interesting happens and
we can actually draw them so here's the
so this is a really interesting paper by
Matt Siler and Rob Fergus and what they
did a few years ago was they figured out
how to basically draw a picture of what
each layer in a deep learning net
Network learned and so they showed that
layer one of the network here are nine
examples of convolutional filters from
layer one of a trained network and they
found that some of the filters kind of
learnt these diagonal lines or simple
dat or grid patterns some of them learnt
these simple gradients right and so for
each of these filters they show nine
examples of little pieces
of actual photos which activate that
filter quite highly right so you can see
layer one these learnt or ever these
these are learnt using gradient descent
these filters were not programmed they
will learnt using gradient descent so in
other words we were learning these nine
numbers so layer two then was going to
take these as inputs and combine them
together and so layer two had you know
this is like my in kind of attempts to
draw one of the examples of the filters
in layer two they're pretty hard to draw
but what you can do is say if the each
filter what are examples of little bits
of images that activated them and you
can see by layer two we've got basically
something that's being activated nearly
entirely by little bits of sunset some
things that's being activated by
circular objects something that's being
activated by repeating horizontal lines
something that's being activated by
corners so you can see how we're
basically combining layer one features
together so if we combine those features
together and again these are all
convolutional filters won't through
gradient descent by the third layer it's
actually learn to recognize the presence
of text another filter has learnt to
recognize the presence of petals another
filter has learnt to recognize the
presence of human faces right so just
three layers is enough to get some
pretty rich behavior so but by the time
we get to layer five we've got something
that can recognize the eyeballs of
insects and birds and something that can
recognize unicycle wheels alright so so
this is kind of where we start with
something incredibly simple right but if
we use it as a big enough scale thanks
to the universal approximation theorem
and the use of multiple hidden layers in
deep learning we actually get the
very very rich capabilities so that is
what we used when we actually trained
our little dog vs cat recognizer okay so
let's talk more about this dog vs cat
recognizer
so we've learnt the idea of like we can
look at the pictures that come out of
the other end to see what the model is
classifying well like as I find badly or
which ones it's unsure about but let's
talk about like this key thing I
mentioned which is the learning rate so
I mentioned we have to set this thing I
just caught it L before the learning
rate and you might have noticed there's
a couple of numbers these kind of magic
numbers here the first one is the
learning rate right so this number is
how much do you want to multiply the
gradient by when you're taking each step
in your gradient descent we already
talked about why you wouldn't want it to
be too high right but probably also it's
obvious to see why you wouldn't want it
to be too low if you had it too low you
would take like a little step and you'd
be a little bit closer and little bits
too little step little step and it would
take lots and lots and lots of steps and
it would take too long so setting this
number well is actually really important
and for the longest time this was
driving deep learning researchers crazy
because they didn't really know a good
way to set this reliably so the good
news is last year a researcher came up
with an approach to quite reliably set
the learning rate unfortunately almost
nobody noticed so almost no deep
learning researchers I know about
actually are aware of this approach but
it's incredibly successful and it's
incredibly simple and I'll show you the
idea right it's built into the fast AI
library as something called @lr find or
the learning rate finder and it comes
from this paper I was actually 2015
paper sorry
cyclic or learning rates for training
neural networks by a terrific researcher
called
Leslie Smith and I'll show you Leslie's
idea
so Leslie's ideas started out with the
same basic idea that we've seen before
which is if we're going to optimize
something pick some random point take
its gradient all right and then
specifically he said take a tiny tiny
step like tiny step so a learning rate
of like 10 e next seven all right and
then do it again again but each time
increase the learning rate like double
it so then we try like to wean X 7 14 X
7 18 X 7 10 in X 6 right and so
gradually your steps are getting bigger
and bigger right and so you can see
what's going to happen it's gonna like
start doing almost nothing right and
it's going to then suddenly the loss
function is going to improve very
quickly right but then it's going to
step even further again and then even
further again all right
let's draw the rest of that line to be
clear all right and so suddenly it's
then going to shoot off and get much
worse right so the idea then is to go
back and say okay at what point did we
see like the best improvement so here
we've got our best improvement right and
so I would say ok let's use that
learning rate right so in other words if
we were to plot the learning rate over
time
it was increasing like so alright and so
what we then want to do is we want to
plot the learning rate against the loss
right so when I say the loss I basically
mean like how accurate is the model how
close in this case the loss would be how
far away is the predictive prediction
from the from the goal okay and so if we
plotted the learning rate against the
loss we'd say like okay initially it
didn't do very much right for small
learning rates and then it suddenly
improved a lot and then it suddenly got
a lot worse so that's the basic idea and
so we'd be looking for the point where
this graph is dropping quickly right
we're not looking for its minimum point
we're not saying like where was it the
lowest because that could actually be
the point where it's just jumped too far
we want at what point was it dropping
the fastest so if you go so if you
create your learn object in the same way
that we did before we'll be learning
more about this these details shortly if
you then call LR find method on that
you'll see that it'll start training a
model like it did before but it'll
generally stop before it gets to 100%
okay because if it notices that the loss
is getting a lot worse then it'll stop
automatically that's what you can see
here it stopped at 84% and so then you
can call one said that gets you the
learning rate scheduler that's the
object which actually does this learning
rate finding and that object has a plot
learning rate function and so you can
see here over by iteration you can see
the learning rate alright so you can see
each step the learning rate is getting
bigger and bigger you can do it this way
we can see it's increasing exponentially
another way that Leslie Smith the
researcher suggests is to do it linearly
so I'm actually currently researching
with both of these approaches to see
which works best recently I've been
mainly using exponential but I'm
starting to look more
using Linea at the moment and so if we
then call shed but plot that does the
plot that I just described down here
learning rate versus loss all right and
so we're looking for the highest
learning rate we can find where the loss
is still improving clearly well right
and so in this case I would say 10 to
the negative 2x that 10 to the negative
1 it's not improving right 10 to the
negative 3
it is also improving but I'm trying to
find the highest learning rate I can or
it's still clearly improving so I'd say
10 to the negative 2 okay so you might
have noticed that when we ran our model
before we had 10 to the negative to 0.01
so that's why we picked that learning
rate so there's really only one other
number that we have to pick and that was
this number three and so that number
three controlled how many epochs did we
run so an epoch means going through our
entire data set of images and using each
each time we do a bunch of they're
called mini batches we grab like 64
images at a time and use them to try to
improve the model a little bit using
gradient descent right and using all of
the images once is called one epoch and
so at the end of each epoch we print out
the accuracy and validation and training
loss at the end of the epoch so the
question of how many epochs should be
run is kind of the one other question
that you need to answer to run these
three lines of code and the answer
really to me is like as many as you like
what you might find happen is if you run
it for too long the accuracy you'll
start getting worse all right and we'll
learn about that why later it's
something called overfitting right so
you can run it for a while run lots of
epochs
once you see it getting worse you know
how many epochs you can run and the
other thing that might happen is if
you've got like a really big model or a
lot lots and lots of data maybe it takes
so long you don't have time and so you
just run enough epochs that fit into the
time you have available so the number of
epochs you run you know that's a pretty
easy thing to set so there are the only
two numbers you're gonna have to see it
and so the goal this week will be to
make sure that you can run not only
these three lines of code on the data
that I provided but to run it on a set
of images that you either have on your
computer or that you get from work well
that you download from Google and like
try to get a sense of like which kinds
of images this is seem to work well for
which ones doesn't it work well for what
kind of learning rates do you need for
different kinds of images how many
epochs do you need how does the number
of the learning rate change the accuracy
you get and so forth like really
experiment and then you know try to get
a sense of like what's inside this data
object you know what are the y-values
look like what are these places mean if
you're not familiar with numpy you know
really practice a lot with numpy so that
by the time you come back for the next
lesson
you know we're going to be digging into
a lot more detail and so you'll really
feel ready to do that now one thing
that's really important to be able to do
that is that you need to really know how
to work with numpy the faster a library
and so forth and so I want to show you
some tricks in Jupiter notebook to make
that much easier so one trick to be
aware of is if you can't quite remember
how to spell something right so if
you're not quite sure what the method
you want is you can always hit tab and
you'll get a list of methods that start
with that letter right and so that's a
quick way to find things
if you then can't remember what the
arguments are to a method hit shift tab
all right so hitting shift tab tells you
the arguments to the method so shift tab
is like one of the most helpful things I
know so let's take in P X P shift tab
and so now you might be wondering like
okay well what does this function do and
how does it work if you press shift tab
twice then it actually brings up the
documentation shows you what the
parameters are and shows you what it
returns and gives you examples okay if
you press it three times then it
actually pops up a whole little separate
window with that information
okay so shift tab is super helpful one
way to grab that window straight away is
if you just put question mark at the
start then it just brings up that little
documentation window now the other thing
to be aware of is increasingly during
this course we're going to be looking at
the actual source code of fast AI itself
and learning how it's built and why it's
built that way it's really helpful to
look at source code in order to you know
understand what you can do and how you
can do it so if you for example wanted
to look at the source code for learned I
predict you can just put two question
marks okay and you can see it's popped
up the source code right and so it's
just a single line of code
you're very often find that fast AI
methods like they they're designed to
never be more than about half a screen
full of code and they're often under six
lines so you can see this case it's
calling predicted with tags so we could
then get the source code for that in the
same way okay and then that's calling a
function called predicted with tags so
we could get that documentation for that
in the same way and then so here yeah
and then finally that's what it does it
either rates through a data loader gets
the predictions and then passes them
back and so forth okay so question mark
question mark is how to get source code
but the single question mark is how to
get documentation
and shift-tab is how to bring up
parameters or press it more times to get
the docs so that's really helpful
another really helpful thing to know
about is how to use Jupiter notebook
well and the button that you want to
know is H if you press H it will bring
up the keyboard shortcuts palette and so
now you can see exactly what Jupiter
notebook can do and how to do it I
personally find all of these functions
useful so I generally tell students to
try and learn four or five different
keyboard shortcuts a day try them out
see what they do see how they work and
then you can try practicing in that
session and one very important thing to
remember when you're finished with your
work for the day go back to a paper
space and click on that little button
which stops and starts the machine so
after it's stopped
you'll see it says connection closed and
you'll see it's off if you leave it
running you'll be charged for it
same thing with Kressel be sure to go to
your cresol instance and stop it you
can't just turn your computer off or
close the browser you actually have to
stop an increase or or in paper space
and don't forget to do that or you'll
end up being charged until you finally
do remember okay so I think that's all
the information that you need to get
started please remember about the
forum's okay if you get stuck at any
point check them out but before you do
make sure you read the information on
course dot fast at AI for each lesson
right because that is going to tell you
about like things that have changed okay
so if there's been some change - witch
Cupid a notebook provider we suggest
using or how to set up paper space or
anything like that and that'll all be on
course doc bastard AI okay thanks very
much for watching and look forward to
seeing you in the next lesson