so I recognize that by going back to
clustering we're going to talk about
clustering again in the next lesson or
two in terms of an application of it but
specifically what I wanted to do was
show you k-means clustering intensive
love it is stay on
um
there are some things which is easier to
do intensive flows and play torch
mainly because tensorflow kind of has a
more complete API at so far so there are
some things that are just yellow content
to float if like oh there's already a
method that does that but there isn't
one in pi torch and so something and
some things are just a bit easier neater
in gentle flow than implied torch and I
actually found k-means quite easy to do
but what I'm going to do is I'm going to
try and show you a way to write custom
tensor flow code in a kind of a really
pie torchy way right and a kind of an
interactivity way and we're going to try
and avoid all of the you know fancy
széchenyi graphics kopi business as
much as possible so to remind you that
where we kind of initially claimed at
clustering was to say hey what if we
were doing lung cancer detection in CT
scans and these were like 512 by 512 by
200 volumetric things which is too big
to really run a whole CNN over
conveniently so one of the thoughts to
fix that was to run some kind of
heuristic that found all of the things
that look like they could vaguely be
modules and then create a new data set
where you basically zoomed into each of
those maybe nodules and created a small
little you know 20 by 20 by 20 cube or
something you could then use a 3d CNN on
there or try planar CNN and I this
general concept I wanted to remind you
about because I feel like it's something
which maybe I haven't stressed enough
I've kind of kept from showing any ways
of doing this think back to the lesson 7
with a fish I showed you the bounding
boxes and I showed you the heat maps so
the reason for all of that would
basically to show you how to zoom into
things and then create new models based
on those zoom different things so in the
fisheries case you know you could really
just use a lower res CNN to find that
maybe fish and
into those in the CT scan case maybe we
can't even do that so maybe we need to
use this kind of mentorship clustering
approach another thing we necessarily do
to be interesting to see what the
winners use but certainly particularly
if you don't have lots of time or you
have a lot of data heuristics become
more and more interesting now the reason
is you're istic is interesting is you
can do something quickly an approximate
that could have lots and lots and lots
of false positives and it doesn't really
matter right because you know those
false positives means just you know
extra data that you're feeding to your
you know your real model so you can
always tune it it's like okay how much
time have I got to train my real model
and then I can decide how many false
positives
I can I can handle so as long as you're
kind of pre processing model is better
than nothing
go you know you can use it to get rid of
some of the stuff that like is clearly
not a nodule for example for example
anything that is like in the middle of
the lung wall is not a nodule another
thing that is you know or whitespace is
not a nodule so forth okay so we talked
about mean shift clustering and how the
big benefit of it is that it allows us
to build clusters without knowing how
many clusters there are at a time also
it without any special extra work that
allows us to find clusters which aren't
kind of Gaussian or tharok all if you
like in shape but can that's really
important for something like a CT scan
where a cluster will often be like a
vessel which is this really skinny long
thing so k-means on the other hand is
faster I think it's N squared rather
than n cubed time we have talked to you
on the forum about dramatically speeding
up means shift clustering using
approximate nearest neighbors which is
something which we started making some
progress on today so hopefully we'll
have results from that maybe by next
week
but the basic naive algorithm is
certainly should be a lot classed at the
k-means so there's one good reason to
use it so as per usual you know we can
start with some listing data and we're
going to try and figure out what where
the cluster centers are so one quick way
to avoid hassles in tensor flow is to
create an interactive session so an
interactive session basically means that
you can call that run on a computation
graph which doesn't return something or
dot eval on our computation graph that
does return something and you don't have
to worry about creating a graph or a
session or you know calling having a
session with the clause or anything like
that it just it just works so that's
basically what happens when you call TF
interactive session
okay so by creating an interactive
session we can then
[Music]
and if do you things one step at a time
so in this case the first step in
k-means is to pick some initial
centroids so you basically start out and
say okay if we're going to create
however many clusters so in this case n
plus tis is six okay then start out by
saying okay well where where might you
know where might those six clusters be
and for a long time with k-means people
picked them randomly but most
practitioners realize that that was a
dumb idea soon enough and a lot of
people had various heuristics for
picking them in 2007 finally a paper was
published actually suggesting a
heuristic I tend to use a very simple
heuristic which is what I use here in
find initial centroids so to describe
this heuristic I will show you the code
so find additional centroids looks like
this basically and I'm going to run
through it quickly and then I'll run
through it slowly basically the idea is
we first of all pick a single data point
index and then we select that single
data point okay so we have someone
randomly selected data point and then we
find what is the distance from that
randomly selected data point to every
other data point
and then we say okay what is the data
point that is the farthest away from
that randomly selected data point the
index of it and the point itself and
then we say okay we're going to append
that to the initial centroids so say
they picked at random this plate as my
random initial point the furthest point
away from that is probably somewhere
around here okay so that would be the
first centroid we picked okay we are now
inside a loop and we now go back and we
repeat the process so we now replace our
random point with the actual first
centroid and we repeat go through the
live once more so if we had our first
centroid here our second one now might
be somewhere up here okay so we now have
two centroids the next time through the
loop therefore this is slightly more
interesting this all distances we're now
going to have the distance between every
one of our initial centroids and every
other data point that's we've got a
matrix in this case it's going to be two
by the number of data points so then we
say okay for every data point find the
closest cluster okay so what's the
distance to the closest initial centroid
okay and then tell me which data point
is the farthest away from its closest
initial centroid so in other words which
data point is the furthest away from any
centroid
so that's the basic that's the basic
algorithm so let's look and see how we
actually do that in tensorflow so it
looks a lot like numpy except in places
you would expect to see NP we see here
and then we see the API is a little
different but not too different right so
to get a random number we can just use
random uniform we can tell it what type
of random number we want so we want a
random int because we're trying to get a
random index so which the choose a
random data point it's going to be
between 0 and the amount of data points
we have
so that gives this is some random index
we can now go ahead and index into our
data now you'll notice that credits
include V data so what is V data when we
said that when we set up this k-means in
the first place the data was sent in as
a numpy array and then I call TS
variable on it now this is the critical
thing that kind of lets us make
tensorflow feel more like paper once I
do this data is now basically copied to
the GPU and so when I'm calling
something using V data I'm calling this
the GPU object okay now there's one
thing problematic are to be aware of
which is that the copying does not
actually occur when you write this the
copying occurs when you write this okay
so anytime you call TS variable if you
then try to run something using that
variable you'll get back an
uninitialized variable error unless you
call this in the meantime
okay so this is kind of like a
performance stuff intensive flow where
they try to try to say okay well you can
like set up lots of variables at once
and then call this initializer and we'll
do it all at once for you
okay so
earlier on we created this k-means
object we know that in place in when you
create an object to calls underscore
underscore underscore underscore at such
a place and works inside that we copied
the data to the GPU by using TF variable
and then inside find initial centroids
we can now access that in order to
basically do calculations involving data
on the GPU
intends to flow pretty much everything
takes and returns a tensor alright so
when you create we call random uniform
it's giving us a tensor you know an
array of random numbers in this case we
just wanted one of them so we have to
use TF squeeze to take that tensor time
turn it into a scalar because then we're
just indexing into here to get a single
item back
so now that we've got that single open
back we're then expand it back again
into a tensor because inside our loop
remember this is going to be a list of
initial centroids that's just that this
list happens to be of length one at the
moment
so one of these tricks in
making tensorflow feel more like a torch
is to use standard Python loops so in a
lot of tensorflow code where it's kind
of you know more serious performance
intensive stuff you'll see people use
like 10 to flow specific loops like T F
dot while or T F dot scan or map or so
close the challenge with using those
kind of loops is it's basically creating
a computation graph of that loop you
can't step through which you can't you
know use it in the normal Python it kind
of ways so we can just use normal loops
normal plays on words if we're careful
about how we do it okay so inside our
normal place and loop we can use normal
Python functions so here's a function I
created which calculates the distance
between everything in this tensor
compared to everything in this tensor
all right so all distances it looks very
familiar because it looks a lot like the
pay torch code we had right so we for
the first array for the first chancer we
add an additional access to access 0 and
for the second we add an additional
access to access one so the reason this
works is because of broadcasting so a
when it starts out is a vector now and B
is a vector now is with a a column or
add a a row what's the orientation of it
well the answer is it's both in it's
neither right it's one-dimensional so it
has no concept of what direction is
looking right so at this so then what we
do is we said expanding an ax is zero so
that's roads right so that basically
says to a ok you are now
definitely a row vector right you now
have one row and however many columns
same as before and then where else with
B we add an axis at the end right so B
is now definitely a column vector ax
that now has one
column and however many rows we had
before okay so with broadcasting what
happens is that this one gets broadcast
to this length and this one gets
broadcast to this length so we end up
with a matrix containing the difference
between every one of these items and
every one of these items so that's like
this kind of simple but powerful concept
of how we can do you know very fast
gpu-accelerated loops and less code than
it would have taken to actually write
the loop and we don't have to worry
about out of bounds conditions or
anything like that it's all done for us
so that's the trick here right and once
you've got that matrix because intensive
flow everything is a tensor we can call
squared difference rather than just
regular difference and it gives us the
squares of those differences and then we
can sum over the last axis so the last
access is the dimensions right so we're
just screwing your Euclidean distance
here and so that's that's all this code
does all right so this gives us every
distance between every Anand of a and
every element of B
okay so that's how we get to this point
so then let's say we've gone through a
couple of loops right so at that bar for
a couple of loops our is going to
contain a few initial centroids so we
now want to basically find out for every
point how far away is it from its
nearest initial centroid
so when we go reduce men
with access equal zero then we know that
that's going over the axis here because
that's what we put into our or distances
function so it's going to go through
like it's reducing across that into that
axis so it's actually reducing across
our centroids so at the end of this it
says alright this is for every piece of
our data how far it is away from its
nearest centroid okay and that returns
the actual distance right because we
said do the actual min so there's a
difference between men and argh
the argh version so arc max then says
okay now go through all of the points we
now know how far away they are from
their closest centroid and tell me the
index of the one which is furthest away
right so Arg max is a super handy
function we used it quite a bit in part
one of the course but it's well worth
making sure we understand how it works
I think intensive flow there I think
they're getting rid of these reduced
underscore prefixes I'm not sure I think
I read that somewhere so in some version
you may find this is called mean rather
than reduced min I certainly hope they
are for those of you who don't have such
a computer science background a
reduction basically means taking
something in a higher dimension and
squishing it down into something that's
a lower dimension for example summing a
vector entering into it into a scalar
this quarter reduction so it was a very
tensorflow API assuming that everybody's
a computer scientist and that you
wouldn't book for me and you would look
for reduce underscore mean
so that's how we got that index and so
generally speaking you know you have to
be a bit careful of data types I
generally don't really notice about data
type problems until I get the error but
like if you get an error that kind of
says oh you passed in 64 into something
that expected a 1032 you can always just
cast things like this okay so you need
to index something within 32 so we just
have to cast it and so this returns the
extra point right append and then this
is very similar to numpy stacking
together the initial centroids to create
them a tensor of them okay
so the code doesn't look at all weird or
different but it's important to remember
that when we run this code nothing
happens
okay other than that it creates a
computation graph so when we call
KDOT find initial centroids nothing
happens but because we're in an
interactive session we can now call eval
and that actually runs it right and it
runs it and it actually takes the data
that's returned from that and copies it
off the CPU and put that's very off the
GPU and puts it back in the CPU as an
umpire array so it's important to
remember that after call of eval we now
have an actual genuine regular numpy
array here and this is the thing that
makes us be able to write code that
looks a lot like pi torch code because
we now know that we can take something
that's an umpire array and turn it into
a GPU tensor like that and we can take
something that's a GPU tensor and turn
it into an umpire array like that so I
don't know I suspect this might um
despite makeup tensorflow
developers shake at how horrible this is
it's not you know really quite the way
you have to do things I think but it's
yeah it's super easy and it seems to
work pretty well um this approach where
we're calling eval you're doing it be a
bit careful if this was like inside a
loop that we were calling the eval and
we were copying back a really really big
chunk of data to the GPU and the CPU
again and again and again that would be
a performance nightmare all right so you
just you do need to kind of think about
what's going on as you do it so we're
looking side the in away from the moment
and just check anyway the results pretty
fantastic as you can see this this
little hacky heuristic and does a great
job and you know it's a hacky heuristic
I've been using for decades now and it's
a kind of thing which often doesn't
appear in papers in this case of similar
hacky heuristic did actually appear in a
paper in 2007 and even better one
appeared just last year but it's always
worth thinking about like how can i pre
process my data to kind of create get it
close to where I might want it to be and
often these kind of approaches are
useful there's actually I don't know if
we have time to maybe talk about it
someday but there's a probe to doing TTA
principal components analysis which has
a similar flavor basically finding
random numbers and finding the farthest
numbers away from them so it's a good
general technique actually all right so
we've got our initial centroids what are
we doing next
well what we do next is we're going to
be doing more computation intensive flow
with them so we want to copy them back
to the GPU
okay and so
copied them to the GPU before we do an
eval or anything later on we're going to
have to make sure we go global variable
initializes run
the question you explained what happens
if you don't create interactive session
so what the tensorflow authors decided
to do in their wisdom was to generate
their own whole concept of namespaces
and variables and whatever else so
rather than using pythons
there's tensor clothes and so a session
is basically a kind of like a named base
that holds you know the computation
graphs and the variables and so forth
you can and then there's this concept of
a context manager which is basically
where you have a wizz clause in Python
and you say like with this session now
you're going to do stuff in this
namespace and then there's a concept of
a graph you can have multiple
computation graphs you can say with this
graph you know create these various
computations where it comes in very
handy is if you want to say like run
this graph on this GPU or you know stick
this variable on that CPU so without an
interactive session you basically have
to create that session you have to say
which session to use using a wisk laws
and then like there's many layers of
that so within that you can then create
name scopes variable scopes and blah
blah blah so then the annoying thing is
the vast majority of tutorial code out
there uses all of these concepts right
it's as if like all of python 0 and
variables and modules doesn't exist and
you use tensorflow for everything so I
wanted to show you that you don't have
to use any of these concepts pretty much
like thank you for the question ok hey I
haven't fight
but it's thinking goodness but have you
tried so because your whatever there's
six clusters up there um and if you have
given if you have initially said I have
seven clusters or eight clusters but you
refine that see you hit your six sheets
all the sudden start getting two codes
are very close to previous existing
control so it seems like you could come
how intelligently define a width of a
cluster or look for a jump and things
dropping down and how far apart they are
on the cluster
yeah and programmatically come up with
the weighting decide the number yeah
yeah I think you could you know maybe
then you're using k-means I don't know
like yeah I think it's a fascinating
question I haven't seen that done there
are certainly papers about figuring out
the number of clusters and k-means so
maybe during the week you check one out
what it's a tends to flow that'll be
that'll be really interesting and i just
wanted to follow up what you said about
session to kind of emphasize that with a
lot of tutorials you could make the code
simpler by using an interactive session
in a jupiter notebook instead yeah I
remember when Rachel was going through a
tensor flow crossed a while ago and she
kept on banging her head against the
desk with sessions and variables cots
and whatever else and we kind of yeah
that was part of what led us to think
okay let's let's simplify all that all
right so I'm step one is to take our
initial centroids and copy them onto the
GPU so we now have a symbol representing
those so the next step in the k-means
algorithm is to take every point and
assign them to a cluster which is
basically to say for every point which
which which of the centroids is the
closest so that's what assigned to
nearest does we'll get to that in a
moment but let's pretend we've done it
this will now be a list
of rich centroid is the closest or every
data point so then we need one more
piece of tensor flow concepts which is
we want to update an existing we want to
update an existing variable with some
new data and so we can actually call
update centroids to basically do that
updating and I'll show you how that
works as well so basically the idea is
that we're going to loop through doing
this again and again and again but when
we just do it once you can actually see
it's nearly perfect already so it's a
pretty powerful pretty powerful idea as
long as your initial cluster centers are
good so let's see how this works assign
the nearest
it's a single line of code
now the reason is a single line of code
is we already have the code to find the
distance between every piece of data and
its centroid
now rather than calling TF reduce min
which returned the distance to its
nearest centroid we call TS dot argh men
to get the index of its nearest centroid
so generally speaking the the hard bit
of doing this kind of highly vectorized
code is figuring out this number which
is what access are we working with right
and so it's a good idea to actually like
write down on a piece of paper you know
for each of your 10 sores it's like it's
time by batch by row by column or
whatever let make sure you know what
every basis represents when I'm creating
these algorithms I'm constantly printing
out the shape of things and another
really simple trick that a lot of people
don't do this is make sure that your
different dimensions actually have
different sizes so when you're playing
around with setting things don't have a
batch size of ten and an N of ten and
the number of dimensions of ten right
but I find it much easier to think of
real numbers so like have a batch size
of 8 and an ad of can and a
dimensionality of four right because
every time you print out the shape
you're finding out exactly what
everything is okay so this is going to
return the nearest indices so then we
can go ahead and update the centroids so
here is update centroids and suddenly we
have some crazy function and this is
where tensorflow is super handy it's
full of crazy functions and if you know
the computer science term for the thing
you're trying to do it generally has
it's generally called that right and so
it's the only other way to find it is to
do lots and lots of searching through
the documentation so in general taking a
set of data and sticking it into
multiple chunks of data according to
some kind of criteria it's called
partitioning in computer science so I
got a bit lucky when I first looked for
this I googled the tensor flow
petition and bang this thing pops up so
let's take a look at it and this is
where like reading about GPU programming
in general is very helpful because in
GPU programming there's this kind of
smallish subset of things which
everything else is built on and one of
them is partitioning
[Music]
okay so here we have TF dynamic
partition partition the data into some
number of partitions using some indices
and generally speaking it's easier to
just look at some code so here's our
data we're going to create two
partitions they're calling them clusters
and it's going to go like this
d-rose partition zeros first first zeros
so 10 will go to the zeroth partition 20
will go to the zeroth partition 30 will
go to the first partition okay this is
exactly what we want right so this is
the nice thing is that there's a lot of
these you can see all this stuff right
there's so many functions available
often there's the exact function you
need and here it is right so we just
take our list of indices convert it to
os/2 in 32 s Parfitt our data the
indices and the number of clusters and
we're done right this is now a separate
array basically a zipper tensor so each
of our clusters
so now that we have done that we can
then figure out what is the mean of each
of those clusters so the mean of each of
those clusters is our new centroid right
so what we're doing is we're saying okay
which points are the closest to this one
and we're kind of going okay these
points are the closest to this one
okay what's the average of those points
right that's all that happens from here
to here
okay so that's taking the mean of those
points
and then we can basically see okay
that's our new partition that's our new
add new clusters so then just join them
all together concatenate them together
okay so
except for that dynamic partitions well
I mean in fact including that dynamic
conditions it was incredibly simple but
it is incredibly simple because we had a
function that did exactly what we wanted
so because we assigned a variable up
here we have to call initializer but run
and then of course before we can do
anything with this tensor we have to
call eval to actually call the
computation graph and copy it back to
our CPU okay so that's all those tips
so then we want to replace the contents
of current centroids with the contents
of updated centroids and so to do that
we can't just say equals everything's
different intensive law you have to call
dot assign right so this is the same as
basically saying current centroids
equals updated centroids but it's
creating a computation graph that
basically does that assignment on the
GPU how can we extrapolate this to other
non numeric data types such as words
images
well they're all numeric data types
really so an image is absolutely a
numeric data type so it's just a bunch
of pixels you just have to decide what
distance measure you want which
generally just means deciding you're
probably using you city and distance but
are you doing it in pixel space or
you're picking one of the activation
layers in a neural net for words you
would create a word vector for your webs
there's nothing specifically
two-dimensional about this it's working
as many dimensions as we like and and
that's really the whole point and I'm
hoping that maybe during the week some
people will start to play around with
some higher dimensional data sets to get
a feel for how this works particularly
if you can get it working on CT scans
that would be fascinating using the five
dimensional clustering we talked about
okay so to use what it looks like in
total if we weren't using an interactive
session
you basically say where's TF session
let's create the session but as default
that sets it to the current session and
then within the width block we can now
run things and then Kay don't run
there's all the stuff we just saw so if
we could okay don't run here it is
right so Kay don't run does all of those
steps so this is how you can create a
complete computation graph in tensor
flow using a notebook you do each one
one step at a time once you put it
working you put it all together right so
you can see find initial centroids eval
put it back into a variable again
assigned a nearest at the centroids
because we created a variable in the
process there we didn't have to rerun
global variable initializer we could
have avoided this I guess by not calling
eval and just treating this as a
variable the whole time but it does
is fresh lime and then we just look
through a bunch of times
calling centroid sort of sign updated
set droids
oh I think I see a bug what we should be
doing after that is then calling up site
centroids each time so there you go
I'll fix that during the week and then
the nice thing is because I've used a
normal place and full loop here and I'm
calling eval each time it means I can
check
Oh have have any of the cluster
centroids moved and if they haven't then
I will stop working right so it makes it
very easy to kind of create dynamic for
loops which could be quite tricky
sometimes with tensorflow otherwise okay
so that is the the tensorflow
algorithm from end to end
Rachel you want to pick out an ano your
question
so actually I kind of am helping start a
company the I don't know if you've seen
my talks on ted.com that I kind of show
this demo of this interactive labeling
tool a friend of mine said that he
wanted to start a company to actually
make that and commercialize it
so I guess my short answer is I'm
helping somebody do that so I think
that's pretty cool
more generally I've mentioned before I
think that best thing to do is always to
scratch an edge so pick whatever you've
been passionate about or something
that's just driven you crazy and you
know fix it if you have the benefit of
being able to take enough time to do
absolutely anything you want I felt like
the three most important areas for
applying deep learning when I last
talked which was two or three years ago
were medicine robotics and satellite
imagery because at that time computer
vision was the only area that was
remotely maturer really for machine
learning deep learning and those three
areas or were areas that very heavily
used computer vision or could heavily
use computer vision and were potentially
very large markets medicine is probably
the largest industry in the world I
think it's three trillion dollars in
America alone robotics isn't currently
that large but at some point it probably
will become the largest industry in the
world if you know everything we do
manually is replaced with automated
approaches and satellite imagery is
basically used by military intelligence
so you have some of the biggest budgets
in the world so yeah I guess those three
areas take it going oh no I got some
higher weather fish okay well next time
alright I know it's like a break soon
before I do I might just introduce what
we're going to be looking at next so
we're going to start on our NLP and
specifically translation deep dive and
we're going to be really following on
from the end-to-end memory networks from
last week the one of the things that I
find kind of most interesting and was
challenging and setting up this course
is coming up with good problem sets
which are like hard enough to be
interesting and easy enough to be
possible and often other people already
done that so I was lucky enough that
somebody else had already shown a
example of using sequence tool sequence
learning for what they called spelling
bee and basically we start with this
thing called the CMU pronouncing
dictionary which has things that look
like this the wiki followed by a
phonetic description of how to read the
where key so the way these work this is
actually specifically an American
pronunciation dictionary the continents
pretty straightforward the vowel sounds
have a number at the end showing how
much stress is an h1 right so 0 1 or 2
so in this case you can see that the
middle one is where most of the stress
is so it's risky
so here is the letter A and it is
pronounced ah okay so the goal that
we're going to be looking out after the
break is to do the other direction which
is to start with how do you say it
I'm turn it into how do you spell it um
this is quite a difficult question
because though English is really weird
to spell and the number of phonemes and
will necessarily match the thumb the
number of letters so this is going to be
where we're going to start and then
we're going to try and solve this puzzle
and then we'll use the solutions in this
puzzle to try and learn to translate
French into English using the same basic
idea so let's have a ten minute break
and we'll come back at 7:40 so just to
clarify this will make sure everybody
understands the problem we're solving
here so the problem we're solving is
we're going to be told here is how to
pronounce something okay and then we
have to say okay here it said a speller
all right so this is going to be our
input and this is going to be our target
so this is like a translation problem
that's writ simpler
have pre-trained phoneme vectors or pre
change letter vectors so they'd have to
do this by building a model I'm going to
have to create some embeddings of arrow
so in general the first steps necessary
to create an NLP model tends to look
very very similar I feel like I've done
them in a thousand different ways now
and at some point I really need to
abstract the cell laughs into us into a
simple set of functions that we use
again and again and again but let's go
through it and if you've got any
questions about any of the code or steps
or anything let me know
um so the basic pronounciation
dictionary is just a text file and I'm
going to just grab the lines which are
actual words so they have to start with
a letter now something which I have
actually it's gonna match that okay so
we're going to go through every line of
the text file here's the handy things
that a lot of people don't realize you
can do in Python when you call open that
returns a generator which lists all of
the lines so I see if you just go for L
in open blah that's now looping through
every line in that file okay so I can
then say filter those which start with a
which start with a lowercase letter okay
so sorry boo start with an uppercase
letter they're all uppercase and then
strip off any white space and spirit on
white space so that's the basically the
steps necessary to separate out the word
from the pronunciation and then the
pronunciation is just white space
delimited so we can then fit that and
that the steps necessary to get the word
and the pronunciation as a set of
phonemes so as we tend to pretty much
always do with these language models we
next need to get a list of like water
all of the vocabulary items so in this
case the vocabulary items are the other
possible phonemes so we can create a set
of every possible phoneme and then we
can sort it and what we always like to
do is to get an extra an extra character
or an extra object in position zero
because remember we use zero for padding
right so that's why I stick I'm going to
use underscore is our special padding
letter here so let's take an underscore
at the front so here are the first five
phonemes
this is our special padding one which is
going to be index zero and then there's
an R with three different level stress
and so forth okay now the next thing
that we can to do anytime we've got a
list of vocabulary items is to create a
list in the opposite direction so we go
from phoneme to index we
just a dictionary where we enumerate
through all of our phonemes and put it
in the opposite order
so from phoneme to index now we've used
this approach 2,000 times before but
it's going to make sure everybody
understands that when you use enumerate
in Python it doesn't just return each
phoneme but returns a tuple that
contains the index of the phoneme and
then the phoneme itself so that's the
key and the value so then if we go value
comma key that's now the phoneme
followed by the index and so if we turn
that into a dictionary we now have a
dictionary which you can give it a
phoneme and return it and index here's
all the letters of English again with
our special underscore at the front and
we've got one extra thing we'll talk
about later which is asterisks so that's
a list of letters and so again to go
from letter to letter index we just
create a dictionary which reverses it
again okay so now that we've got our
phoneme to index and letter to index we
can use that to convert this data into
numeric data right which is like what we
always do with these language models we
end up with just a list of indices we
can pick some maximum length word so I'm
just going to say 15 and so we're going
to create a dictionary which maps from
each word to a list of phonemes we're
going to get the indexes for them yes
Rachel okay so this dictionary
comprehension is a little bit awkward so
I thought this would be a good
opportunity to talk about dictionary
comprehensions and list comprehensions
for a moment so we're going to pause
this in a moment but first of all let's
look at a couple of examples of list
comprehensions so the first thing to
note is
when you go something like this the
string X Y Z or the string here - is
perfectly happy to consider that a list
of letters so the placing considers this
the same as being a list of X comma Y
comma debt so you can think of this as
two lists list of X Y Z and almost of
ABC so here is the simplest possible
list comprehension okay so go through
every element of a and put that into a
list so if I call that then it returns
exactly what I started with okay that's
not very interesting what if now we
replaced o with another list
comprehension okay so what that's going
to do is it's now going to return a list
for each list okay so this is one way of
pulling things out of sub lists is to
basically take the thing that was here
and replace it with a new list
comprehension and that's going to give
you a list of Lists now the reason I
wanted to talk about this is because
it's quite confusing in Python you can
also write this which is different so in
this case I'm going for each object in
our a list and then for each object in
that sub list and you see what's
different here I don't have to like in
square brackets right it's just all laid
out next to each other so I find it's
really confusing but the idea is you're
meant to think of this is just being
like a normal for loop inside a for loop
right and so what this does is it goes
through X Y Z and then ABC and then in X
Y Z to go to your each of x and Y and
Zed but because there's no embedded set
of square brackets that actually ends up
flattening the list okay so we just saw
um I think
we're about to see an example of the
square bracket version and pretty soon
we'll be seeing an example of this
version as well these are both used for
it's very useful to be able to flatten a
list that's very useful to be able to do
things with sub lists and then just to
be aware that anytime you have any kind
of expression like this you can replace
the thing at the here with any
expression you like right so we could
say for example we could say o dot upper
okay so you can basically map different
computations to each element of a list
and then the second thing you can do is
put an F here to filter it if o 0 take
all day
very wrong there sorry
oh thank you okay okay so that's
basically the idea you can create any
list comprehension you know you like by
putting computations here filters here
and optionally multiple lists of lists
here the other thing you can do is
replace the square brackets with curly
brackets in which case you need to put
something before a colon and something
after a colon the thing before is your
key nothing after is your value so here
we're going for oh and then there's
another thing you can do which is if the
thing you're looping through is a bunch
of lists or tuples or nothing like that
you can pull them out into two pieces
like so so this is the word and this is
the list of phonemes so we're going to
have the lowercase word will be our keys
in our dictionary and the values will be
lists
so we're doing it just like we did down
here and the list will be let's go
through each phoneme and go phoneme to
index okay so now we have something that
maps from every word to its list of
phoneme indexes all right so that's that
we can find out what the maximum length
of editing is in terms of how many
phonemes that are and we can do that by
again we can just go through every one
of those dictionary items calling
lengths on each one and then doing a max
on that okay so there is the maximum
length so you can see like combining
list comprehensions with other functions
is also powerful all right so finally
we're going to create our nice square
arrays normally we do this with CAD
sequences just through a change we're
going to do this manually this time so
the key is that we start out by creating
two arrays of zeros because all the
padding is going to be 0 right so if we
start off with all zeros and we can just
fill in the non zeros so this is going
to be our all of our phonemes this is
going to be our actual spelling that's
our target labels so then we go through
all of our and we've permitted them
randomly so randomly ordered things in
the pronunciation dictionaries and we
put in size input all of the items from
the pronunciation dictionary and into
labels we go lesser to indexed all right
so we now have one thing called input
once in court labels that contains nice
rectangular arrays padded with zeros
containing exactly what we want
okay I'm not going to worry about this
line yet because we're not going to use
it for the starting point
so anyway you see dick something just
ignore that for now we'll get back to
that later
trains have split is a very handy
function from SK learn that takes all of
these lists and splits them all in the
same way with this proportion in the
test set and so input becomes input
train and input test labels becomes
labels train and labels test so that's
pretty handy we've often written that
manually but this is a nice quick way to
do it when you've got lots of lists to
do
um okay so just to have a look at how
many phonemes we have a no vocabulary
there are 70 how many letters in our
vocab read is 28 that's us we've got
that underscore and the star as well
okay
so let's go ahead and create the model
so here's the basic idea
[Music]
the model has three parts the first is
an embedding right so the embedding is
going to take every one of our phonemes
okay max Lenti is the maximum number of
phonemes we have in any pronunciation
and each one of those phonemes is going
to go into an embedding right and the
look up for that embedding is the vocab
size for phonemes which I think was 70
and then the output you know is whatever
we decide what dimensionality who you
want and in experimentation I found 120
seems to work pretty well I was
surprised by how high that number is but
there you go it is we started out with a
list of phonemes
all right list of 13
this embedding we now have a list of
embeddings so this is like 70 and this
is like 120 okay so the basic idea is to
take this big thing which is all of our
phonemes embedded and we want to turn it
into a single distributed representation
which contains all of the richness of
what this pronunciation says later on
we're going to be doing the same thing
with an English sentence right and so we
know that when you have a sequence and
you want to turn it into a
representation one great way of doing
that is with an RNN now why an RN
because an RNN we know is good at
dealing with things like state and
memory right so when we're looking at
translation we really want something
which can remember like where are we
right so let's say we were let's say we
were doing this simple phonetic
translation the idea of you know have we
just had a C because if we just had a C
then the H is going to make a totally
different sound too if we haven't just
had a C right so an iron n we think is a
good way to do this kind of thing and in
general this whole class of models
remember is called seek to seek sequence
to sequence models which is where we
start with some arbitrary length
sequence and we produce some arbitrary
length sequence and so the general idea
here is taking that arbitrary length
sequence and turning it into a six size
representation using an hour a ten is
probably a good first step and you're
using dropout in your Alice TN is it
best practice to do drop out across time
you
[Music]
so okay so looking ahead I'm actually
going to be using quite a few layers of
RNN so to make that easier I've still in
drawing mode so to make that easier
we've created a get RNN function which
just and so we can you can put anything
you like here GRU or LS TM or whatever
and yes indeed I am using drop out the
kind of drop out that you use in our in
an R and N is slightly different to
normal drop out it turns out that if the
particular thing that you drop out it's
best to have some the same things at
every time step in an RNN there's a
really good paper that explains why this
is the case and shows that this is the
case so this is why there's a special
drop out parameter inside the air and in
and clear us it does its proper RNN
style drop out so yeah so we'll you know
I put in a tiny bit of drop out here and
if it turns out that we over theater we
can always increase it if we don't we
could always turn it to zero so so what
we're going to do is yes Rachel I want
more question about that
can you explain consume less than equals
GPU so yeah always do that they're
deeply I don't know if you remember but
when we looked at like doing harridans
from scratch last year we learnt that
you could like actually combine the
matrices together and led to a single
matrix computation if you do that it's
going to use that more memory but it
allows the GPU to be more highly
parallel so basically if you look at the
case documentation or Oteri's of
different things you can use but since
we're using a GPU you probably always
want to say consume less equals GPU
okay the other thing that we learned
about last year is bi-directional arrow
names and maybe the best way to come at
this is actually to go all the way back
and remind you how RNs work we haven't
done much revision but it's been a while
since we put our an enzyme at the detail
so just remind you this is kind of our
drawing of a totally basic neural net
square is input Circle is intermediate
activations hidden and triangles output
and arrows represent affine
transformations with nonlinearities we
can then have multiple copies of those
to create deeper convolutions for
example and so the other thing we can do
is actually we can have inputs going in
at different places so in this case if
we were trying to predict the third
character from first two characters we
can use a totally standard neural
network and actually have input coming
in at two different places and then we
realized that we could kind of make this
arbitrarily large but what we should
probably do then is make everything
where an input is going to a hidden
state feeds the same matrix so this
color coding remember represents the
same weight matrix so hidden to hidden
would be the same weight matrix and hit
into output and is a separate weight
matrix so then to remind you we realize
that we could draw that more simply like
this okay so our it ends when they're
unrolled just look like a normal neural
network at which some of the weight
matrices are tied together and if this
is not ringing a bell go back to I think
it's lessons 5 where we actually build
these weight matrices from scratch and
tie them together manually so that will
hopefully remind you of what's going on
now importantly we can then take one of
those our and ends and have the output
go to the input of another errand and
these are stacks arrogance and stacks
are and ends basically give us you know
richer computations in our recurrent
neural Nets and this is what it looks
like when we unroll it so you can see
here that we've got multiple inputs
coming in going through multiple layers
and creating multiple outputs but of
course we don't have to create multiple
outputs
you could also present networking you
could also get rid of these two
triangles here and have just one output
and remember in care out the difference
is whether or not we say return
sequences equals true or return
sequences equals false this one your
thing here is return sequences equals
true this one here is return sequences
equals false so what we've got is input
train has 97 thousand words each one is
of length 16 it's 15 characters long
plus the
the padding and then no sorry 1616
proteins long-haul stop plug possibly
with padding if necessary and then
labels is 15 because we chose earlier on
that I max length would be a 15 long
spelling so phonemes don't match two
letters exactly so after the embedding
so if we take one of those tens of
thousands of words remember it was
length
um
of length sub 4 phonemes length 16 all
right and then we're putting it into an
embedding matrix which is 70s by 120 and
the reason it's 70 is that each of these
phonemes contains a number between
naught to 69 okay so basically we go
through and we get each one of these
indexes and we look up to find it so
this is fives here then we find number
five here okay and so we end up with 16
by 120 and then part two of the question
says are we then taking a sequence of
these phonemes represented as 120
dimensional floating-point vectors and
using an RNN to create a sequence of
word to bec embeddings which we will
then reverse to actual words so we're
not going to use words avec here right
we're Tyvek is a particular sort of pre
trained embeddings we're not using pre
trained embeddings we have to create our
own inventing we're creating phoneme in
betting's so if somebody else would add
your own wanted to do something else
with phonemes and we like save the
result of this we could provide phoneme
Tyvek and you could download them and
use the fast a I pre train phoneme to
bec embeddings this is how embeddings
basically get created right the people
build models starting with random
embeddings and then
save those embeddings and make them
available for other people to use as
indian misinterpreting it but I thought
that question was getting it the second
set of embeddings when you want to get
back to your words right so let's wait
until we get there because we're going
to create letters not words and then we
just join the letters together so there
won't be any word to the next year so
we've got as far as creating our
embeddings and then we we've then got an
R and n which is going to take our
embeddings and attempt to turn it into a
single vector that's kind of what an RNN
does so we've got here return sequences
by default is true so this first r and n
returns something which is just as long
as we started with right and so if you
want to stack our and end on top of each
other every one of them is return
sequences equals true until the last one
isn't right so that's why we have false
here right so at the end of this one it
goes gives us a single vector which is
the final state the other important
piece is bi-directional and
bi-directional you can totally do this
manually yourself you take your input
and feed it into an R and N and then you
reverse your input and feed it into a
different narrative and then just
concatenate the two together
so care us has something which does that
for you which is called bi-directional
and bi-directional actually requires you
to pass it an R and n right so it takes
an RN n and returns two copies of that
are against ax on top of each other
one of which reverses its input and so
why is that interesting well that's
interesting because often in language
what happens later influences what comes
before for example in French the gender
of your local lawyer your definite
article depends on the noun
refers to so you need to go to look
backwards or forwards in both directions
to figure out how to match those two
together or in any language with temps
you know what verb do you use depends on
the tense and often also depends on the
details about the subject and the object
so we want to be able to both look
forwards and look backwards right so
that's why we want two copies of the RNN
one which goes from left to right and
one which goes from right to left and
indeed we could assume that when you
spell things I'm not actually sure how
this work but when you spell things
depending on what the latest dressers
might be or the later details of
athletics might be might change how you
pronounce things earlier on
as the bi-directional RNN can cat to our
limbs or does it's Jackson
it
if you end up with the same you end up
with the same number of dimensions you
had before but it basically doubles the
number of features that you have so in
this case we have 240 so I just had
doubled so and I think we had one
question here
so the currency level is about order
regarding to level of our men or lsdm
would be the input of the length of a
pizza box alone underscore drag that's
the 16 yeah okay the number 70 here is
it like all the possible characters of
yeah all about the phonemes we're going
from phonemes or you okay okay okay so
let's simplify this down a little bit
again and basically say we started out
with a set of embeddings and we've gone
through two layers well we've gone
through a bi-directional RNN and then we
feed that to a second Aaron in
right to create a representation of this
ordered list of fillings right and
specifically this represented a vector
okay
so X at this point is a vector okay
because return sequences equals false
that vector once we've trained this
thing the idea is it represents
everything that important there is to
know about this ordered list of phonemes
everything that we could possibly these
know in order to spell it okay so the
idea is we could now take that vector
and feed it into a new RNN or even a few
layers of RNN okay and that are an N
could basically go through and be with
returned sequences equals true this time
it could spit out at every time step
what it thinks the next letter in this
spelling is right and so this is how a
sequence to sequence works is one one
part which is called the n coda takes
our initial sequence
into a distributed representation into a
into a vector using generally speaking
some stacked iron ends then the second
piece called the decoder takes the
output of the encoder and passes that
into a separate stack of our it ends
with return sequences equals true and
those are n ends are taught to then
generate the labels in this case two
spellings
when I later kate's the english
sentences now in Caruth it's not
convenient to create an R and n by
handing it some initial state some
initial hidden status that's not really
how care ass likes to do things Tara
expects to be handed a a list of input
problem number 1 problem number 2 if you
do hand it to an R and n just at the
start it's quite hard for the RN to
remember the whole time what is this
word I meant to be translating right it
kind of has to keep two things that's
head one is like what's the word I meant
to be spelling and the second is like
what's the letter I'm trying to spell
right now so what we do with care us is
we actually take this whole state and we
copy it so
case we're trying to create a word that
could be up to 15 letters long so in
other words 15 time steps so we take
this and we actually make 15 copies of
it
okay and those 15 copies of our final
encoder state becomes the input to our
decoder R and n so it seems kind of
clunky right but it's actually not
difficult to do in chaos we just go like
this
we take the output from our encoder and
we repeat it 15 times all right so we
literally have 15 identical copies of
the same sector and so that's how Clara
expects to see things and it also turns
out that it's actually you get better
results when you pass into the R and n
the state that it needs again and again
at every time step so we're basically
passing in saying something saying we're
trying to spell this word we're trying
to spell this work we're trying to spell
this word we're trying to spell this
word and then as the R and n goes along
it's generating its own internal state
figuring out like what have we spelt so
far and what are we going to have to
spell next there's a question why can't
we have return sequences equals true for
the second bi-directional illa and not
bi-directional for the second LS TM we
only have one bi-directional calais TM
we don't want return sequence with
equals true here because we're trying to
create a representation of the whole
word we're trying to spell so there's no
point having something saying here's
reputation representation of the first
phoneme of the first two of the first
three or the first four or the first
five because we don't really know like
exactly which letter of the output is
going to correspond to which phoneme of
the input and particularly when we get
to translation it can get much harder
like some languages totally reverse the
subject and object order or put the verb
somewhere else so that's why we try to
package up the whole thing into a single
piece of state which has all of the
information necessary to build our
target sequence so remember these
sequence to sequence models are also
used for things like image captioning
right so with image captioning you
wouldn't want to have like something
that created a representation separately
for every pixel you know when you're
trying to capture an image you want a
single representation which is like this
is something that
how contains all of the information
about what this is the picture of or if
you're doing neural language translation
here's my English sentence that turns
into a representation of everything that
it means so that I can generate my
french sentence
we're going to be seeing later how we
can use return sequences equals true
when we look at tension models but for
now we're just going to keep seeing some
simple
the question is then I have an
underlying question regarding why don't
need discrete text problems the same way
we do images images have relationships
between pixels and shapes that are
complex and rely on positional
information why doesn't that work with
word or phoneme embeddings well it does
it absolutely does and indeed we can use
convolutional models but if you remember
back to lesson 5 we talked about some of
the challenges with that so if you're
trying to create something which can has
you know some kind of markup block like
this it has to both remember that oh you
know you've just opened up a piece of
markup you're in the middle of it then
in here you have to remember that you're
actually inside a comment block so that
at the end remember to close it this
kind of long-term dependency and memory
and stateful representation becomes
increasingly difficult to do with CNN's
as they get longer it's not impossible
by any means but our an ends are one
good way of of doing this but it is
critical that we start with embedding
because where else an image we are
already given you know valued numbers
that really represent the image that's
not true with text right so with text
where you have to use embeddings to turn
it into these nice numeric
representations are nervous and on
generic term she writes or specific
network uses lsdm yes but there's other
types of computers GRU
remember yeah yeah so careful are it in
Solaris support like yeah weird all the
ones we did in the last part of the
course so we looked in simple r NN g iu
and Emmas TM / so it looked like the LCM
which is the best preserved task no no
not at all um the GI is knows TM is
pretty similar
not worth thinking about too much okay
all right so at this point
here when
now have 15 copies of the 15 copies of X
right and so we now pass that into
two more layers of our den so if this
here is our encoder and this here is our
decoder now there's nothing we'd get
particularly in care us to say this is
an encoder to the decoder the important
thing is the return sequences equals
false here and the repeat vector here
right so like this what does it have to
do well somehow it has to take this
single summary and create some layers of
RN ends until then at the end we say
okay here's a dense layer okay and it's
time distributed so remember that means
that we actually have 15 dense layers
and so each of these dense layers now
has a soft max activation which means
that we basically can then do an Ag Max
on that to create our final list of
letters so this is kind of our reverse
embedding if you like
so the model is very little code okay
and once we've built it
and again if things like this are
mysterious to you go back and relook at
lessons four five and six remind you how
these embeddings work and how these kind
of time distributed dense works to give
us effectively a kind of reversed
embedding so that's our model starts
with our phoneme input into that time
tribute dead output we can then compile
that our targets are just indexes
remember we turn them into indexes so we
use this handy sparse categorical cross
entropy it's just the same as our normal
categorical cross entropy but rather
than one hot encoding we just skip the
whole one code encoding and just leave
it as an index
and we can go ahead and sit plussing in
our training data so that was our
rectangular data of the phoneme indexes
our labels and then we can use some
valid test set data that we set aside as
well
so we've hit that for a while I found
that the first three o'clock the loss
went down like this
the secondary epochs that went down like
this it seemed to be flattening out so
that's where as far as I stopped it so
we can now see how well that worked
now what I wanted to do was not just say
what percentage of letters are correct
because that doesn't really give you the
right sense at all okay what I really
want to know is what percentage of words
are correct so that's all this little
eval chaos function does it takes the
thing that I'm trying to evaluate called
predict on it it then does the AG max as
usual to take that softmax and turn it
into a specific number which which
character is this and then I want to
check whether it's true for all of the
characters that the real character
equals the predicted character okay so
this is going to return true only if
every single item in the word is correct
and so then taking the mean of that it's
going to tell us what percentage of the
words to get totally right
and unfortunately the answer is not very
many 26% so let's look at some examples
so we can go through 20 words at random
and we can print out all of the phonemes
with dashes between so here's an example
of some phonemes we can print out the
actual word and we can print out our
prediction so here is a whole bunch of
words that I don't really recognize
Turtle Bay shuns it should be spelt like
that oh we spelled it like that slightly
wrong so you can see some of the time
the mistakes it makes you pretty clear
so laro could be spelt like that but
this seems perfectly reasonable
sometimes on the other hand it's way off
and interestingly what I what you find
is that most of the time when it's way
off
I found a chance to be with the longer
words and the reason for that it's that
the longer the words so like this one
where it's terrible it's by far the most
phonemes I think one two three four five
six seven eight nine ten eleven phonemes
so if we had to somehow create a single
representation that contained all of the
information of all of those eleven
phonemes in a single vector and that's
hard to do right and then that single
vector got passed
I mean copied that passed to the decoder
and that was everything it had to try to
create this output okay so
that's the problem with this basic
encoder/decoder
method and indeed here is a graph from
from the model that means from the
tanker which originally
introduced attentional models I
this is the knurl translation what it
showed is that as the as the sentence
lengths got bigger the standard approach
which we're talking about the standard
encoder/decoder approach the accuracy
absolutely died so what these
researchers did was that they built a
new kind of R and n model coordinate
attentional model and with the
attentional model
the accuracy actually stayed pretty good
so goal number one the next couple
weapon system may not have a cold
anymore
yeah so basically we're going to finish
our deep dive into neuro translation and
then we're going to look at time theory
so that we're not specifically looking
at time theories it turns out that the
best way that I've found the time series
is not specific to time to use at all
that you're certainly reinforcement
learning was something I was planning to
cover but I just haven't found almost
any good examples of it actually being
used in practice to solve important real
problems and indeed when you look at the
you can see in the paper in the last
week or two about using evolutionary
strategies for reinforcement learning
basically it turns out that using
basically random search is better than
reinforcement learning that this paper
by the way like ridiculously overhyped
these evolutionary strategies is
something that I was working on over 20
years ago and in those days these are
genetic algorithms as we called them
used much more sophisticated methods
than sick minds brand new evolutionary
strategies so people are like
rediscovering these randomized Mediterra
sticks which is great that they're still
far behind where they were at forty
years ago but fire ahead of
reinforcement learning approaches so
given I try to teach things which I
think actually going to stand the test
of time I'm not at all convinced at any
current technique for reinforcement
learning to understand the test of time
so I don't think we're gonna touch that
part three yeah I think before that we
might have a plateau where where we do
practical machine learning for coders
talk about decision tree ensembles and
training test clips and stuff like that
um yeah and then yeah we'll see where we
are that yet I'm sure Rachel knows I'm
not going to stop doing this and
Harriet's it's really fun and
interesting and and we're really
interested in your ideas about how to
how to keep this going like by the end
of plat to you know you guys have put in
hundreds of hours you know maybe you
know on average maybe 140 hours put
together your own box written blog posts
done hackathons you know you're
seriously in this now
and in fact I could have say this week's
kind of been special for me like this
week's been a week where again and again
I've spoken to various folks of you guys
and heard about how like how many of you
have like implemented projects at your
workplace that have worked and are now
running and making your business money
or that you've you know achieved the
career thing that you've been aiming for
or that you've you know won yet another
GPU at a hackathon like you know or of
course the social impact seeing where
it's like all these transformative and
inspirational things that you know it's
it's gone from yeah we Rachel and I
started this we had no idea if it was
possible to teach people you know with
no specific required math background
other than high school math you know
deep learning to the point that you
could use it to build cool things we
thought we probably could because I
don't have that background and I've been
able to but you know I've been kind of
playing around with similar things for a
couple of decades so it was a bit of an
experiment and yeah this this week's
been a week that for me it's been fear
that the experiments worked so I don't
know what party is going to look like
it's I think it'll be a bit different
because it's like it'll be more of a
meeting of minds along stack group of
people who were kind of at the same
level and thinking about the same kind
of thing and so maybe it's more of a
yeah more of a ongoing keep out
knowledge up-to-date kind of thing it
might be more of us teaching each other
I'm not sure certainly interested to
hear ideas okay we don't normally have
three breaks but I think I need one
today and they were covering a lot of
territory so why don't we have a short
break and well I have a 34 yeah let's
have a short break and we put all the
last 20 minutes let's come back at em
8:40
okay thank you so attention models
attention models
so I actually I really like these
I think theory and fairly the paper that
introduced these it was quite
extraordinary paper introduced both GI
use and attention models at the same
time I think it might even be before the
guy had his PhD is remember correctly it
was just a wonderful paper very
successful
and the basic idea of an attention model
is it's actually pretty simple you'll
see here
see where does this happen
okay here is is a decoder right okay and
here's our embedding
okay and notice here
remember that my ghetto and and return
sequences equals true with the default
so the decoder now is actually spitting
out a sequence of states
now the length of that sequence is equal
to the number of phonemes okay and we
know that there isn't a mapping one to
one of phonemes de letters all right so
this is kind of interesting to even
think about how we're going to deal with
this now how we're going to deal with
sixteen states and the states because
they started with bi-directional state 1
both represent the combination of
everything that's come before the first
phoneme and everything has come after
and state 2 is everything that come
before the second phoneme and everything
has come after and so forth
okay so the states in a sense they're
all representing something very similar
but they've got a different focus you
know each one of these states at each
one remembers at length of 16 right so
it's one of these 16 states represents
everything that comes before everything
that comes after that point but with a
focus on on that phony okay
so what we want to do now is create a an
RNN
where the number of inputs to the iron n
needs to be 15 not 16 because remember
the length of the word we're creating is
15 right so we're going to have at 15
output time steps
and at each point we wanted to have the
opportunity to look at all of these 16
output states but we're going to go in
with the assumption that only some of
those 16 are going to be relevant but we
don't know which right so what we want
to do is basically create a so take a
basically take each of these 16 States
and to a weighted sum write sum of
weights times encoded fixed
right where these weights somehow
represent how important is each one of
those 16 inputs for calculating this
output and how important or each of
output and so forth right if we could
somehow come up with a set of weights to
every single one of those time steps
then we can replace the length 16 thing
with a single thing right and if it
turns out that output number 1 only
really depends on input number 1 and
nothing else then basically that input
those weights are going to be 1 0 0 0 0
0 right like it can it can learn to do
that but if it turns out that if it
turns out that output number 1 actually
depends on phonemes 1 & 2 equally that
it can learn the weights 0.5 0.5 0 0 0 0
0 so in other words we want some
function WI equals some function that
returns the right set of weights to tell
us which bit of the decoded input to
look at so it so happens we actually
know a good way of learning functions
what if we made the function a neural
net and what if we learn to it using SGD
why not so here's the paper neural
machine translation by jointly alert
learning to align and translate and the
great paper it's not the clearest in my
opinion in terms of understandability
but let me describe some of the main
pieces
okay so
here's the starting point oopsy-daisy
yes I have to do it
[Music]
okay let's subscribe how to
read this equation when you see a
probability like this you can very often
think of it as a loss function right the
idea of of SGG basically most time when
we're using it is to come up with a
model where the probabilities that the
model creates are as high as possible
for the true data and as well as
possible for the other data that's like
it's just another way of talking about a
loss function right so very often when
you read the papers where we would write
a loss function a people will see a
probability and what this here says
earlier on they say that y is basically
our our outputs very common for Y to be
an output and what is it saying is that
the probability of the output at time
step I write so at some particular time
step depends on to this bar here means
depends on all of the previous outputs
right in other words in our spelling
thing when we're looking at the fourth
letter that we're spelling it depends on
the three letters that we spelt so far
you can't have it depend on the later
letters that treating right so this is
basically a description of the problem
is that we're building something which
is time dependent and where the ice
thing that we're creating can only be
allowed to depend on the previous I
minus 1 things comma that basically
means and and it's also allowed to
depend on ok anything in bold is a
vector right a vector of inputs and so
this here is our list of phonemes right
and this here is our list of all of the
letters we've spelt so far ok so
so that whole thing right that whole
probability we're going to calculate
using some some function right and
because this is a neural net paper you
can be pretty sure that's going to turn
out to be a neural net and what are the
things that were allowed to calculate
with well we're allowed to calculate
with the previous letter that we just
translated
what's this the R and N hidden state
that we've built up so far and what's
this a context vector
the context vector the context vector is
a weighted sum of annotations H so these
are the hidden States to come out of our
encoder and these are some weights okay
so I'm trying to give you enough
information to try and pass this paper
over the weekend right so that's
everything I've described so far the
weights and now the nice thing is that
hopefully you guys have now read enough
papers that you can look at something
like this and skip over it and go oh
that's just softmax over time your
pattern recognition starts getting good
right like you start seeing something
like this you go oh that's a weighted
sum and you say something like this
together
oh that's soft mess like people who read
papers don't actually read every symbol
that I looks at it and goes softmax
weighted sum adjusted function okay got
it right as if it was like pieces of
code only this is like really annoying
clothes you can't look up in a
dictionary and you can't run and you
can't check it you can't debug it but
apart from that it's just like oh okay
so alright so the alphas are things that
came out of a softmax all right what
goes into the softmax all right
something called e the other annoying
thing about math notation is often you
introduce something and define it later
all right so here we are
later we define e what a equal to e is
equal to some function of what some
function of the previous hidden state
and the encoder state okay and what's
that function or that function is again
a neural network now the important piece
here is jointly trained jointly trained
means it's not like a again where we
train a bit of disseminator and a bit of
generator it's not like one of these
kind of manual attentional models where
we first of all figure out the modules
are here and then we zoom into them and
find them there jointly trained means we
create a single model in a single
computation graph if you like where the
gradients are going to flow through
everything so we have to try and come up
with a way basically where we're going
to build a standard regular RNN okay but
the iron N is going to use as the input
at each time step this right so we're
going to have to come up with a way of
actually cup of actually making this
mini neuron it's just a single one
hidden layer standard neuron it it's
going to be inside every time set in our
RN
so this whole thing
is summarized in another paper this is
actually really cool paper grammar as a
foreign language lots of things you
probably recognize here Geoffrey Hinton
who's kind of father of deep learning
earlier who's now I think chief
scientist or something at some director
of science at open AI Oreo venules done
lots of cool stuff this paper is kind of
neat and fun anyway it basically says
what if you didn't know anything about
grammar and you attempted to be able to
neural net which assigned grammar to
sentences it turns out you actually end
up with something more accurate than any
rule based grammar system that's been
built one of the most things they do is
to summarize all the bits and again this
is where like if you were reading a
paper the first time and didn't know
what an LS TM was and when oh and lsdm
is all these things that's not going to
mean anything to you right you have to
recognize that people write stuff in
papers I mean there's no point writing
Atlas TM equations in papers right but
it's basically you're going to have to
go and find the lsdm paper or find a
tutorial like learn about lsdm when
you're finished come back in the same
way they summarized attention okay so
they say we've used add or adapt to the
attention model from - if you go and you
have a look at - okay that's the paper
we just looked at all right but the nice
thing is that because this came a little
later they've done a pretty good job of
trying to summarize it into a single
page so during the week if you want to
try and get the hang of attention you
might find it good to have a look at
this paper and look at their summary and
you'll see that basically the idea is
that it's a standard sequence of
sequence model so a standard sequence
two tickets model means encoder hidden
states the final hidden state decoder
right
plus adding attention okay and so we
have two separate LS GMS an encoder and
a decoder and now be careful of the
notation encoded states are going to be
called H the decoder states h1 through
HTA
the decoder states are D which are also
going to call H ta plus 1/2 T a plus T B
so the inputs are 1 through T a and here
you can see is defining a single layer
neural net okay so we've got our decoder
States we've got our current encoder
state put it through a non-linearity put
it through another affine transformation
stick it through a soft Max and use that
to create a weighted sum ok so there's
like all of it in one little snapshot ok
so again like don't expect this to make
perfect sense the first time you see it
necessarily but hopefully you can kind
of see that you know these bits there's
all stuff you've seen lots of times
before so next week we're going to come
back and work through you know creating
this code and seeing that seeing how it
works
did you have some ritual we have two
questions one is what the way speed the
waiting's be heavily impacted by the
padding down to the input set sure
absolutely and specifically those
weights will say oh the padding is
always weighted zero it's not going to
take it very long to learn to create
that pattern and is a shared among all
IJ pairs or do we train a separate
alignment for each pair so a is not
trained a is the output of a suppose a
is the output of a soft max what trained
is w1 and w2 and note there capital
letters are matrices
right so we just have to learn a single
w1 and a single w2 but note that they're
being applied to all of the input so
it's all of the encoded states and the
current state of the decoder all right
and you know in fact easier is to just
abstract out this all the way back to
say it is
function right like this is the best way
to think that it's some function of what
some function of the current hidden
state and all of the decoder states okay
so that's that's the inputs to the
function and we just have to learn a set
of weights that will spit out the inputs
to ourself Mac you can see you have
another question okay great so I don't
feel like I want to study news so let's
take one final AMA before we go home
[Music]
advice on imbalance to dataset oh okay
unbalanced datasets yeah
there's not really that much clever you
can do about it you know basically if
you've got well a great example would be
young one of the impact talks talked
about breast cancer detection from
mammography scans and you thing called
the drain challenge had a little Mia
what was it like less than once
Teresa them 0.3% of the scans actually
had cancer so that's very unbalanced I
think the first thing you try to do is
such an unbalanced data set is ignore it
and try it try it and see how it goes
the reason that often it doesn't go well
is that the initial gradients will tend
to point to say they never have cancer
you know because that's going to give
you a very accurate model so one thing
you could try and do is to come up with
some kind of initial model which is like
you know maybe some kind of heuristic
which is not terrible
and gets it to the point where the
gradients are you know don't always
point to saying they never have cancer
but the really obvious thing to do is to
adjust your thing which is creating the
mini-batches so that on every mini batch
you grab like half of it as being people
with cancer and half of people being
without cancer so that way you know you
still go through lots and lots of epochs
it's a bit of a challenges that you're
going to the people that do have cancer
you're going to see lots and lots and
lots of time so you have to be very
careful of overfitting and then
basically it is kind of thing
between those two extremes so I think
what you really need to do is figure out
what's the smallest number of people
with cancer that you can get away with
you know what's the smallest number
where the gradients don't point to zero
and then create a model where let's say
it's 10% so create a model where every
batch mini-batch you create 10% of it
with people with cancer and 90% people
without train that for a while the good
news is once it's working pretty well
you can then decrease the size that has
the has cancer size because you're
already at a point where your models not
kind of pointing off to zero so you can
kind of gradually start to change the
sample to have less and less data get
the basic technique and so in this
example we're here you're repeating the
positive results over and over in your
sphere essentially is waiting more yeah
could you get the same results by just
throwing away one to the false base and
yeah you could do that and like that's
the really quick way to do it but that
way you're not using like the
information about the false stuff still
has information so yeah okay thanks
everybody have a good week
[Applause]