okay so welcome to less than 14 the
final lesson Fidel and Juno will talk at
the end about like what now but as you
can see from what's increasingly the in
happening what next is very much about
you're with us rather than us we're
leading you or telling you so you know
Vera community now and we can figure
these out together and obviously USF is
a one for Li to have yeah so for now
this is the last of these lessons and
one of the things that is great to see
this week was a terrific article in
Forbes that talked about declining
education and it was written by one of
our terrific students worth and focuses
on the great work of some of the
students that have come through this
course and yeah so I wanted to say thank
you very much and congratulations on
this great article I hope everybody
check it out really beautifully written
as well and terrific stories I found a
quite inspiring
so today we are going to be talking
about a couple things that we're going
to start with kind of time series and
structured data and time series I wanted
to start very briefly by talking about
something which I think you basically
know how to do this is a fantastic paper
because it is not side deepmind
nobody's heard of it it actually comes
from the Children's Hospital of Los
Angeles and believe it or not perhaps
the epicenter of practical applied AI
and medicine today is in Southern
California and specifically Southern
California pediatrics at Children's
Hospital of Orange County Chuck and the
Children's Hospital of Los Angeles
THL a socially with this paper comes
from actually has this thing they call
the PICU of a virtual pediatric
intensive care unit where so many many
years they've been tracking every
electronic signal about how every
patient every kid in the hospital was
treated and what all their ongoing kind
of sensor readings are and one of the
extraordinary things they do is when the
when the doctors there do rounds data
science has come with them like I don't
know anywhere in the world else in the
world that happens and so a couple of
months ago they released a draft for
this amazing paper where they talked
about how they pulled out all this data
from the EMR and from the senses and
attempted to predict patient mortality
now the reason this is interesting is
that when a kid goes into the ICU
if if the morals start saying this kids
looking like they might die then that
that's the thing that sets the alarms
going and everybody rushes over and
bucks you don't looking after them
and they found that they built a model
that was more accurate than any existing
model those existing models were built
on many years of deep clinical input and
are using RNN now this kind of
time series data is is what I'm going to
refer to as a signal
hi I'm Terry's data so let's say you've
got a series of like blood pressure
readings right so they might be you know
they come in and their blood pressure is
kind of low and it's kind of all over
the place and then suddenly it shoots up
right then and then you know in addition
to that maybe there's other readings
such as like you know at which points
they receive some kind of medical
intervention you know there's one here
one here and then there was like six
here and local so these kinds of things
generally speaking the state of health
at time T is probably best predicted by
all of the various sensor readings at t
minus 1 and t minus 2 and 2 months
really great so in statistical terms we
would refer to that as autocorrelation
what are correlation in correlation 35
years right and for this kind of signal
I think it's very likely that an RNN is
the way to go
obviously you could probably get a
better result using a bi-directional RNN
but that's not going to be any help to
you because you don't have to keep your
time period sentence right so be careful
of this verb data linkage issues and
indeed this is what this team at the VT
curve at Children's Hospital where
central incisors use an R and n to get
this state of the Amazon um I'm not
really going to teach you more about
this because basically you already know
how to do it ok that's it you can check
out the papers you'll see this almost
nothing special
the only thing which was quite clever
was that their their sensor readings
were not necessarily equally spaced so
for example you know did they receive
some particular medical intervention
clearly they're very widely spaced and
they're not equally spaced so rather
than having the RNN
have basically a sequence of
interventions that gets fed to the R and
N
instead they actually have two things
one is the signal and the other is the
time since the last signal is red so
each point at the R and if you the
errand is basically just some function s
it's receiving two things that's
receiving the signal at time T and the
value of T observe right what is the
time for the difference in time I wasn't
in the last one but that doesn't require
any different deep learning
that's just concatenating one extra
thing in director and they actually show
kind of mathematically that this makes a
certain amount of sense as a way to deal
with this and then they find empirically
that it does actually seem to work
pretty well okay so I can't tell you
whether this is state-of-the-art
anything because I just haven't seen you
know deep comparative papers or any
competitions or anything that really
have this kind of data which is weird
because a lot of the world runs on this
kind of data this kind of data doing it
effectively things with it super
valuable like you know if you're an oil
and gas company what's the drill head
telling you or what's the you know
signals coming out of the pipe telling
you or so on and so forth but you know
there we go
it's some not the kind of cool things
that the Google kids work on so you know
so I'm not going to talk more about that
that's how you can do time theories with
this kind of signal data you can also
incorporate all of the other stuff we're
about to talk about which is the other
kind of time series data for example and
there's a clerical competition which was
looking at forecasting sales well how
does that forecasting
sales using for each store at this big
company in Europe quad Ruffman based on
you know the date and what motions are
going on and what competitors doing this
kind of data is likely to look like kind
of this plastic kind of be you know
like that or maybe it'll have or maybe
it'll have some kind of trend to it okay
so these kinds of seasonal plan time
series are very widely analyzed by
economy trician and they're there
everywhere particularly in business if
you are trying to predict you know how
many widgets you have to buy next month
or you know whether to increase or
decrease your prices or you know all
kinds of operational type things tend to
look like this you know how all your
planes are going to be you know what
whether you should add promotions so in
circles so it turns out that the state
of the art for this kind of approach is
not necessarily some years and I run in
and I'm actually going to look at the
third-placed result from this
competition because the third-placed
result was nearly as good as places 1 &
2 but way way way way simpler and also
turns out that there's stuff that we can
build on top of for almost every model
of this kind and basically surprise
surprise
it turns out that the answer is to use a
neural network so you know I need to
warn you again what I'm going to teach
you here is very very uncool you'll
never read about it from deep mind or
open AI it doesn't involve any robot
arms it doesn't involve thousands of
GPUs it's the kind of boring stuff that
normal companies used to like make more
money or less money or satisfy their
customers so I apologize deeply for that
oversight
being said that in the 25 years more
I've been doing you know machine
learning work applied in the real world
98% of it had been this kind of data
whether it be when I was working in
agriculture I worked in wool macadamia
nuts and rice and we were figuring out
you know how how full our barrels were
going to be whether we needed more we
were figuring out you know how to set
futures markets prices where for
agricultural Goods whatever was in
mining and brewing which you know
required analyzing all kinds of
engineering data and sales data I've
worked in banking that revived looking
at kind of transaction account pricing
and and wrist control all of these areas
basically involve this kind of data so I
think although like no one publishes
stuff about this because you know
anybody who comes out of a Stanford PhD
and goes to Google doesn't know about
any of those things I guess it's
probably the most useful things of the
vast majority of people um and you know
excitingly it turns out that you don't
need to learn any new techniques at all
in fact to model that they've got this
third-placed result with a very very
simple model is basically one where each
different categorical variable was one
hot encoded and chucked into an
embedding layer the embedding layers
were concatenated and chapter a dense
player and then a second dense layer and
then through went through a sigmoid
function it would output layer so very
simple some the continuous variables
they haven't drawn here and these all
these pictures are going to come
straight from is paper which leads to
the folks that came third kinds we
actually wrote a paper about this the
continuous variables basically get
directly into the desk where okay so
that's that's the structure of the model
how well does it work so the short
answer is compared to K nearest
neighbors random forest from gPMs just
debase a simple neural network based on
all those approaches just with standard
kind of 100 in whatever but then the AE
is entity embeddings so adding in this
idea of using embeddings interestingly
you can take the embedding trained by a
neural network and fit it into a KNN or
a random forest or a GBM and in fact
using embeddings with every one of those
things is way better and all of those
things are any of anything other than
your own networks ok so that's pretty
interesting
and then if you use the embeddings
within your network you get the best
results still so this actually it's kind
of fascinating because training this
neural network taught me you know some
hours on a Titan X where else training
the GPM took and I think less than a
second like it was so fast I thought I'd
screwed something up and then I kept
tried running it it's like holy shit
it's giving accurate predictions so
gbm's and random forest so far so you
know in your organization you know you
could try taking everything that you
could think of as a categorical variable
and once a month train a neural net with
with embeddings and then store those
embeddings
in a database table until you know all
of your business users ok anytime you
want to create a model that incorporates
day a week or a store ID or customer ID
you know you can go grab the embeddings
and so they're basically like word
vectors but their customer that is in
store vectors and product vectors
so um I've never seen anybody write
about this other than this paper and
even in this paper they don't really get
to the the hugely important idea of like
what you could do with these inventing
what's the difference between a and B
and C is like different data types
flowing in a and B and C are the
prettiest yeah we're going to get to
that in a moment so yeah basically the
different things is like a might be the
store ID beat might be the product a B
and C might be today of which one of the
really nice things that they did in this
paper was to then draw some projections
some projections of some of these
embeddings and they just use teasley it
doesn't really matter what projection
method is but is them some interesting
ideas they talk on each state of Germany
deserve more votes and Germany and they
did a projection of the embeddings from
the state field okay and here is those
projections and I've drawn around them
different colored circles and you might
notice the different colored circles
exactly correspond to the different
colored circles on a map of Germany now
this work just random embeddings trained
with SGD trying to predict sales and
stores at ruffman and yet somehow
they've drawn a map of Germany so
obviously the reason why is because you
know things close to each other in
Germany have similar behaviour around
how they respond to events and you know
who buys what kinds of products and so
on and so forth so that's like crazy
fascinating here it's the kind of bigger
picture every one of these dots is the
distance between two stores and this
shows the correlation between the
distance in embedding space versus the
actual distance between the stores right
and so you can basically see that
there's a strong correlation
the
between things being close to each other
in real life and close to each other in
these SGD train embeddings you have a
couple more pictures those are all the
lines drawn on top of mine but
everything else is just there from the
paper on the left is days of the week
inventing and you can see the days of
the week better near each other have
ended up embedded close together on the
right each month of the year inventing
again same thing so and you can see that
you know the weekend is clearly separate
so that that's where we're going to get
to all right and I'm actually going to
take you through the end-to-end process
and I rebuilt the I rebuilt the
end-to-end process from scratch and
tried to make it in as few lines of code
as possible
because you know we just haven't really
looked at any of these structured data
type problems before so you know it's
kind of a very different process and you
know even a kind of a different set of
techniques
all right so we import the usual stuff
when you're trying to do this stuff
yourself you'll find a tree or four
libraries we haven't used before so when
you hit something that says module not
sound just pick install you can just get
install all these things if you were
pure piped we'll talk about them is
beginner okay so the data that comes
from Carol comes down a bunch of CSV
files and I wrote a quick thing to
combine some of those TSVs together and
this is one of those competitions where
people were allowed to use additional
external data as long as they were
shared on the forum so the data I'll
share with you I'm going to kind of
combine it all into one place
for you so I've commented these apps
because the the stuff I'll give you will
already run this concatenation process
so the basic tables that you're going to
get access to is the training set itself
a list of stores a list of which stage
each store is in a list of each the
abbreviation in the name of each stage
in Germany a list of data from Google
Trends so like if you've used Google
Trends you can basically see how Pixlr
keywords change over time I don't
actually and I actually know which
keywords they used but it'll somebody
found that there was in Google Trends
keywords that correlated well so we've
got access to those some information
about the weather and then a test set so
I'm not sure that we've really used
pandas much if at all yet so let's talk
a bit about pandas so pandas lets us
take this kind of structured data and
manipulate it in similar ways to the way
you would manipulated in a database
right so the first thing you do so
pandas the flight number items become MP
pandas tends to become pleading so PD
htsb is going to return a
a data frame okay so a data frame it's
like a database table if you use ours
called the setting so this red CSV is
going to return a data frame containing
the information from this CSV file and
we're going to go through each one of
those table names and read the CSV so
this will end up this list comprehension
is going to return a list of data frames
so I can now go ahead and display the
Hance so the first five rows from each
table and that's a good way to kind of
get a sense of what these tables are
okay so here's the the first one is the
trading set so to some store on some
date they had some level of sales to
some number of customers and they were
either open or closed
they are they had a promotion on all it
didn't matter what the holiday or it
wasn't for steak and school and then
some additional information of
annotation so that's the basic
information we have and then everything
else we join on to that so for example
for each store we can join up some
information some kind of categorical
variable what kind of store it is I have
no idea what this is it might be a
different brand or something what kinds
of products do they carry again just a
letter I don't know what it means that
maybe it's like summer electronics maybe
summer supermarkets
maybe summer full-spectrum how far away
is the nearest competitor and what year
and month did the competitor open for
business notice that sometimes the the
competitor open for business
quite linked in the game like like later
than some of the data were actually
looking at so that's going to be a
little bit confusing and then there's
thing called promo - which as far as I
understand it is basically is this a
store which has some kind of
standard promotion training going on and
so you can see here that these are this
store has standard promotions in January
April July and October so that's the
stores we also know if each store what
state they're in based on the
abbreviation and then we can find out
for each state what is the name of that
state and then for each this is slightly
weird this is a state abbreviation the
last two letters in this state during
this week
this was the Google trend data for some
keyword I'm not sure what key what it
was for this state name on this date is
the temperature dew point so forth and
then finally here's the test set it's
identical to the training set but we had
don't have the number of customers and
we don't have the number of sales okay
so like this is a pretty standard kind
of industry data set it's you know we've
got something we've got a kind of a
central table various tables related to
that and some things representing time
periods or plan points one of the nice
things you can do in pandas is to use
this pandas summary module and called
data frame summary for a table summary
and that will return a whole bunch of
information about every field so I'm not
going to go through all of it in detail
but you can see if example for the
number for the sales you know on average
fifty eight hundred sales standard
deviation of thirty eight hundred
sometimes sales heads all the way down
to zero sometimes all the way up to
forty one thousand there's no missing
details that's good to know
so this is kind of thing that's quick to
kind of scroll through and identify you
know okay competition token since month
is missing about a third at the time
it's good to know there's 12 unique
states that might be worth checking
because there's actually 16 things in
our state table for some reason
um Google trend data is never missing
that's good the ear goes from 2012
through 2016 the weather data is never
missing and then is our test set you
know this is the kind of things that
might screw up a model is like actually
sometimes the test set is missing the
information about whether that store was
open or not that's going to be careful
of okay so we can take that list of
tables and just see structure it out
into a whole bunch of different table
names find out how big the training set
is find out how big the test set is and
then you know with this kind of problem
there's going to be a whole bunch of
data cleaning and I want your picture
engineering and so you know neural nets
don't make any of that go away
particularly because we're using this
style of neural net where you know we're
basically feeding in a whole bunch of
separate continuous and categorical
variables so simplify things a bit to
take holidays into billions and then I'm
going to join all of these tables
together right so I always use a default
join type of an alpha join right so you
can see here this is how we join in
pendants we say table don't merge table
two and then to make a left outer join
how it will left and then you say okay
what's the name of the field that you're
going to join on the left hand side what
are the fields are going to join on the
right hand side and then if both tables
have some fields with the same name what
are you going to Suffolk so fields with
so the left hand side we're looking to
add any suffix on the right hand side
we'll put in underscore Y so you know
again I try to refactor things as much
as I can so we're going to join lots of
things let's create one function to do
the joining and then we can call a lots
of terms
was there any fields or referring to the
same value but named different king I
look at I saw no but it and it wouldn't
matter too much if there were because
you know when we run the model no
problem I think we have a question in
the forum would you liken the use of
embeddings from a neural network to
extraction of implicit features or can
they think of it more like what a PCA
would do like dimensionality reduction
let's talk about it more when we get
there but I mean basically when you deal
with categorical variables in any kind
of model you have to decide what to do
with them right and one of my favorite
data scientists or pair of them actually
who very nearly neighbors of Rachel and
mine have this fantastic R package
called V trees which has like a bunch of
state of the art approaches to to
dealing with stuff like categorical
variable encoding and so you know the
the obvious way to do categorical
variable encoding is to just do a 100
coding and that's the way nearly
everybody puts it into their gradient
boosting machines or random forests or
whatever but one of the things that V
tree does is it has some much more
interesting techniques so for example
such as John and Nina's package you know
you could look at the univariate mean of
sales for you know each day of week and
you could kind of encode day of week you
know using a continuous variable which
rested the mean and sales but then you
have to think about like oh well would I
take that mean from the trading set or
the test set or the validation set how
do I avoid
kidding you know there's all kinds of
complex statistical battlekey's to think
about that lead tree handles all this
stuff automatically now that is you know
that there's a lot of great techniques
that they're kind of complicated and in
the end they tend to make a whole bunch
of assumptions about like linearity or
univariate correlations or whatever
where else with embeddings we're using
SGG to learn how to deal with it you
know just like we do when we build an
NLP model or or a laboratory filtering
model you know we provide some initially
random embeddings and the you know the
system learns you know how the movies
vary and compared to each other or users
very or words dairy or in enough so you
know this is a to me the ultimate pure
technique and of course the other nice
thing about embeddings is we get to pick
the dimensionality of the embedding so
we can decide how much complexity and
how much learning are we going to put
into each of the categorical variables
and what we'll see how to do that in a
moment okay so one complexity was that
the because the weather yes the weather
uses the name of the stage rather than
the radiation of the stage so we can
just go ahead and join whether two
states to get the abbreviation the
Google Trends information about the week
you know week from from A to B we can
split that apart you can see here one of
the things that happens in the Google
trend data is that one of the states is
called ni or L so the rest of the data
is called HD konna ni so this is a good
opportunity to learn about pandas in
so pattered indexing first the time
you're watching uses spot ax method
right and the dot IX method is your kind
of general indexing methods and it's
going to take two things a list of rows
to select and a list of columns the flat
and you can use it in kind of pretty
standard intuitive way this is a lot
like numpy right this here is going to
return a list of boolean which things
are in this state and if you pass the
list of boolean to the pandas root
selector it will just return the rows
where that ball in is true so therefore
this is just going to return the rows
from Google trend where Google Translate
state is and I and then the second thing
we pass in is a list of columns in this
case we just want one column and one
very important thing to remember again
just like lump a you can put this kind
of thing on the left hand side of an
equal sign in computer science we call
it an L value so you can use it as an L
value so we can take this state field
for things which equal to NI and change
their value to this okay so this is like
a very nice simple technique that you'll
use all the time independence both for
looking at things and for changing
things excuse me we have a few questions
and one is in this particular example do
you think the granularity of the data
matter is in per day or per week it's
one better than the other yeah I mean I
would want to have the lower granularity
so that I can capture that I mean the
ideally you at one time as well it kind
of depends how the organization is going
to use it right like today what are they
going to do with this information it's
probably for like purchasing and stuff
so maybe they don't care about an hourly
level there clearly the difference
between Sunday sales and Wednesday sales
will be quite significant
yeah it's mainly a kind of business
context or domain understanding question
another question is do you know if
there's any work that compares for
structured data supervised DIMM beddings
like these two embeddings that come from
an unsupervised paradigm such as an
autoencoder it seems like you get more
useful for prediction embeddings with
the former case but if you wanted
general-purpose embeddings you might
prefer the latter yeah I mean I think
you guys are aware of my feelings that
orderly owners you know it's like giving
up in life you know you can always come
up with a lost function that's more
interesting than an autoencoder loss
notion basically I would be very
surprised if embeddings that came from a
sales model were not more useful for
just about everything there's something
from the unsupervised model that these
these things are easily tested and if
you do find a model that they don't work
as well with and you can come up with a
different set of supervisors embeddings
for that model I'm in a there's also
just to note that dot IX is deprecated
and we should use dot Logan said okay I
was going to mention pandas is changing
a lot and because I've been running this
course I have not been keeping track of
the recent versions of pandas so thank
you so that should be Google trend oh
look there's impendence there's a whole
page called advanced indexing methods I
don't find the pandas documentation
terribly clear to be honest but there is
a fantastic book by the author of pandas
called pison for data analysis there is
a new edition out and it covers pandas
done primarily of whatever yeah that's
the best way by far to actually
understand tenders to the documentation
is a bit of a nightmare and it keeps
changing so the new version has all the
new stuff it oh yeah with these kind of
indexing methods pandas tries really
hard to be intuitive which means that
like quite often you'll read the
documentation for these methods and it
will say like you know if if you pass it
a boolean it'll behave in this way if
you pass it a float this way if it's an
index
it this way unless this other thing
happens and like I don't find it
intuitive at all because in the end I
need to know how something works in
order to use it correctly and so you end
up having to remember this huge list of
things right so this is I think pandas
is great but this is one thing to be
very careful of is to really make sure
you understand how all these indexing
methods actually work and I know
Rachel's laughing because you've been
there and you know probably laughing in
Augusta or you want to go through
another question when you use embeddings
from a supervised model in another model
do you have to worry about data leakage
yes you always have to worry about their
leash I think that's a great point you
know I I think I've anything to add to
that you can figure out easily enough of
his data leakage so yeah but so it's a
great question and you need to
definitely think to think about okay so
there's this kind of standard set of
steps that I take for every single
structured machine learning model I do
and one of those is every time I see SH
I always do this but I always create for
more feelings the year the month of here
the week of year and the day of whim
this is um you know something which
should be like automatically built into
every data loader I feel it's so
important because you know these are the
kinds of structures that you see and
once every single baek's has got this
added to it you're doing great so you
can see that I add that into all of my
tables that have a date field and so
we'll have that for now on
so then we go ahead and do what with
these out of joints and you'll see that
the first thing I do after every outer
join is check whether the thing I just
joined with has any nodes but so like
even if you're sure that these things
match perfectly I still never ever do it
in a joint right through the outer join
and then check the Noles and that way at
anything changes ever or if you ever
make a mistake one of these things will
not be zero now if this was happening in
a production process you know this would
be this would be an assert this would be
you know emailing Henry at 2:00 a.m. to
say like you know something you're
relying on it's not working the way it
was meant to walk out so that's why I
always do it this way so you can see I'm
just basically joining my training to
everything else until it's all in there
together in one big thing okay so that
table everything drawing together is
called join and then I do a whole bunch
more thinking about what I'll enjoy the
thinking of the people that won this
competition and I replicated their
results from scratch you know think
about what are all the other things you
might want to do with these days so
competition open we notice before a
third of the time they're empty so we
just fill in the empties with some kind
of sentinel value because a lot of
machine learning systems don't like
missing values fill in the missing month
with some Sentinel value again keep on
filling in missing data so fill in a is
a really important thing to be aware of
retro is the filling in the month with
one isn't one and a real-valued it's not
a problem
the answer is yes it is the problem but
in this case they happen to know that
every time year is empty month is also
empty and we only ever use both of them
together so any model whether it be tree
based or neural net based or whatever is
going to take advantage of that of that
fact so yeah probably would have been
secretive differently innocence okay so
we don't really care actually when the
competitions door was open what we
really care about is how long is it
between when they were open and the
particular row that we're looking at you
know the sales on the 2nd of February
how long was it between second of every
2014 and when the competition opened so
you can see here we use this a very
important apply function which just run
the Python function on every row of a
data frame and in this case the function
is to create a new date from the opens
in here and the open since month we're
just going to assume that at the middle
of month and that's our competition open
sense and then we can get our days open
by just doing a subtract in
pandas every date field has this special
metrical DT property which is what all
the then you know days month year all
that stuff is sits inside this little DT
property now sometimes as I mentioned
the competition actually opens later
than the particular observation we're
looking at so that will gives us a
negative so if we replace our negative
to zero
um
we're going to use an embedding for this
so that's why we replace days open with
months open so we have less values yeah
I mean I didn't actually try replacing
this with a continuous variable I
suspect it wouldn't make too much
difference but you know this is what
they do in order to make the embedding
again not too big they replace anything
that was bigger than two years with two
years okay so there's our unique values
now every time you do something print
something out to make sure that the
thing you thought you did is what you
actually do it's much easier if we're
using Excel because like you see
straightaway what we're doing so in
Python you know this is the kind of
stuff that you have to really be
rigorous about checking your work at
every step you know when I build stuff
like this I generally make you know at
least one error in every cell so check
carefully okay do the same thing for the
promo days turn those into weeks yeah
okay so that's some basic pre-processing
you get the idea of how pandas works
socially so the next thing that they did
in the paper was some again some a very
common kind of time series feature
manipulation one to be aware of which is
they basically wanted to say okay every
time there's a promotion very time
there's a holiday I want to create some
additional fields to every you know for
every one of our training set roads
which is on a particular date which it's
like on that date how long is it until
the next holiday how long was it until
the previous holiday how long was it
until the next promotion how long is it
since the previous promotion so if we
basically create those fields you know
this is
this is the kind of thing which is super
difficult for any GBM or random forest
or neural net to figure out how to
calculate itself right it's not a you
know there's no obvious sort of
mathematical function that's going to
build on its own so we've this is the
kind of feature engineering we have to
do in order to allow us to use these
kinds of techniques effectively on time
series data so a lot of people who work
with time series data are particularly
in academia outside of industry they're
just not aware of the fact that the you
know the state of the art approaches
really involve all these heuristics
right you know separating out your dates
into their components turning everything
you can into durations before backwards
and also doing a bunch of you'll see in
a moment
running averages so you know when I used
to do a lot of this kind of work I had
you know a bunch of library functions
that I would run on every file that came
in and would automatically do these
things for every combination of dates
you know so this thing of like how long
until the next promotion how long the
previous promotion is not easy to do in
any database system pretty much or
indeed in pandas because generally
speaking these kind of systems are
looking for relationships between tables
but we're trying to look at
relationships between rows okay so I had
to create a tiny little simple little
class to do this so basically what
happens is let's say I'm looking at
school holiday right so I sort my data
frame by store and then by date and I
call this little function called add
elapsed school holiday after and what
does add elapsed to an elapsed is going
to create an instance of this class or
elapsed and it's going to be poor with
school holiday so what this class is
going to do we're going to be calling
this apply function again
so I'm just going to run them every
single row and it's got a call my
elapsed class yet
for every row so I'm going to go to
every row in order a store in order date
and then try to find how long has it
been since the last school holiday so
when I create this object I just have to
keep track of okay what field is it okay
school holidays initialize when was the
last time we saw a school holiday and
the answer is we have interested you
know initialize it's another number and
we also have to know like each time we
like cross over to a new store like when
we cross over means to all with exactly
reinitialized
so the previous store was zero so every
time we call catch we basically check ok
have we crossed over to a new store and
if so just initialize those are those
things back again and then we just say
ok if this a school holiday if so then
the last time you saw a school holiday
is today and then finally return how
long is it the train today and the last
time you saw a school holiday right so
it's basically this class is a way of
keeping track of kind of to memory about
like when do they last
see these observation so I've been by
this calling EF not apply it's going to
keep track of this to every single row
and so that I can call that for school
holiday after and before the only
difference being that I four before I
just sort my dates in descending order
state holiday and promo ok so that's
going to add in the end six fields how
long until and how long since the last
school holidays state holidays and
promotion and then there's a question
our two questions and one asking is this
similar to a windowing function look
what we're about to do a window resume
and then is there a reason to think that
the current approach would be
problematic with sparse data but
see why that I'm not sure I quite follow
along at all so we don't care about
absolute DS we care about time dentist
between events we care about two things
we can we do care about the date that
we've already let's hold out the it we
don't care about the like what year is
Earth whatever we could is yeah
and we also care about the elapsed time
between the the data and predicting
sales for and the previous and missed
appearances okay and then windowing
functions to do another room yes and for
the features that are time until an
event how do you deal with that given
that not you might not know when the
last event is in the data well all I do
is I've sort of sorted descending right
and then we initialize last with a lot
of number so basically when we then go
subtract here we are subtracted it tries
to subtract not a number will end up
with an all right so basically anything
that's unknown time because it's at one
end or the other is going to end up null
which is why we there is later on but
shortly and we're going to replace those
noises with zeros okay
pandas have this slightly strange way of
thinking about indexes but what to get
used to define at any point you can call
data frames octet index and pass in the
field you don't have to just kind of
remember what field you have as the
index because quite a few methods in
pandas use they're kind of currently
active index by default and of course
things will run faster when you do stuff
they're currently active index thumb and
you can pass multiple fields in which
actually end up with a multiple key
index
okay so the next thing we do is the
windowing function so a windowing
function in pandas we can use this
rolling it's like a rolling mean rolling
mean
that's whatever you like so this
basically said all right let's take our
data frame with the columns we're
interested in school holiday state
holiday and Provo and we're going to
keep track of like how many holidays are
there in the next week and the previous
week
how many promos are there in the next
week of previously so to do that we can
sort by date group by store and then
rolling will it be applied to each group
so within each group create a rolling 7d
son okay so it's kind of like you know
it's the kind of notation I'm never
likely to remember you know if it is
just look it up and this is how you do
like group by type stuff Candace's
actually has quite a lot of time series
functions when this rolling function is
one of the motions for one's you know
where the Kinney had a background with
the quantitative memory says directly
and so you know quads love their time
serious functions I think that was a lot
of the history of dependence so if
you're interested in time series stuff
you'll find a lot of times recess and
pendants okay one helpful parameter that
sits inside a lot of methods is in place
equals true that means that rather than
returning a new data frame with this
change made it changes the data frame
you already have and when your data
frames are quite big this is going to
save a lot of time in memory so that's a
good little trick to know about okay so
now we've merge all these together and
we can now see that we've got all these
after school holiday before school
holiday and our backward and forward
running means um and then we join that
up to our original data frame
and here we have our final result so
there it is
you know we ended up we started out with
a pretty small set of field from the
training set but we've done this feature
engineering and this feature engineering
is not arbitrary like although I didn't
create this solution I was just
reimplemented the solution that was came
from the competition so please get us
this is nearly exactly the set of
picture engineering steps I would have
done like it's just a really standard
way of thinking about a time series okay
so you know you can definitely borrow
these ideas pretty closely ok so now
that we've got that you know we've got
this this table we've done our feature
engineering we now want to feed it into
a neural network so to feed it into a
neural network we have to do a few
things the categorical variables have to
be turned into 100 coded variables or at
least in two contiguous integers and the
continuous variables we probably want to
normalize to a zero mean one standard
deviation there's a very little known
package called SK learn pandas and
actually I contributed some new stuff to
it for this course to make this even
easier to use if you use this data frame
mapper
from SK learn pandas as you'll see it
makes life very easy without it life is
very hard and because very few people
know about it about the jority of code
you will find on the internet makes life
look very hard ok so use this code not
the other code actually I was talking to
some of the students the other day and
they were saying like for their project
they were like feeling lots of code from
part one of the course because I just
couldn't find you know anywhere else
people writing any of
kinds of code that we've used like you
know the stuff that we've learned
throughout this course is in on the
whole not not code that lives elsewhere
very much at all so like feel you know
feel free to use a lot of these
functions in your own work you know cuz
I've really tried to make them the best
version of that function so one way to
do the embeddings and the way that they
did it in the paper is to basically say
for each categorical variable they just
manually decided what inventing
dimensionalities use they don't say in
the paper how they pick these
dimensionalities by generally speaking
things with a larger number of separate
levels tend to have more dimensions so
like there's I think there's like a
thousand stores so that has a big
embedding dimensionality where else
obviously things like promo or what
backward or they've week or whatever you
know have much smaller so this is this
dictionary I created that basically goes
from the name of the field to the
embedding dimensionality and Candice or
pose that you guys can use in your
models so then all I do is I say okay my
categorical variables is okay go through
my dictionary sort it in reverse order
of the value and then get the first
things in that so that it's going to
give me the keys from this in reverse
order of dimensionality and continuous
variables it's just a list okay just
make sure that there's no null so
continuous variables replace nulls of
zeros categorical variables replace
models with empty s and then here's
where we use the data frame member a
data frame mapper takes a list of tuples
a list of tuples with just two items in
the first item is the name of the
variable for this case I'm looking
through each categorical variable name
the second thing is a tuple is a class
or actually an instance of a class which
is going to do your
processing and there's really just two
that you're going to use almost all the
time two categorical variables SK learn
comes with something called label
encoder it it's really badly documented
and certainly misleading you documented
but this is just most this is exactly
what you want it's something that takes
a column figures out what are other
unique values that appear in that column
and replaces them with a set of
contiguous integers and so if you've got
the days of the week Monday through
Sunday it will replace them with zero
through zero through seven and then very
importantly this is critically important
you need to make sure that the training
set and the test set have the same codes
there is no point having Sunday be zero
in a training set and one in the test
set so it can't square actually
instantiating this this class here this
object is going to actually keep track
of which codes it's using and then ditto
for the continuous we want to normalize
them to 0 1 variables but again we need
to remember what was the mean that we
subtracted what was the standard
deviation we divided by so that we can
do exactly the same thing to the test
set otherwise again our models will need
nearly totally useless so the way the
data frame mapper works is that it's
using this instantiated object it's
going to keep track with its information
so this is basically code you can copy
and paste in every one of your models
right once we cut those mappings you
just pass those to a data frame mapper
and then you call dot fetch passing in
your data set
and so this thing now is a special
object which has a dot features property
that's going to contain all of the
pictures all of the pre-processed
features that you want so categorical
columns contains a result of doing this
mapping basically doing this label
encoding so yeah so it you know in some
ways the details of how this work
doesn't matter too much because you can
just use exactly this code and every one
of your models
continuous is exactly the same code but
of course continuous it's going to be
using standard Tacoma which is a
scikit-learn thing that turns it into a
zero mean one standard deviation and
variable so we've know about continuous
columns have all been standardized
here's an example of the first five rows
from the zero column for a categorical
and then ditto for a continuous okay so
you can see these have been turned into
integers and these have been turned into
numbers which averaged to zero and have
a standard deviation of one one of the
nice things about this data frame mapper
is that you can now take that object and
actually store it nicoleff and so now
you can use those categorical and
codings
and scaling parameters elsewhere
unpicking it you've immediately got the
same same parameters and for my
categorical variables you can see here
the number of unique classes and every
one okay so here's my thousand one
hundred doors and thirty one day to the
months and seven days of the week and so
forth
alright so that's the kind of key
pre-processing that has to be done
so here is their big mistake and I think
if they didn't do this big mistake they
probably would have won their big
mistake is that they went join join but
sales not equal to zero so they've
removed all of the rows with no sales
and over all of the roads where the
store was closed
why was its big mistake because if you
go to the rustman store sales
competition website and click on kernels
and look at the kernel that got the
highest rating this is another right one
so this kernel Laura Tori data analysis
Rossmann I'll show you a couple of
pictures here is an example of the store
store 708 and these are all from this
circle here as a period of time where it
was close to refurbishment this happens
a lot in Rossum storms you get these
periods of time when you get zeros to
sales what's in a row look what happens
immediately before and after right so in
the data set that we're looking at our
unfortunate third-place winners deleted
all of these right so they had no
ability to build a feature that could
find these so this store 7 away look
here's another one
whereas closed same thing so this turns
out to be super common and the second
place winner actually built a feature
and you know it's going to be exactly
the same feature we've seen before how
many days since they're closing and how
many days until when they're closing and
if they had just done that pretty sure
they would want so that was that big
mistake this um this kernel has
a number of interesting analyses in ER
here's another one which I think our
neural net can capture although it might
have been better to be explicit some
stores open on Sundays not most students
but some did and for those stores that
opened on Sundays their sales on Sundays
for far higher than on any other day
right I guess that's because in Germany
I guess not many shops open on Sundays
so something else that they didn't
explicitly do was create a like in store
open on Sunday field having said that I
stick the neural net may have been able
to put that in the embedding so like if
you're interested during the week you
could try and in this field and see if
it actually improves it or not certainly
be interested to hear if your try adding
this field like do you find that you
actually would win the competition
because this this Sunday thing this is
these are all from the same Cargill
kernel here's the day of week and here's
the sales of the box plot and you can
see you know normally on a Sunday it's
not that the sales in my China
so it's really explicitly just for these
particular stores ok so that's the kind
of visualization stuff which is really
helpful to do as you work through these
kinds of problems is July now I'll just
throw lots of pictures and those
pictures were drawn in are and you know
are is actually pretty good for this
kind of structured data so we have a
question so for categorical fields
they're converted by the numbers not
lose me in zero right they were kept
your kids you know Monday zero Tuesday
one whatever easy will send to neural
network just like we're going to get
there oh yeah yep we're going to use
embeddings just like we get with word
embeddings remember we turn every word
into a into a word index you know so our
sentences rather than being like
you know the dog ate the beans it would
be you know three six twelve two we're
going to do the same basic thing we've
done the same basically okay so now that
we've done our terrible mistake we've
now put still got eight hundred twenty
four thousand rows left as per usual I
made it really easy for me to create a
random example and did most of my
analysis with a random sample but can
just as easily not do the random sample
so now I put a separate sample version
of it
okay split it into training and test now
notice here the way I spit it into
training and test is not randomly and
the reason it's not randomly is because
in the cattle competition they set it up
the smart way the smart way to set up a
test set in a time series is to make
your test sets the most recent period of
time but if you choose random points
you've got two problems the first is
you're predicting tomorrow's sales where
you always have the previous day's sales
which you know is very rarely the way
things really work
and then secondly you're ignoring the
fact that in the real world you're
always trying to model you know a few
days or a few weeks or a few months in
the future that hasn't happened yet so
the way you want to set up if you were
building if you were setting up the data
for such a model yourself you would need
to be deciding okay how often am I going
to be running this model how long is it
going to take for those model results to
get into the field they used and however
they're being used in this case I guess
I can't really look like a month or two
alright so in that case I should make
sure there's a month or two gap between
you know or a month or two test set
which is the last bit right so you can
see here I've taken the last ten percent
of my validation set and it's literally
just is the first bit and here's the
last bit and since it was already sorted
by date this ensures that I have it done
the way I want I just wanted to point
out that it's tend to lead since your
public take a break then we sure will
okay so this is how you take that data
frame metal object we created earlier
and we caught fit in order to like learn
you know the transformation parameters
see you then call transform to actually
do it right so take my training set and
transform it to grab the categorical
variables and then the continuous creep
processing needs the same things my
continuous map so pre-process my
training set and grab my continuous
variables okay so that's nearly done the
only final piece is in their solution
they modified their their target so
there's their sales value and the way
they modified it was that they found
what is the highest amount of sales
right and they took along with that and
then they modified all of their y-values
to take the log of sales divided by the
maximum work or sales so what this means
is that if the Y values are going to
vary they're going to be no higher than
one and furthermore remember how they
had a long tail the average was five
thousand but the maximum was like
40-something thousand this is really
common right like most financial data
sales data so forth generally has a
nicer shape when it's logged that it
does not so taking the log is a really
good idea the reason that that as well
as taking the log they also did this
division and as it means that what we
can now do is we can use an activation
function in our neural net of a sigmoid
right which goes between Norton one and
then just multiply by the maximum log
and so that's
actually go to ensure that the data is
in the right scaling area I actually
tried taking this out and it actually
this technique doesn't really seem to
help and it actually reminds me of the
style transfer paper where they
mentioned they originally had like a
hyperbolic tanh layer at the end so
exactly the same reason to make sure
everything was black between Norton to
55 and actually turns out if you just
use linear activation it worked just as
well so interestingly this idea of using
sigmoids at the end in order to get the
right range doesn't seem to be that
helpful my guess is the reason why is
because for a sigmoid it's like really
difficult to get the maximum and I think
actually what they should have done is
they probably should have like instead
of using maximum they should have used
like maximum x 1.25 you know so that
they never have to predict one you know
but it's impossible to predict one
because it's a sigmoid someone asked is
there any issue in fitting the
pre-processors on the full training and
validation data shouldn't they be fit
only to the training set no it's fine
in fact to the categorical variables you
know if you don't insert the test set
then you're going to have some codes
that aren't there at all or else its
weight is going to be random which is
better than failing
[Music]
yeah as for deciding you know what to
divide and subtract in order to get a
zero one random variable it doesn't
really matter it's not it's there's no
leakage involved that's what you're
worried about
okay root mean squared percent error is
what the cattle competition use as the
official loss function so this is just
calculating it so before we take a break
we'll just finally take a look at the
definition of the model I'll kind of
work backwards this okay here's the
basic model right
get our embeddings combine the
embeddings for the continuous variables
tiny bit of drop out one dense layer to
ten players more drop out and then the
final sigmoid activation function you'll
see that I've got like comments as out
stuff all over the place and this is
because like I had a lot of questions
we're going to cover this after the
break a lot of questions about some of
the details like why did they do you
think certain ways you know some of the
things they did were like so weird I
just thought they couldn't possibly be
right I did some experimenting we'll
know more about that in a moment
so the embeddings as per usual I create
a little function to create an embedding
which first of all creates my regular
chaos input layer and then it creates my
embedding layer and then how many
embedding dimensions are going to use
sometimes I look them up in their
dictionary I had earlier and sometimes I
calculated them using this simple
approach of saying I will use however
many levels there are in the categorical
variable divided by two with a maximum
of 50 so it's like these for two
different techniques other planners
normally with like word embeddings you
have a whole sentence right and so you
end up you've got to feed it to an hour
and n and so you have time steps but so
normally you have an input length equal
to the length of your sentence now this
is the time sketch when ironing we don't
have an R we don't have any time steps
we just have one element in one column
so therefore I have to pass flattened
after this because it's going to have
this redundant unit one prime axis that
I don't want right so this is just
because you know people don't normally
do this kind of stuff with embedding so
they're assuming that you're going to
kind of want it in a format ready to go
to an R and n so this is just turning it
back into a normal format so we grabbed
each embedding we end up with a whole
list of those we then combine all of
those embeddings with all of our
continuous variables
into a single list of variables and so
then our model is going to have all of
those embedding inputs and all about
continuous inputs and then we can
compile it and train it alright so let's
take a break and see you back here at
five past 8:00 okay so so we've got our
neural net set up we trained it in the
usual way go see it and yeah where we go
so that's basically that and it's um the
Train reasonably quickly six minutes in
this case
sorry to show you and so you got two
questions that came in and right when we
bring you over one of them is for the
normalization is it possible to use
another function other than log such as
sigmoid I don't think you're going to
use stick noise like a kind of financial
data and sales data and stuff tends to
be of a shake we're low chroma cat more
linear which is generally what you want
and then when we lock lock transform our
target variable we're also transforming
the squared error is this a problem or
is it helping the model to find a better
minimum air in the I'm transforming
space
yeah so you're going to be careful about
what loss function you want in this case
the caracal competition is trying to
minimize root mean square error
so I actually then said okay I want you
to do mean absolute error because that
you know what in in log space that's
kind of basically doing the same thing
right the percent is a ratio so this is
the absolute error between two logs
which is basically the same as a ratio
so yeah you need to make sure your loss
function is appropriate in that space
and I think this is one of the things
that they didn't do in the original
competition with node tribe as you can
see I tried changing it I think it
helped okay by the way extra boost is
fantastic here is the same series of
steps to run this model with extra boost
as you can see I just concatenate my
categorical and continuous for training
and for my validation set here is a set
of parameters which tends to work pretty
well now XG boost has a data type called
D matrix of data metrics which is
basically a normal matrix but it keeps
track of the names of the features so it
like print out or you know better better
information and then you go to on train
and this takes like less than a second
to run and it's not massively worse than
our previous result and so it's like a
good way to kind of get started the
reason that next G boost and random
forests is particularly helpful it's
because it does something called
variable importance right so this is how
you get the variable importance for an
excuse model so it takes a second and
suddenly here is the information you
need so when I was having trouble
replicating the original results from
the first place Twitter's one of the
things that helped me a lot was to look
at this feature importance plot and say
okay competition distance holy cow
that's really really important let's
make sure that my competition distance
results
you know pre-processing really is
exactly the same
on the other hand event doesn't really
matter at all so I'm not going to worry
really at all about checking my events
this feature importance or variable
importance plot also it's known you can
also create with a random forest these
things are amazing right because you are
using a tree ensemble it doesn't like it
doesn't matter the shape of anything it
doesn't matter if you have or don't have
interactions you know this is all like
totally kind of assumption free so like
this is in real life this is the first
thing I do like the first thing I do is
try to get a feature important spot
printer because that tells me it often
it turns out there's only three or four
variables in there but like if you've
got 10,000 variables so I worked on a
big credit scoring problem a couple of
years ago I have nine and a half
thousand variables it turned out that 99
is the matter great and so the company I
was working for like literally it spent
something like five million dollars on
this big management consulting project
and this big management consulting
projects have told them all these ways
in which they can like capture all this
information is really clean way to their
credit scoring models and of course none
of those things are in these nine and
that you know so they could have saved a
billion dollars down it goes it's been
shrinking so many companies don't these
random firsts so you know I can't
overestimate you know uh overstate the
importance of this plot but you know
it's this is a deep learning course so
we're not really going to spend time
talks about it now I mentioned that I
had a whole bunch of like there's a
whole bunch of like really really really
weird things in the way that the
competitions that place getters did
things for one Thank You does normalized
a continuous variance who does that but
then when people do well no competition
something's working you know
[Music]
the ways in which they initialize their
embedding were really really weird
there's all these things that really
really weird so what I did was I wrote a
little script
rosemon experiments and what I did was
basically I copied and pasted all the
important code out of my logbook and
remember I've already pickled the
parameters for the you know label
encoder and the gala so I don't have to
worry about doing those again and once
they copied and pasted all that code in
so this is exactly all the code you just
saw I then had this you know bunch of
for loops right pretty inelegant but
these are all of the things that I
wanted to basically find out like
doesn't matter whether or not you use
you know one zero scanning it doesn't
matter whether you use that we had
approach to initializing embeddings
doesn't matter whether you use their
particular dictionary of embedding
dimensions or use my simple little
formula something else I tried it you
know they basically took all their
continuous variables and put them
through like a separate little dense
layer each so I was like why don't we
put them all together now so try some
other things like using batch
normalization so I ran this and got back
every possible combination of these
right so this is like this is where you
want to be using the script you know and
like I'm not going to tell you that I
jump straight to this first of all I
spent days screwing around experiments
in a notebook by hand continually
forgetting what I had just done until
eventually I just you know it took me
like an hour to write this and then of
course
i pasted it into Excel and here it is
right chuck it into a pivot table use
conditional formatting and here's my
results right so you can see all my
different combinations with and without
normalization with my special function
versus their dictionary using a single
dense matrix S is putting everything
together using their weird in FS not
using a weird inner so my n FS is there
live in it and here is this stark blue
here is their what they do right I'd
like to it's full of weird to me right
then as you can see it's actually the
darkest blue it's actually it actually
is the band but then when you kind of
zoom out you realize there's a whole
corner over here that's like got a
couple of eight-six's nearly as good
right but seems much more consistent
which is and also more consistent with
sanity like yet do normalize your data
and yes do use an appropriate
initialization function and if you do
those two things and it doesn't really
matter what else you do and so on and
work fine so when I then did was I
created a little spark line in Excel for
the actual training graphs right and so
here's their here's their winning one
chomp again went over 85 that here's the
variance of like getting there and as
you can see their approach was kind of
pretty bumpy up and down up and down up
and down the second-best on the other
hand okay point hello a six thousand
over five is going down very smoothly
okay and so that makes me think
different that it's in like this very
stable part of the world and given us
training much better I actually think
this is just random chance you know it
just happened to be low at this point
I actually thought this is a better
approach you know it's more it's more
sensible and it's more consistent it
quickly
so this kind of approach to running
experiments place I thought I just
show you you know to say like when you
run experiment try and do it in a
rigorous way and track both the kind of
stability of the approach as well as the
actual result of the approach so you
know this one here makes so much sense
it's like use my simple function rather
than there we're dictionary use
normalization use the single dense
matrix and use a thoughtful
initialization and you do all those
things you end up with something
basically it's good and much more stable
okay that's all I wanted to tell you
about rustman I'm going to very briefly
mention another competition which is the
cattle taxi destination competition the
cattle destination yeah nice to never
hear through um you you were saying that
you did a couple of experiments one you
feel them bearing from them to them
balancing to running forests and then to
invariance again into you know
needlework oh I didn't do that the that
was from the paper yeah I don't know a
ten because you just use one your
network to where we think together or
not yeah so what they did was for this
one here this one one five they they
trained the neural network I just showed
you they didn't throw away the neural
network and trained a GBM model but for
the categorical variables rather than
using one hunting coatings they use the
events that's all okay so the taxi
competition was won by the team with
this unicode game which is pretty cool
and it's actually turned out for your
team run by Joshua NGO who some you know
one of the people that stuck it out
through the AI winter and is now kind of
one of the leading lights in deep
learning
and interestingly the thing I just
showed you the rustling competition
today actually this paper they wrote in
the rustling competition they claimed to
have invented this idea of categorical
inventing but actually the entre of NGO
team won this competition a year earlier
with the same technique but you know
again it's someone cool nobody noticed
even though it josh of NGO so I want to
quickly show you what they did this is
the paper they wrote ok and their
approach to picking an embedding size
was very simple use 10 okay so the data
was which customer is taking this taxi
which taxi are they in which taxis pain
did they get the taxi from and then
quarter hour of the day day of the week
week of the year and they didn't add all
kinds of other stuff this is basically
it right and so then they said ok we're
going to learn embeddings
inspired by NLP but and so actually to
my knowledge this is the first time this
appeared in the literature
having said that I'm sure I'm a thousand
people the course is not obvious
machination four came up as a quick
sanity check if you have days a week
like the southern even one seven one hot
variable potentials and inventing sizes
10 yeah that doesn't make any sense
right yeah so I used to think that but
actually it does like such an absence
having the last few months
quite often ended up with bigger
embeddings in my original fab analogy
and often it does give better results
and I think it's just like when you
realize it's just a dense layer on top
of a 100 coding it's like okay why
shouldn't a dense layer have more
information you know yeah I found it
weird too I still find a little weird
but it definitely seems to be something
that's quite useful
they're fuckin kids doesn't help
cuz that's tough huh yeah yeah I have
absolutely found pretty good times down
where I need be here of any metrics
dimensionalities in my than my cat
analogy of my categorical variable
okay now in this competition again at
the time Terry's competition really
because the main thing you've given
other than all this metadata is series
of GPS points which is every GPS point
along the route and at some point for
the test set the route is cut off and
you have to figure out what the final
GPS point would have been where are they
going
I'm here's the model that they won with
turned up again to be very simple you
take all the metadata with the store and
Chuck it through the embeddings you then
take the first five GPS points and the
last five GPS points and concatenate
them together with the embeddings chuck
them through the hidden layer enter a
soft Max and now this is quite
interesting what they didn't do is they
check the result of this soft max right
and they combine it with clusters now
what are these classes they used mean
shit clustering and they use mean shift
clustering to figure out where are the
places people can to go but to attack
these people tend to go to the airport
or they'd enter go to the hospital or
they tend to go to the shopping strip
right so using mainship clustering they
came up with I think was about three
thousand factors you know XY coordinates
or places that people tend to go however
people
I always go to those 3,000 places so
this is the really cool thing by
producing a soft mat and then they took
the softmax and they multiplied it to
here multiplied it and took a weighted
average using the softmax as the weight
and the cluster centers as the thing
that you're texting the weighted average
up so in other words if they're going to
the airport
Koosh or the softmax will end up getting
a PR very close to 1 to the airport
cutter on the other hand if it's not
really that clear whether they're going
to this shopping trip or this movie then
those two trans defenses could both have
a soft mess about point 5 and so it's
going to add end up getting somewhere
halfway between the two so like this is
really interesting like they built a
different kind of architecture to
anything we've seen before where the
softmax
is not the last thing we do right it's
being used to average about your
clusters and so this is really smart
because the softmax forces it to be
easier for it to pick a specific
destination that's very common but also
makes it possible for it to predict any
destination anywhere by combining you
know the average of a number of classes
together but I think this is really
elegant architecture engineering
um so projectory prefix so last four
dots it's like 5 5 kgs point but just
isn't central to return continue last
five GPS points that we're given right
and so to create the training set what
they did was they took all of the routes
and they truncated them randomly
basically so every time they sampled
another route I think of the data
generator basically the data generator
would like randomly slice it off
somewhere so this was the last 5 points
which we have access to and the first
five points
the reason is not all the points is
because they're using a standard
multi-layer perceptron here so there's
you know it's a variable length you know
a and also you don't want it to be too
big there's a question so the prefix is
not set into an RNN it's just fed into a
dense layer correct yeah so we just get
10 points concatenated together into a
dense layer so surprisingly simple how
good was it well
look at the results 2 1 4 2 1 4 2 1 3 2
1 3 2 & 3 2 1 3 2 1 1 or early 2 & 2
you know everybody's clustered together
one person is a bit better at 2:08 and
then we're way better at sure what a
tree and then they mentioned by the way
in the paper they didn't actually have
time to finish training so when they
actually finished training it was
actually one fourth at 7:00 right so
they like their one so easily as more
funny and interesting in the paper they
actually mentioned the test set was so
small that the oh they knew that the
only way that could be shorter win was
to make sure they won easily now the
constitution step is so small the
leaderboard is actually not
statistically that great so they created
a custom test set and try to see if they
could find something that's even better
still on the custom test set and it
turns out that actually an RNN is better
still it still would have won the
competition but I'm just there's not
enough data in the cable test set that
this is a statistically significant
result in this case it is statistically
significant a regular RNN wasn't done up
but what they did instead was they said
let's take an hour an end where we
passed in five points at a time in the
RNN basically I think what probably
would have been even better would be to
have had a convolutional layer first and
then pass that into an R and n they
didn't try it as far as I can see from
the paper so importantly at
bidirectional RN n which ensures that
the initial points in the last point
tend to have more weight because we know
that our NN you know their states
generally reflects them lives in more
regionally so so this result of this
model so our poor long-suffering intern
branch has been trying to replicate this
result he has it had at least two
all-nighters in the last two weeks but
hasn't quite managed to yet so I'm not
going to show you the code but hopefully
once bread starts sleeping again he'll
be able to finish it off and we can show
you the notebook during the week on the
forum that actually
reimplementation process to watch Brad
try to replicate this you know because
the vast majorities of times in my
experience when people say they've tried
a model and the model didn't work out
and they've given up in the model it
turns out that it's actually because
they screwed something up not a problem
with the model and and if you weren't
comparing to Joshua of NGOs teams
results knowing that you haven't
replicated it yet you know at which
point do you give up and say all my
models not working this is saying oh I
have a superbug now it's very difficult
to please I've machine learning models
so you know what rats actually had to
end up doing is literally take the
original benzio team code run it line by
line and then try to replicate it in
Karis line by line and literally NPI or
clothes every time because you know to
build a model like this it doesn't look
that complex but there's just so many
places that you can measure little
mistakes no no normal person will make
like zero mistakes in fact normal pick
not you know normal people like me make
dozens of mistakes so when you build a
model like this you need to find a way
to test every single line of code any
line of code you don't test I guarantee
you'll end up at the bug and you won't
know you have about and there's no way
to ever find out you have a bug so did
you have a neutral we had several
questions one is if a note that piti is
very similar to what happens in the
memory network paper in that case the
output embeddings are weighted by the
attention probability no or you know
it's a lot like a regular attentional
and language model yes
can you talk more about the idea you
have about first having the
convolutional layer and passing that to
an RNN what do you mean by that so here
is a fantastic paper which is uh
so cut it up right let me just find this
paper oh here it is yes you know we
looked at um these are kind of
supporting coatings last week for
language models I don't know if any if
you thought about this and wondered like
or what if we just had individual
characters and there's a really
fascinating paper called fully character
level machine translation with no
explicit segmentation from the member of
last year and they actually get
fantastic results on just character
level
beating pretty much everything including
the VP approach we saw last time I'm
just showing the results here yeah so
they looked at lots of different
approaches and you know comparing bpe
to individual character and most of the
time they got the best results
there our model looks like this right
they start out with every individual
character it goes to a character
embedding just like we've these Taktarov
any lots of times and then you take
those character embeddings
and you pass it through a one
dimensional convolution yeah I don't
know if you guys remember that in part 1
of this course then actually had a blog
post about showing how you can do like
multiple size convolutions and catnip
them all together so you could use that
approach or you could just pick a single
size right so you end up basically
scrolling your convolutional window
across your sets of characters and so
you end up with the same number of
convolution outputs as you started out
with letters right but they're now
representing the information in a window
around that letter right in this case
get max Pauling right so they basically
said okay which window
assuming that you know maybe we had I
think so this is to look at different
sizes of size 4 or size 3 and of size 5
which bits you know seem to be centered
got the highest activations around here
and then they took those max called
things and they put them through a
second set of second embeddings they
didn't put that system called a highway
network which details that matter too
much it's kind of something like a
identity like we learned about last week
this is a slightly older approach from
the internet and then finally UPS doing
all that think that to a neuron in fact
so the idea here in this model was they
basically you know did as much word
pre-processing as possible and then
finally put that into nrm and because
we've got these Mac falling layers this
R and n ends up with a lot less time
points
is really important to minimize the
amount of processing in the air Annette
so I'm not going to go to detail on this
but you know check out this paper
because it's a really interesting next
question is so for the destinations we
would have more air for the peripheral
points are we taking a centroid of
clustered I don't understand that sorry
you understand it I mean all we're doing
is we're taking the soft next P
multiplied by the collapse of C over
play them up I thought the first part
was asking that with destinations that
are more peripheral peripheral they
would have higher air because it would
be harder to predict this way yeah
probably
which is fine because by definition
they're not close to a cluster Center so
they're not common and then going back
there's a question on the the Rossman
example what does ma PE with neural
networks mean I would have expected that
result to be the same why is it lower so
this is just using a one-pot encoding
without an without an embedding layer
okay all right
gosh we could have run out of time a bit
quickly but I really want to show you
this so quite a few of the students and
I have been trying to get a new approach
to segmentation working and I finally
got it working in the last day or two
they really wanted to show to you we
talked last week about dense net and I
mentioned the sense net is like
ass-kicking lis good at doing image
classification with a small number of
data points like credibly good ah but I
also mentioned that it's the basis of
this thing called 100 plate of tiramisu
which is an approach to segmentation so
segmentation refers to taking a picture
of an image and figuring out you know
where's the tree
where's the dog where's the bicycle and
so forth
so it seems like we're not sure of NGO
fans today because this is one of his
proofs papers as well let me set the
scene so Brendan what about students too
many of you have seen what with blog
post he has successfully got a PI torch
of his working
so I've shared that on our fire bastard
ai and I got the carrot version for
working so I'll show you the cows
version because I actually understand it
and if anybody's interested in asking
questions about the pipes watch version
hopefully Brendan will be happy to
answer them during the week so the data
looks like this so there's an image and
then there's a show and then there's a
labels ok so that's basically what it
looks like so you can see here you know
got traffic lights you've got holes
you've got trees buildings or paths
roads interestingly the Dana step we're
using is something called can bed and is
actually the data set is actually frames
from a video so a lot of the frames are
first in order each other and there's
only like 600 frames in total so there's
very variable data and it can be data
set furthermore we're not going to do
any pre training so we're going to try
and build a state-of-the-art
notification system on video which is
already much lower information content
because most of the frames are pretty
similar
using just eccentric frames without
pre-training now if you ask the amonth
ago I would have told you it's not
possible like this just seems like an
incredibly difficult into some but just
watch
so I'm going to skip to the answer first
and here's an example of a particular
frame we're trying to match here is the
ground truth for that frame so you can
see there's a pony cart here and a
little car here so there is little cars
there's a tree you know trees are really
difficult right they're kind of
incredibly fine funny things and here is
my trained model and as you can see it's
done really really well right it's
interesting to look at the mistakes that
made this little thing here is a person
but you can see that the person it kind
of their hair looks a lot like traffic
life and the jacket looks a lot like
mailbox you know where else these tiny
little people here it's done perfectly
okay or very physically yeah or else
this person got a little bit confused
okay another example of where it gone
wrong is this should be a road or else
it wasn't quite sure what was road and
what was footpath which makes sense kind
of the colors do look very similar but
had we have pre-trained something a pre
train network would have understood that
you know cross roads tender go straight
across they don't tend to look like that
right so you can kind of see this you
know where this minor mistakes it made
say I also would have learned and it
looked at more than you know a couple of
hundred exams to people that people
generally are a particular shape but so
this is not enough data for actually
learn some of these things but
nonetheless it is extraordinarily
affected you know like look at this
traffic light has kind of surrounded by
a sign so like the ground truth actually
has the traffic light and then a tiny
little edge of sign and like it's even
got that right you know so it's
incredibly accurate model so how does it
work
and in particular how to do these
amazing trees so the answer is companies
picture Thank You Klee until um this is
inspired by model called unit until the
unit model came along everybody was
doing these kinds of segmentation models
using an approach just like what we did
for style transfer which was basically
you have a number of convolutional
layers with max pooling or with
australia - which gradually make the
image smaller and smaller bigger
reception field and then you go back up
the other side using up sampling or
deconvolution until you get back to the
original size and then your final layer
is the same size as your starting layer
and has a bunch of different classes
that you're trying to use in the softmax
the problem with that is that you end up
with effect I'll show you an example
there's a really nice paper called
Annette Annette is not only an
incredibly accurate model for
segmentation but also incredibly fast it
actually can run in real time we can
actually run it on the video but the
mistakes it makes sort of this chair
right this chair has a big gap here and
here and here but Annette gets a totally
wrong right and the reason why is
because they use a very traditional you
know down sampling up sampling approach
and by the time they get to the bottom
they've just lost track of the fine
detail so the trick are these
connections here what we do is we start
low input we do a standard initial
convolution just like we did with cell
transfer we then have a dense network
that Fisher knows about last week and
then that block okay we keep going down
we do a max falling track being more
dense
our next polling type things are going
down and then if we go up the other side
so we do a deconvolution dense block
deconvolution dense block we take the
output from the dense blocks on the way
down so and we actually copy it over to
here and concatenate the two together
right
so actually Brendon a few days ago
actually threw this on our whiteboard
when we're explaining some Elissa and so
he's shown us every stage here we start
out with a - 24 - 24 now this is what
bream didn't think the Jeremy suit looks
like despondently - 24 - 24 input go
through the convolutions for 48 filters
go through a dense block at another 80
filters and then goes through our they
call it a transition down so basically a
max calling just now size 112 right the
kicker in their dense flop transition
downs is now 56 56 28 or 28 14 by 14 7
by 7 and then on the way up again
we go transition up it's now 14 by 14 we
copy across the results of the 14 by 14
from the transition down and concatenate
together now into a dense block
transition up now 28 by 28
so a copy across there 28 by 28 from the
transition down and so forth so by the
time we get all the way back up here
we're actually copying across something
that was originally of size 224 by 224
and haven't had much done to it right it
had only been through one convolutional
layer and one dense block that haven't
really got much rich computation being
done but the thing is because by the
time it gets back up all the way up here
the model knows pretty much you know
this is a tree and this is the person in
the house and it just needs to get the
fine little details you know where
exactly does this leaf finish where
exactly to the person's hat finish so
it's basically copying across something
which is very high resolution that
doesn't have that much rich information
but
fine because it really only needs to
fill in the details but so these things
here they're called skip connections but
they're really inspired by this paper
called unit which has been you know one
mini careful competitions - using dense
blocks rather than normal feeling
connected blocks so let me show you and
you know we're looking not going to have
phones going to this in detail but I've
done all this coding chaos from scratch
this is actually like a fantastic to
care a certain have to create any custom
layers and if we have to do anything
weird at all
oh except for one thing
data augmentation so the data
augmentation was we start with 480 by
360 images we randomly crop some 224 by
224 part and also randomly we left click
at horizontally that's all perfectly
fine well
caris doesn't really have the random
drops unfortunately but more importantly
whatever we do to the input image we
also have to do it as a target inch
please get a third same 224 perfectly
for crop we need to do the same
horizontal clip so I have to write a
data generator which you guys may
actually find useful anyway so this is
my data generator basically I call it a
segment generator and it's just a
standard generator so it's got a next
function right then each time you call
next you have some random bunch of
indexes it goes through each one of
those indexes and grabs the necessary
item grabbing a random slice sometimes
randomly flipping it horizontally and
then doing this to both the X is n for
the Y's returning them back along with
this segment generator in order to
randomly grab grab a batch of random
indices each time I created this little
class called batch indices which can
basic
please do that and it can have a shuffle
true or shuffle false so this this pair
of classes you guys might find really
helpful for creating your own data
generator this batch indices class in
particular you know now that I've
written it you can see how it works
right
like I say batch indices from a data set
of size 10 I want to grab 3 indices at a
time so then let's grab five batches now
in this case I've got by default shuffle
equals false
so just returns Oh 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9
finished commence at a 1/2 okay on the
other hand if I say shuffle equals true
it returns them in random order but
still makes sure it captures all of them
right and then we're done if it starts a
new random order okay so this makes it
really easy to create random generators
so that was the only thing I had to add
to care us to get this sort of work
other than that you know we wrote the
tiramisu and the tiramisu looked very
very similar to the density that we saw
last week right except we've got all our
pieces the value to drop out the batch
norm the irelia on top of batch norm
concat layer so this is something you
had to add my convolution to d followed
by drop out and then finally my batch
norm Paula values followed by
convolution to D so this is just the
dense blocks that we saw last week so
dense block is something where we just
keep grabbing twelve or sixteen filters
at a time concatenated them to the last
set and doing that a few times that's
what this block is so here's something
interesting the original paper or it's
down sampling before transition down did
a a one by one convolution followed by a
max falling and I actually discovered
that doing a
strive to convolution gives better
results so you'll see I actually have
not followed the paper so the one that's
in comments comes without fear is what
the paper did but actually it is works
better that was interesting
interestingly though on the transition
upside to remember that checkerboard
artifact blog post free we saw that
shows that up sampling 2d followed by a
convolutional layer works better it does
not work better if it is in fact a
deconvolution works better that is so
that's why you can see opal is
deconvolution layer but i thought that
was interesting so basically you can see
when I go down sampling a bunch of times
it's basically do a dense block and then
I have to keep track of my skip
connections that's right so basically
keep a list of all of those kid
connections but they're going to hang on
to all of these so every one of these
get connections like just stick in this
little rain right appending them after
every dense block right and so then I
keep them all and then I pass them to my
upward path ok so I basically do my
transition up and then I can catenate
that with that skip connection okay so
that's the basic approach and so then
the actual terribie to model itself with
those pieces is less than the street of
code right basically just to actually
very con do my down paths do my up path
using those get connections then one by
one times at the end and a soft map
ok um so these dense nets and indeed
this stuff is kind of a full fully
convolutional dense net or at least some
term is to model they actually take
quite a long time to train they don't
have very many parameters which is
thinking why I think they work so well
with these tiny datasets but they do
still take a long time to train each
epoch
minutes and in the end I have to do you
know many hundreds of epochs and you
know I was also doing there you know a
bunch of learning rate and kneeling so
in the end this kind of really had to
Train overnight even though I had only
about five or six hundred friends but
you know in the end training training
training training in the end I got a
really good result now interest I was a
bit nervous at first like getting this
like 87.6%
accuracy but in the model in the paper
though again getting 90% plus it turns
out that 3% of the pixels are marked as
per week I don't know why they make
sense for you but in the paper and
actually remove them so you'll see when
you get to my results section I've got
this bit where I remove those void ones
and I ended up with eighty nine and a
half percent
mummy busting class managed to replicate
the paper the paper got 91 and a half or
nine 11.2% we tried the lasagna cosy
provided we tried a Brendon high scorch
we tried my Claire us even though we
couldn't replicate their result this is
still better than any other result I
found so this is still super accurate a
couple of quick notes fellas first you
they track training also on thing called
the g8x data set and just another video
data set the degree to which this is an
amazing model is really clear here
there's 76% it's from a model which has
specifically built to video so it
actually includes the time component
which is absolutely critical
and it uses a pre train network so it's
used like a million images to kind of
pre train and it's still not as good as
this model right so like that is
extraordinary comparison
and this is the cam tech comparison
here's the model we were just looking at
and again I actually looked into this I
thought oh 91 in the half or else this
one here 88 Wow
it actually looks like it's not that
much better I'm really surprised
like even tree like I really thought it
should win easily on tree but it doesn't
win very much so I actually went back
and got for this paper and it turns out
that the authors of the internet paper
this is the tapir by the way Lonsdale
that they're comparison comparing to it
turned out that they actually trained on
crops at 85 to buy 85 - so they actually
use like a way higher resolution image
to start with so like you've got to be
really careful when you read these
comparisons sometimes like people
actually kind of shoot themselves in the
foot so these guys were comparing their
result to another model that was using
like twice as bigger picture so again
this is actually way better than they
actually did it look like another one
like this one here it is 88 also looks
impressive but then I looked across here
and I noticed that the dilution dilution
8 model is like way better than this
model on every single category way
better and yet somehow the average is
only point-three better and then I
realized ok this actually has to be an
error right so this model is actually a
lot better than this this table gives
the impression so I briefly mentioned
that there's a model which doesn't have
any skip connections caught in it which
is actually better than the pyramus - on
everything except for tree but on the
tree it's terrible in seventy seven
point eight versus I am pleased every
tree all right okay I took that back I'm
sure it was less good than this model
but now I can't find that data anyway
the reason was to mention this is that
Virginia is about to release a new model
which combines these approaches with
skip connections called link next so you
know keep an eye on the forms I'll be
like looking into that quite shortly
okay
you got something Rachel you have a few
short questions as I know we're almost
out of time energy yeah let's answer
them in the forum because like really um
you know I actually wanted to talk about
this basically a lot of you have come up
to me and being like oh we're finishing
what do we do now
and the answer is you know we have now
created a community of all these people
who have spent well over 100 hours
working on deep learning for many many
months and have filtering boxes and
written blog posts and you know done all
kinds of stuff you know set up social
impact talks written articles and forms
like ok this communities happened right
so it doesn't make any sense in my
opinion for Rachel and I to now be
saying like is what happens next right
so just like Elena has decided okay I
want a book club so she took the Lindy
and we now have a book club a couple
Monday's time you can all come to the
book club
you know so what's next right well you
know the forum's will continue forever
you know we all know each other and
let's like do good shit right but most
importantly write code but please write
code write code you know build apps
take your work projects and try doing
them with big learning you know build
libraries to make things easier you know
maybe go back to stuff from part one of
the cost and look back and think like oh
why didn't we do it the other way maybe
I can make this simpler you know write
papers right so I showed you that
amazing result of the new style transfer
oppression Vincent last week you know
hopefully government turned into a paper
write blog posts in a few weeks time all
the mooc guides are going to be coming
to you in part two of the course so like
help them out on the forum you know
teaching is the best way to learn
yourself I really want to hear the
success stories like um people don't
believe that what you've done is
possible like I know that because like I
like as recently as yesterday there was
you know the highest-ranked hack amused
comment on a story about deep learning
was about how like it's pointless trying
to do deep learning unless you have
years of mathematical background and you
know C++ and you're an expert in machine
learning techniques across the board and
otherwise there's no way that you're
going to be able do anything useful in
the real or project static to that today
is what everybody believes so we now
know that's not true but so Rachel and I
are going to start up a podcast where
we're going to try to both help big
learning learners but one of the key
things you want to do is tell your
stories right so if you've done
something interesting at work or you you
know got an interesting year result or
you just in the middle of a project is
kind of fun please tell us right either
on the forum or private message or audio
or whatever I please tell us because you
know we really want to share your story
and it's not a story yet you know tell
us the map that we can help you you know
and the community can help you
you know get get together you know so
you know the book club if you're
watching this on the MOOC you know
organize other people in your geography
to get together and and and and meet up
or your workplace like in this group
here I know we've got people from Apple
and uber and airbnb who started doing
this in kind of lunchtime MOOC chests
and now they're they're here at is
course essentially and also when it's
recommend you it would be great to start
meet up to help lead other people
through say part one of the course kind
of a system going through it yeah
absolutely you know so you know I'm you
know Rachel and I really just want to
spend the next 6 to 12 months focused on
supporting your projects you know so I'm
very sitting you know working working on
this one cancer stuff but I'm also
interested in like every project that
you guys are working on I want to help
with that I also want to help people who
want to teach this so Jeanette is going
to go from being student to teacher
hopefully soon there will be you know
teaching you assess students about deep
learning the next batch of people about
acquiring anybody who's interested in
teaching you know let us know because we
this is the best high leverage activity
is to teach the teachers so yeah you
know I don't know where where this is
going to end up but my hope is really
that basically I'll say the experiment
has worked you know you guys are all
here you're reading papers you're
writing code you're understanding the
most cutting-edge research level deep
learning that exists today we've gone
beyond some of the cutting-edge research
and you know many situations some of you
have gone beyond the cutting-edge
research so yeah you know let's go from
here as a community and anything that
Rachel and I can do to help please tell
us because we just want you to
successful we want the community be
successful so yeah one question so will
you be still active in the forums are
very active yeah yeah that's you know my
job is to make you guys success okay so
thank you all so much for coming and
congratulations to all
[Applause]