lesson 13 lucky fetid welcome
the penultimate lessons so who's heard
of the Google brain residency program
yeah a pretty famous traitor sitting
around here I think it's probably maybe
teach our program to get into the
hardest big mining program to get into
the world the reason I mention it is
because it so happens one of our
students was just accepted so I'd like
if we need to congratulate I'm Sarah
whole club soccer is our a new Google
brain resident and I thought maybe we
could have a brief chat appear to find
out about her path to this program so
ochre is a a new Google brain resident
and I thought maybe we can have a brief
chat there to find out about her and her
path to this program I'll throw over the
green box trying to hurt anybody close
enough so hello congratulations
so much very excited yeah so this is a
pretty huge thing to get into so you
must be like a machine learning PhD been
coding for a few decades so forth
yes exciting thing about the whole
process is that really in China kind of
a diverse set of fellows Brisbane for
the years so there's many different
buckets that would definitely phd's that
i've sat next to in the interview room
were well published and incredibly
accomplished so also undergraduate here
this would be their first draw after
college and my background was that I
have seen an industry I join and on the
consulting so I didn't on equality in
statistics and now I working with data
scientists so how long have you been
coding for so I've been coding to you
well what makes me page yeah yeah Rachel
told me you had a you had a same moment
when the in Goodfellow interview - is
that true thing about the whole process
is that you're so nervous the whole time
I'm so excited but also you're talking
to these people whose research you
followed for yeah and that's how you
would just my my my Google hangout
script hanger interview is actually when
you go there shell and start learning
about neural nets watching has moved so
it's just it feels so real and I think
that's quite of intent of the program is
to take very very different people at
different prices and create so you told
me that before the start of this course
your awareness of neural nets was a
little bit of theory from a few blog
posts I mean so how much is going
through this course kind of helped you
get the skills you needed to get into
this program I wasn't coding in winter
for MIDI 9 picture before this board I
done I done to be family guy and I was
fascinated by it be planning for what I
did if I was pretty deep in the theory
but I think part of why it was blog post
with business it wasn't a coherent body
of work and so now some other bands book
that is an spec which I have read
is really a fantastic treatment and I
think that what this course offers and I
said like many of you may have had the
same experience is the implementation
which was very new to me and and
definitely something I don't think it
would have found in a different forum
yeah I mean I know from talking to
Rachel that some of the interview
process was like actually sounded the
critic question Santa letter came
straight out of the course it was like
about how to do transfer learning and
like all these kind of practical
application stuff it seemed like at
least in my case it was a fairly
consistent breakdown throughout the
process of very math questions and then
a project experience and with the
project they're really trying to gauge
implementation and do a knowledge of
basically concepts that we've covered
very thoroughly in this class over
fetty's that was pretty distribution
understanding like how to address these
distribution differences so that's why I
think that that was standard throughout
the whole process with the big spectrum
YouTube and they expect the attendees to
have this holistic approach of both
coding but also a strong foundation and
opinions so if I could give a pitch for
your program one of the amazing things
that Sarah's done and her extraordinary
life is to create a organization called
Delta analytics which is applying data
science for social impact projects is
there room for people who might be
interested to contact you if they are
interested in doing that kind of work
and for me I wrote it honestly and I
think that the the cows of this course I
would be so thrilled to work with anyone
from this course going towards the like
the way that works I'll just
we pair with nonprofits all over the
world and you work with engineers and
data scientists over a six-month project
and and right now we like both with
eight different process and then we'll
try a new cycle to it then associate
well congratulations again I think are
also proud of you
so talking of talking of great work I
also wanted to mention other work with
another student who also has the great
challenge of having to deal with being a
fast AI in turn being on bread Brad took
up the challenge I set up two weeks ago
in implementing cyclic all learning
rings you might remember that the
psychical learning rate paper showed
faster training of neural nets and also
more automated and Brad actually had a
code of up super quickly and so if you
if you jump on the forum you'll find a
link to it there maybe Brad you can edit
or Elle's wiki thread do we have a wiki
stretch yet Rachel listen thirteen could
you create one you just click at the
bottom they make wiki and I obviously
this as I mentioned when we first taught
this this paper has been so little
looked at we don't yet really know like
I have a feeling it's going to turn out
that like this is the best way to train
like every kind of neural net in every
kind of situation so I've asked bread to
try as many possible experiments here
and you can clone keep water mating it
this is exactly the kind of thing like
Rachel and I at far say is going to do
if this really works out is like get rid
of the whole question of how to set
learning rates you know which currently
is such a personal thing
so yes so congratulations Brad on
getting that working and it worked
really well in care as I think you know
with the callbacks they had a code in
that they were quite neat as well yeah
you got those air please add the current
luster but I'm you're so excited about
this callbacks and Karis because you
would like our set call backs to stop
training if it's like you should stop
improving and then you can enter another
cycle to do different things and that
kind of oscillate between these like
different ways yeah the callbacks and
fully automate this whole process so I
kind of implemented similar leg zigzag
ins in this room so this case is really
cool like it's like ten lines of code
hoop breathing so far was this cold yeah
yeah absolutely
and so remember you know that Kara has
great source code right so if you look
in your anaconda live person packages
chaos directory you'll find all the
current callbacks so when I said to you
know pay for ads and chips is to how to
get started I see if you don't go here
look at the existing callbacks and see
if that helps you get it started you
know anytime you want to build something
in Kara one of the best ways to get
started is to read the source code for
something that it already has somewhat
similar to watching earlier and
certainly with callbacks it's an easy
way to do that it's been a big week in
deep learning as usual everything I
taught you in this course is now
officially out of date hopefully so what
are the things I have noticed is it's
all building on stuff that we've been
learning around about perhaps it began
to Brad for I'm drawing my attention to
this paper which is the new style
transfer paper which can transfer to any
style in real time so you don't have to
build a separate Network for each one
this is the kind of thing which you
could absolutely turn into an app and
obviously no one's done it yet because
paper just came out so you could be the
first one to say you know here's a path
which can create any
photo into any style you like and
honestly I think this third column is
their the new paper in my opinion if you
compare it to kind of the gold standard
which is the guidance paper we
originally looked at I actually think
it's maybe better you know like this one
looked more styling better this one so
there's an interesting paper one of the
basic ideas are the same but your
excellency has got some interesting
approaches Dan's have had a big step
forward these this is the previous state
of the art and face generation this is
new as you can see these are now pretty
much at photorealistic at least at one
from yet I 128 these are only 64 by 64
the August area so this is a pretty
exciting step forward in in games and as
we've talked about people use scans at
the moment to create textures but they
can be used as a kind of additional loss
function for any kind of generative
Network and so I think one of the things
I always look for is what's under
pressure what's underappreciated what's
not they used much at the moment and I
would say stands for a wider range of
generative models you know if you want
to create a really great super
resolution thing or if you want to
create a really great automatic create a
line-drawing creator or you know
colorization system or whatever any can
and your approach I'm Brett the most
amazing one is this paper you can relate
on to wiki which does a bi-directional
transfer even without matching pairs and
so for example clearly this would not be
possible to do if you require matching
pairs take a money and turn it into a
photo okay we don't have any data on how
to do that because we don't have any
photos of mine but as you can see it
works incredibly well so the
differential horse or a horse in for
zebra
summer into winter winter sauna again
you know this is a again based system
creating photorealistic images or very
impressive
at work I think this approach to sale
transfer by putting again layer that's
more interesting than the file transfer
we cannot so far because it really has
to create a painting that Class B
recognize is not the in real painting
otherwise the can will fail so I think
this is a really interesting approach to
social transfer as well okay so really
interesting week these are all papers
which I think any of you guys can can
tackle right now because they're all
built on the things we've learnt to its
cost if anybody's interested in tackling
any of them this week that'd be super
fun to talk about it from the forum yes
just to clarify is this large paper also
the again from the prior slide or is
this a different paper this is a
different paper of other story I'm
embarrassed that I didn't come actually
write on it where it comes from
could be do that
[Music]
actually rather than metering this maybe
somebody can find find out because I I
think I showed Brad from a direction of
our MC no don't file it in my Twitter
and put it on the wiki so I talked in
yeah I knew something like that
there we go cycle game okay disk a turn
forces into zephyrus not really to the
pictures okay thank you for the question
um all right
I'm talking about the interest
clustering a bit from time to time and
so we will talk about it more next week
in terms of applications but the main
application we've talked about so far is
using it for the kind of faster
pre-processing of really large data
items like CT scans in order to find
objects of interest in this case loan
modules among cancers and one of the
things I mentioned that I was interested
in was experimenting with combining
approxima sneer approximate nearest
natives with with mean shift clustering
and so to remind you the basic idea was
that here's our TTU version we went
through each mini batch and with each
mini batch we then basically data a
distance from every element in that mini
batch to every single data item and then
we took the weighted sum of all the data
items weighted by the webadvisor
Gaussian on those weights and I pointed
out that most the vast majority of data
points are far enough away that they're
wasted so close to zero that we could
probably ignore them so maybe we could
have tried putting a approximate nearest
neighbor step beforehand so rather than
adding up the entire data set which
could be a million points we could just
be the nearest hundred divas so I
actually tried that during the week this
is basically what happened in Pugh so
this is a profit there's I just use the
existing scikit-learn dot natives
algorithm so I haven't written my own
it--which version and I know one of you
guys on the forum has already started
writing applied for traditional so I
just try to a bowl tree which is a
particular kind of approximate nearest
neighbors and the basic idea is you say
okay here's the data that I want you to
index so that I can rapidly do nearest
neighbors so now please do a query
looking at I don't know the first 10
data points and for each one of those 10
data points jimmies are 3 nearest
neighbors and that return something like
this right here are the 10 data points I
passed in and here are their 3 across
the nearest neighbors
and of course all the time itself is the
phone nearest neighbor so that's why the
first one is is kind of boring so then I
thought okay that looks good so then I
just put that into the loop of our
mainship clustering so I said okay each
time we go through another epoch Index
the data we have so far we've checked
into a really small trees and then when
we do our distances don't do them to
every point but instead stories into the
nearest point so I did this did a query
here to find the 50 nearest neighbors
this then puts that into GPU I'm turning
it into a senator and tutoring us so
that gives me the list of the indexes
not the data itself so but interestingly
the hardest step was the one that seems
like it should be the easiest which is
that I have to then look up each of
these indexes into the data to return
the actual points right now easy enough
to do if you just look through it one
step at a time but we're trying to use
the GPU right if I tried doing a one
step at a time it made the thing take
better because GPUs are not quick at
doing things at a time so I created a
little batch wise indexing function
which is the end ret Rachel and I
realized we could do actually with very
very little code and this is basically
something where we could pass in our
array and plastic limit our kind of
matrix of indexes and it would return a
three dimensional tensor basically as
every one of the points for every one of
those nearest neighbors formula finish
so that was the only bit that was
remotely tricky other than that that
this function other than that the rest
of the code is the same so this works in
the sense that have sped things up but
it didn't work in a sense of the result
here was the input we gave it and here's
the output
what happened is it turns out each one
of these little colored dots actually
now represent 50 coins so what it's done
is it's taking me to literally right
it's basically found the 50 nearest
neighbors to each point and created a
cluster of 50 points and once it's
created these clusters of 50 points it
nailed that right there's no way for it
to cluster these any further because
every time it now goes nearest neighbors
there's other tipping points to the
right on top of you so an engine is to
basically show the kinds of things that
can can go wrong hopefully by next week
this will be six you know it's like when
I described this problem this thing like
that was clearly going to work and then
as soon as I saw this picture I
immediately saw that it couldn't
possibly work you know so this is kind
of the nature of trying things out but
the interesting thing is I now realize
that the solution to this will be way
faster than this right the solution is
what Rachel describes as an approximate
approximate nearest neighbors right
which is something that doesn't return
the 50 probably nearest point returns 50
points which probabilistically close to
ones are more likely to be there but
there are like zero guarantees like we
want it to be less good so you know if
you're interested during the week if one
of you want to try creating a
approximate approximate nearest
neighbors algorithm I think it will
basically be a case of taking like LSH
or whole tree or something and like
removing a lot of the code you know
removing the code that makes it better
so hopefully you know next week we'll
see this working but I thought it'd be
interesting to see that you know the
intermediate stage and actually this
kind of thing is like showing you the
failures like you don't get to see most
of the failures so I was working with
some of the students over the weekend on
implementing some finger will see later
on today and actually on Saturday
afternoon I was sitting with Melissa
going through some of this coding and
Atlantis bit and look to look like oh
wow it's really interesting to see the
process
because it's like becoming on Monday the
thought that's working where else we
spent the entire Saturday afternoon like
slowly going through one at a time and
completely making mistakes do you have
any better to sort of see what happens
so yeah the actual process is everything
you see in class getting it working is
full of failures and in fact Brad is
currently working on building one of the
two things we're doing it the next week
I need to turn a key before class it's
like yeah finish reading and nothing
worked at all you know looks like yeah
of course nothing ever worked so tiny
and so part of the process is you know
something I've been trying to kind of
talk to Brad about with you know his
work is like
recognizing that every time you build
something new it won't work means that
you need to build it in a very different
way right like right and I apply for the
notebook as if you're going to be
teaching at next Sunday's class right
because the closet won't work the first
time you're going to have to go back and
if you like which one of these steps a
great so at every step you want to be
printing out a result summarizing the
best you know the keys kisstixx drawing
pictures writing down the reasoning that
you did things you know so that then
when it doesn't work you could go back
and be like okay where where does this
go wrong for even better hopefully
seeing the mistake earlier on rather
than waiting for for finish so there's a
whole lot of like data science process
sets which you know those of you that
watch data scientists will be pretty
familiar with by now hopefully and those
of you that haven't it's really a case
of bringing in the software engineering
money set there are lots of testing of
iterations the more data scientists can
learn about software engineering
practices early together um so
very interestingly today or maybe
yesterday thanks books it announced that
they have implemented a enormous
improvement in the state of the art and
approximate nearest editors so you can
check us out if you like our essay is
safe by the way everything I've
mentioned here I've mentioned earlier on
Twitter right so if you follow me on
Twitter or you know my Twitter account
you'll see all these things first
regardless of whether class is still
running or not so this was particularly
interesting to me you know a because
I've been talking quite a bit during
this part of the course about
approximate nearest neighbor it's
actually really important for deep
learning and you can get a sense of how
important is by how much Facebook
invested in this right this is a
multi-gpu distributed approximately rasa
native system that runs about ten times
faster than the previous set of the are
now I could to get a particular insight
into this because the earlier this week
I was at a conference at Berkeley since
thanks very much to Melissa you know
about the conference and texture
national people conference living me in
the day before when it had been for four
months and I chatted to young lagoon and
I chatted to him about this thing I've
been thinking about a lottery that's
part of course about transfer weather
you know and like you know how come
people seem to always use vgg so to the
best transfer learning results when
there are so much better than systems
around and you know I've been really
coming to this conclusion that the
reason is that fully convolutional nets
like Brad's match and inception net have
very very large very very redundant
intermediate representations so because
they don't have a fully connected layer
like in ResNet the penultimate layer is
seven by seven by two thousand which a
is huge and B if you look through that
seven by seven most of them were the
same more or less as their neighbors
right because most plasma energy similar
so
and if you want to go back and far
enough through enough bottleneck layers
if you actually get a fairly general
representation like we do with the gg
when we go to the first fully connected
layer you're at like 28 by 28 no 500 you
know that far too big to work with and
far too redundant so I asked John McCune
about the estimate that you know with
anybody working on the question of like
how do you capture the benefits of these
much more accurate architectures but
create efficient distributed
representations and a lacuna slivovitz
absolutely of course so where do I read
about it it is like well we visited
Facebook all the time like a Facebook we
take every object in Facebook and we
create a compressed distribute
representation of it and we save it in
databases and then we give little bits
of code to all the groups so that they
can create simple linear models on top
of these distribute representations and
like this is everywhere in Facebook and
that's like oh so it is written down
somewhere there I don't know maybe - the
technical report somewhere on and if I
don't know it's like one of these things
that I knew it must be having and so now
I know at least one company very very
big company but it's happening at a huge
scale and so when they say here that
this is used to search the multimedia
documents a similar to each other if we
read between the minds they're not
talking about looking at pixels or
samples of audio they're talking about
activations
you know distributed representations and
we know now like when we've talked about
perceptual losses for example how much
better it is for the CAPTCHA similarity
using activations than you do using
pixels so here's a huge opportunity for
this learning which sure um you know
yeah I was I'd read briefly a YouTube
paper in which they say something like
an admin I'm asking you because maybe
you have a better insight on how these
done I have been very interesting and
understanding it better so they
basically do some kind of embedding of
the user an embedding of a video which
is probably something kind of similar to
this and then so they first build is
this kind of representation of every
user and every video and then on top of
that they have another deep learning
network that actually does everything
else yeah yeah absolutely my
understanding is most as they were
vetting the based on more of a
collaborative filtering approach like it
is in Lesson four
I'm not to my knowledge they're not
doing actual video features as far as I
know so there's no reason they shouldn't
be so I now know that Facebook actually
yeah right and so thinking of thinking
about this is like I thought about this
for many years in a medical context you
know medical imaging every every medical
image you have you have a compressed
distributed representation of it such as
the first fully connected layer of vgg
it's stored in the database they want to
say a database I actually mean a fast
indexed approximate nearest neighbors
tree or structure and now you can go and
grab you know every medical image to
display similar symptoms
this medical image or whatever okay yeah
go from closure it gives me the thumbs
up
so exactly so this kind of stuff is
really exciting and it's like as far as
I know it hasn't even written down
anywhere and it's not really being used
anywhere and much other than at least
Facebook probably Google does this too
[Music]
okay so that's just a bit of background
we are going to talk about the by lsdm
hegemony and these slides come from
Chris many so he has come across Chris
Manning before fut so Chris is a
linguistics professor at Stanford
it is PhD in linguistics and at some
point in the last small number of years
he discovered that everything he learned
about it including linguistics was
basically a waste of time because now
you can throw a bidirectional lsdm word
attention at pretty much anything and
get a better result than everything from
his PhD in linguistics so nowadays he
actually teaches these learning and in
fact his deep learning for natural
language processing videos just went
online today so if you want to learn
more about that feel free so at this
conference last week this was one of the
slides
he put up he is describing Socrates
appointed about the situation it's not
where he wants linguistics to be but
there it is and so this is what we're
going to learn about today
bi-directional LSD ends with attention
so this is what happened when people
started throwing bidirectional other
schemes with attention at new york an
inflation this looks a lot like the 2012
internet picture the red is the kind of
two generations ago approach to
participant machine translation process
the purple is the last four years of the
group you know next generation approach
which is syntax based digital machine
translation neural machine translation
didn't really appear properly into a
2015 and this is the that's now on and
we're probably well beyond that now
because of course people you know
machine translation system is now online
and a lot of the stuff that's coming out
of there for the period
so actually back here at about 2013 I
actually go to the talk at one of the
academic conferences which is like a
introduction to deep learning for people
in the statistics academia who maybe
weren't familiar with it one of the
things they told them was all of you who
are in NLP start learning deep learning
now because there's no question in the
next three years or so it's going to be
the state of the art and pretty much
everything and so hopefully some of
those people listen to me and they're
very happy like even though we couldn't
exactly tell at that point how that was
going to happen it was just really
really obvious that it's like you know
it could at the system which you know
uses the triggered representations and
you know that's all the property - she
would expect to see in something with
these learning will be successful and
you know today I think increasingly
people are realizing that large areas of
basic statistics turning machine
learning and the process being replaced
so crisp a digital crisp slave Chris
described the four big winds of your own
machine translation and I think one of
the most interesting ones is number
three which is the statistical
approaches tended to use like engrams so
like these three words of here
these three words appear these three
would appear next to each other in these
situations you can't get beyond about
five grand
so this is five words because you just
get a total exponential explosion of how
big that dataset is with our own ends
remember when we very first learn about
our own ends we talk the reason why
steak for memory long-term dependencies
right so this is exactly what you want
if you want to make sure that your verb
tense and everything else lines up with
your you know details of your subject
they could be 20 words apart or more
right so we need to ever have that kind
of thing so this is where this works
very well interestingly and you know I'm
not deep in the NLP world so I wasn't
quite clear on where things are with all
of the success
yeah Chris said in his talk by all stems
with attention are the plenty are
basically everything okay and so well we
actually have an NLP person you can I
ask you a quick question Hana about it
um it this kind of line up with your
experience as you have your own like an
NLP researcher yeah my research is
mostly information abstraction but you
know first of all if Chris Manning does
it it's true okay but also difficult in
general so the other part of this is
that in some of those areas while while
this is state of the art definitely the
state of Yi ID is not that impressive
Sasori a second that's definitely true
as well isn't it but he's right like
this is what's happened people have
found that for all those guys yeah and
others which are noted for their which I
was going to similar in certain ways
that is the state of okay yeah what I
was talking about about the kind of
disappointing statuses so like a lot of
these slides actually Chris Manning had
a big frowny face and one of the
audience is like what's with the frowny
face and it's you know he is basically
describing all of the ways in which the
state of the art result still a far
short of where we want them to be so you
know NLP is by no means solved you know
we could kind of say basic image
recognition is kind of solved for basic
NLP is not resolved so that is a great
example Chris gave of something that you
know this approach has worked really
well for very difficult perfect it is to
read a story like this okay and then in
the story highlights one of the words or
what phrases is deleted and the the
neural net has to figure it out so Star
Wars is deleted will be characters in
movies have gradually become with a
burst and you have to predict Star Wars
so this is a challenging problem that
really requires some in-depth
understanding and the work that Chris
showed
here's a senior researcher on is to
basically take the query chuck it into
an embedding text the entire story chuck
it into an R and n check the error in
that comes out to the whole thing with
attention and that's it okay so let's
talk about how to do this
[Music]
so there's a really nice
so under sealed up which has a bit of a
picture of this
[Music]
imagine we're translating English into
French so here's our English okay and so
we're trying to translate
the European Economic Area so that is LA
right but that is laughs because of the
gender of the noun area so you see these
little purple lines here this is showing
that this here or network model has
learnt that when it is looking at
translating from the area and
specifically the it also needs to look
at the word area in order to figure out
that it's love
so these purple lines are showing the
weights in the neural network for
translating that particular word so when
it was translating signed this is what
I've talked about long term long
distance dependencies it's not just
using the word sign but also looking at
what was signed in order to figure out
the details of pattern how to use his
third right and in some things you know
you kind of need to look at combination
so was fine you know you have multiple
prepositions working together so we need
to come up with a architecture which is
capable of learning these attention
waves
so
as we ventured last week there's really
fun paper called grammar as a foreign
language Geoffrey Hinton with the senior
research on this one has a nice little
summary this is not where it originally
came from but as a massive summary of
how attention works so let's let's go
through it like we don't often go
through we don't often go through these
things by looking at the math but I
think in this case you know the math is
simple enough
so this is actually maybe a good
practice so let's start off by looking
for their patient okay so there's an
encoder right so remember the end coder
is the R and n or number of layers of
our an N which you're going to look
through the original source sentence so
in this case the English sentence can it
kind of spit out a hidden state right
and if in carrots we say returns Lincoln
physicals true we'll get ahead in state
after every single English word ok so if
you've got ten words in the English
sentence we'll have 10 pieces of encoder
set so the encoder state they're going
to call it h all right and so here
remember these things that are
underneath or on the top generally just
the same as in lump I as putting single
square brackets right
so what they're doing here is they're
telling us that ta so easier ta is the
number of words in the English sentence
okay so we've got one through ta get to
the safe each one's called H so that's
the encoder isn't there and then the
decoder as you run through each step
trying to translate this thing into
French is getting its own creating its
own hidden space that's difficult D and
D will go as far as TV that will be the
highest in debt of the French
so in the end our goal is to replace
every one of these so we can write these
as d-t needing each one of these items
of decoder see we're going to try and
create something called
the - see which is going to represent
the result of this attention process
right so basically it's going to
represent the the word and it says the
representation in the hidden state of
the word for area waited quite a lot and
economic weight is a little bit and
everything else - not much at all so not
surprisingly the way to do that is with
is with
a weighted sum okay so here remember H
that's out in code of C okay so that's
the state from the RNN run over that
English sentence okay so the word for
area and circle
yes picture now we have a question to
clarify in this case instead of creating
one condensed representation vector that
captures the entire English sentence
here are we just looking at the existing
hidden states that get generated as the
English sentence is processed word by
word yeah exactly it's just a difference
between the terms because it equals true
versus pathetic and six equals false so
it's true it just throws away everything
except the last state so but this is
false throw away everything to the last
state the ten seconds equals true is
keep it over ones in the middle and
remember importantly this is a pie LS TM
a bidirectional lsdm right so we've got
one LS TM going forward through the
sentence and another one going backwards
through the center's so every one of
these pieces of encoded hidden state
represents all of the words before it in
that order and all of the words a
stretch in your verse order start
together
and remember also it be layers so that's
like quite a few layers little layers of
nonlinear neural net layer that's going
on now so that's what is a state comes
from so yeah so each element of H is
already a pretty complex calculation to
get there pretty sophisticated
calculation and so we're going to take
those and we're going to multiply them
by some weight some weight and the
weight see how the weights got to index
are done that means that the weight
depends on two things one is T which is
which word in the French translation am
I trying to create right now and I which
is which piece of encoded hidden state
am I currently calculating the weight
for right so and because this is being
calculated with a function you know in
if we
- with probably the you know writing
like get wait you know T comma I okay
and so the line of father tells you how
to go about car planning that way but
and it tells you not surprisingly that's
a calculate that wait we're going to be
using soft Max and we're going to be so
using soft Maps on top of some other
function so why soft max well if we're
doing the weighted sum we want the
weights to add up to 1 that's one reason
secondly most of the time in translation
the thing that you're translating is
largely just one word okay so 1992 is
translated as 1992 I don't even know how
to say that that's you know best serve
this August right then sometimes it's
mainly one word like in but a little bit
of other so it's soft max because it's
eated of something divided by sum of e
to the something remember it tends to be
very big of just one item in the vector
and fairly small for everything out but
by using soft masks we capture that
quite naturally so that's why that's why
we use soft maps to calculate influence
that so softmax of you correct you with
another function or the result of
another function and what is this this
is just a multi-layer perceptron with
one hidden layer a neural net with one
hidden layer if you have a look
a couple of bits of data multiplied by
weight matrices
put to a non-linearity x and other
weight metrics but through another loop
non-linearity so that's the definition
of a neural net with one hidden layer so
when it all comes down to it what this
all says is in order to calculate the
weights on each of the source encoding
words for each of the target translated
word train a tiny little neural net with
one hidden layer which learns to figure
out which soft words translate down okay
and so remember one of the things that
Chris mentioned in his like what way is
your machine translation good one of his
reasons was because it's end-to-end
trainable we're going to invest this
many neural net inside the bigger R and
n so the whole thing is going to be just
fgz all in one go
okay so that's what we're going to try
and do
make sure that clear before we look at
the code that how to do it anybody a
couple persons there they're just quick
so how's our hidden state looks like is
it like set of activations yeah so the
he says it's just a normal LSD and
hidden safe so it's just a data if they
go back to we got a question right over
there
so anytime like you want to remind
yourself of what's really going on with
iron ends go back to this lesson 5 iron
in PowerPoint because we go through and
we remember like ok this is not an iron
end you know here's a basic neural net
and we could like have a multi-layered
neural net and then we can have a
multi-layer neural net which we have a
second input coming in still not on our
end we could have two things something
in a treatise of x and then we could
also tie these weight matrices and the
the notebook that goes with this part we
do all this like by hand in care out of
all the web time and everything's you
see every set and then we realize oh
that last picture could have been drawn
like that okay
and we also realized we could do this as
well right so so all of these circles
represent just a bunch of applications
of the vector validation and so we have
a bunch of these layers until eventually
we decide to keep some final set of
ambition so this is this is all we're
doing and so then the I don't want to
call the attentional model yeah it's
relatively simple it's just a single
single thing load and there's other
reason that it wasn't more complex or
some fancy architecture you know I'd be
wondering with those I don't know
I guess the answer is it seems to work
you know there's no reason you couldn't
have too many motors I guess you know
it's so easy to go back and look and see
what the attentions are presumably so
far they're basically using this they're
finding that the essential model is
getting the correct size I think if
you're trying to do an attentional model
for something else and that doesn't
happen so yeah check another layer in
fact how'd this up this terrific post
actually shows a really cool example of
this which is on the bottom here as a
sound wave and on the top is the speech
recognition and so you know people are
actually using attention models to
automatically do speech recognition by
figuring out which parts of the sound
wave represented which butters and in
fact one of the super cool things to
come out this this week was the taco
trot which is one of the best names
repect I've come across and the taco
Tron
have some fantastic examples actually of
what it sounds like
nominees if I can guess
[Music]
basilar membrane and Oh charlie rangel
gr not autocorrelation so the cool thing
here is like it changes depending on
like where the punctuation is pretty
aggressively or even whether those
capitals up the buses aren't the problem
they actually provide a solution
problem they actually provide a solution
or questions
so the quick brown fox jumped over the
lazy dog so with this kind of intro in
training like this right you don't have
to really build anything special and
make that happen you just need to make
sure that you're labeled data is correct
and actually somebody pointed out
something really neat the other day
which is if you want to build a speech
recognition system so one easy way to do
it would be like perhaps inaudible calm
audiobooks and the actual books and like
you could have 40 hours of training date
on of that so in fact if you grab the
Stephen Fry reading Harry Potter and you
could like have that every Harry Potter
voice as well so this is a this is a
super amazing technique and surprisingly
enough this single hidden layer seems to
be enough to do attention pretty well so
last week we were looking at the
spelling bee right whether you don't
input were things like the the key and
we were having to figure out to sell it
to wiki we tried it without attention
and we didn't get great results we
looked at the paper from the original
battle or a towel paper that shows that
with longer sentences in particular you
get much better results if you do use
attention so let's have a look and see
what that looks like so here US doesn't
really have anything to do this
effectively so I have to write something
so before I show what I wrote let me
describe kind of what it looks like most
of it looks exactly the same as the
original spelling bee model we have our
list of phonemes at the input we have
our list of letters spell the word with
as our decoder decoder input we check
them both through embedding
we then do a bidirectional are an M on
the phoneme and then we check and hone
in on top of that and check inherently
on top of that right you might remember
from last time is Karen in function just
to remind you it just was returning in
our cm and by default we're saying
returns because because true perhaps the
last week the final one was get our own
in false we put everything into a single
little package and then we set that to
the RN but now we're leading return
sequences equals true all the way
through so that we can then pass that to
this special attention layer that I've
created we're looking at how this works
at the moment but let's first of all
talk about like what does an intention
layer need it needs to know what kind of
RNN layer do you wanted to create right
so I just passed it a function which
creates inherit in layer
okay I'm in your decoder how many layers
do you want to create so I say okay
create three lsdm layers in the decoder
and then what information is it going to
need to create that it's going to need
these all of the encoder States versus
sitting in here and then we can do
something else to make it easier we can
do two encored teacher forcing and the
teacher forcing is when you're going to
pass it as well as the encoded state
we're going to pass it the answer but
we're going to pass it the answer for
the previous time period right so in
other words if we're trying to learn how
to spell the wiki at set one we're not
going to pass it anywhere at set two
were part of Z at step three were part
of Y therefore were part of W in other
words we're going to tell it what the
previous time steps correct answer was
why do we do that it makes it much
easier to train tickly early on but
early on it has no idea how to spell and
so it gets most things wrong most of the
time and so the let the later letters
everything's wrong before it so happy to
possibly know what letter to use now
okay so with teacher fourteen we're
going to take our sign Churchill we're
going to take our input data being all
of those encoded hidden state but we're
also going to tell us all right even if
you've got the previous letter wrong
this is what I should have seen right
and so it's just it's going to make it a
bit easier for it and all we do is we
just concatenate together the giving
space plus that that decoder input so
that's called teacher 40 right you don't
have to use teacher forcing but if you
do it just makes it faster and easier to
train so that's why we pass in this
special decoder input
and just to show you the decoder imports
yeah the decoder input
okay yeah so if all of my labels right
except not the very last one okay so
it's going to be one less to the full
number of items to film lettuce the cell
and then I can calculate a column of one
on to the front now why is the column of
plot so one with x go token and then go
token with something that I set up on
that here here yeah I decided that an
asterisk right so an Asterix is going to
be like a special character which mean
this is the start of the word okay so
we're going to get past every time going
to get past before the wiki we'd get
past
Asterix then why WIC 10 that's that's
going to be this teacher 14 informal
okay so this attention layer is going to
create a three layer RM it's going to
get given all of the encoded states
going to get given that special decoder
input and it's going to spit out just
the list of six again and so we can just
do the usual thing of doing a time
distributive dense with our appropriate
boat capsized softmax to turn that into
child target activations so putting it
aside how we calculate this everything
else is pretty familiar and so we can
let's go ahead build that model compiler
fish passing in both the the phonemes
and those decoder inputs trainer for a
while
bit of annealing trended a bit more
until eventually we have actually a
pretty good accuracy 51 percent and here
it is did you have a question here sure
yes there's a question do you know if
the current work strictly uses the
hidden states of the final RNN layer or
if people try using attention sums over
different indices over multiple layers
the way we did in using perceptual loss
for multiple layers you know that's
actually a great question the answer is
to a knowledge people are always using
the last layer it is same but I kind of
accidentally use all of them once and
got some better results so I don't know
if I screwed something up or if this is
a good idea so that might be something
if you want to test it in order to try
it out yeah I was like after fixing a
bug things got worse it's a different
with fine so maybe it's not a bug after
all um so remember last time we had
trouble with a really long words we love
the funny but here's a
phonemes and it's done it perfectly
actually that's a good sign that this is
handling some longer ones pretty well
and you know is 51% good or bad
I don't know right because like spelling
is you know it's not exact right there's
no way you could algorithmically get
100% going like is it Mississippi speak
like this or speak like this you consume
a test set right there's no way for to
know so I think it's done pretty well so
the only thing remaining is how to do
this tension layer so the bad news is
that the attention layer is the largest
[Music]
the largest
custom layer we've looked out and it's
not terrible but it's a it's a hundred
lines of code okay but a lot of its kind
of pretty repetitive so it really
depends how interested you are a in
custom layers and be in attention as to
how much you want to look at this some
but basically I'll show you the key
features right there are two really
important methods that they're called in
your custom layer and they are Bill and
called
build is the method that's called in
your custom layer when your layer is
actually inserted into a neural network
and that that causes get built right
when once it's inserted into a into a
carrot neural network and that's the
point at which it knows how big
everything has to be right because
you're told and having the input was and
then you've got the another various
layers connected for each other and so
eventually you can figure out how beat
is you know in fact specifically what is
the shape of the input right so when
your build method is called you get told
what is the shape of your input and this
is the point where you now have to set
everything up to work with that input
shape now in this case bill would get
called as soon as it finishes running
this line right because it knows that it
got this input right and it can figure
out this input shape by going all the
way back to this
now we have two inputs and we have the
encode of state and the decoder input so
we can follow the part in to the encoder
shape and the decoded internship
so some things we've seen like they
might be hard actually incredibly easy
to create my three layers are items is a
single line of code remember I just
passed in the air and end generating
function grab Titus column for each
player right and with a list
comprehension I now have there is three
RNN loads in a list that is easy on the
other hand to do this I'm going to have
to do it all by hand right and in fact
there's some things are being hidden
here for example a bias term is not
included here but if we definitely want
one it's like people often don't include
bias term because you'd like to convoys
avoid it by like adding a column of one
your data so like it's common in math
not to mention the highest term they're
federally speaking anytime you see the
neural net and let's say state otherwise
there's probably a virus in there so we
have to in build we're going to have to
create
W 1 W 2 and V ok to create them Kerris
actually has a convenient method that
comes from the layer superclass called
Edward right so add ways you basically
say if I want the size of the weight
matrix
plus your initialization function and
give it a name so I just took that and
brought it W right so here I guess go
wwwww passing in all right so if W one
topic is second a bit W to have a good
second of these here's my bias because
that going to be is my V so because that
going to be and then I've got two other
things here which is the w3 the p3 and
that's because this is kind of hand
braved over something which is this
final answer basically needs to become
the hidden state right of your next
layer of the RNN but it might not be the
right size so then I just added one more
transformation to the end to basically
make it the red silence and in some of
the attention model cases they to lay
that out so I don't know like whether
Insurance Group
just ignore it or maybe they built it so
that the shapes work anyway I don't know
so we've got one extra one extra half
and transmission a minor note for those
of you have played with high score I'm
sure you've discovered how cool it is
that you can go self add module and it
keeps track of like everything that you
need to train or the parameters Terrace
is not so clever so that's why we have
to go self to add weight to every one of
these weights
I'm compare us have to know what to
train when you optimize what should you
train unfortunately when we created all
these are n ends
these are a tens of lots of weights
which we haven't told Cara that we need
to optimize them so I actually hadn't I
have not found any examples of custom
layers anywhere on the internet where
people have actually done this but I
figured out what you can do is you can
basically press this little function
that go through every one of my layers
every one of those are and in layers and
find all the attributes that Kaos needs
to know about so it needs to know what
at the trainable weights and on general
weights losses up and constraints so
anyway you can copy and paste this code
if you want to create a custom layer
which is self-contained some chaos
layers of intensive code and it seems to
work
that is really much ok so that's the
first main thing you have to create when
you create a custom layer is build some
training build is really boring because
you have to get all these money
dimensions to a pre correct which is
obtained in the ER and so when I built
that I've had to fit all
bunch of like tensorflow playing around
code where I'll just keep going in and
being like okay if this is my X this is
the size of my w1 let's try you know
during each calculation so I liked it
each calculation in a Cell one step at a
time and you know look to see what other
shapes were and then with that can put
them in so you know like I don't think
any normal mortal person could like
write all of these dimensionalities in
there to get into work without doing
them one little set a plan so make
things easy for yourself so the other
key thing that happens in the lair is to
call home and call it the thing that
basically that's your just your forward
path and this is like okay this is
calculate go calculate and so you get
passed in the data the caps going on
right so in this case
come we actually have to step through
the sets of an RNN and Kara actually has
a k dot r NN function which is very very
similar to CR no dots can cause remember
theano dot sin
this is basically something which it
called some functions that each step etc
each part of your input as some initial
States and so forth but it's almost
identical to see oh no goddamn right
it's a really low level thing and so
some Terrace really doesn't have a
convenient user facing API so like
creating custom R and n code in fact
this is something which nobody's really
figured out yet tensorflow has just
released a new kind of customer and in
API but there isn't any documentation
for it
so I was hoping to feature in this
course but I think it's just a little
too early and I don't know if it's good
or not so you know this is this is like
a bit of an open question really is like
how do you create something as easy to
use as kara that with the flexibility to
design your own kind of R and n details
you know and as you can see in this case
it wasn't it wasn't convenient at all
you know I had to go back and kind of
run you know run this scan function from
scratch and set everything out good
stretch anyway so basically all the work
happens in here which means all the work
is happening in this step function I've
created but here's where the actual
calculations of them
so here's most def function and so in
the end when it actually gets to it this
now looks a lot like the Hinton team
code right
we basically can see us doing the
adoption at the bias and here's the ban
and here's the V and the softmax and
here's the bit where we do the weighted
sum right and then this is just one
extra step I mentioned which is to get
it to the right shape for the rmn again
and so now that I've done all of that
pre-processing okay - basically I
started with X and I ended up creating
this thing called H you can now go ahead
and go through all of those three RNN
calling step on each of those okay so
that you know this probably shouldn't
have been that hard in the end but it's
just the nature of kind of the chaos API
but it's stuff that doesn't really exist
that we had to go in and create it so
all we really wanted to do was say okay
Kara before you run the free decoder
ardennes
take your input and modify it in this
way okay so that's but we have to do it
for every sin you know that's basically
what was missing is some wearing
character easily say to say like change
the extent so I've spoken to France well
you know the careless offer about this
is well aware that it is not convenient
right now and he really wants to fix
this but I mean this is difficult to get
right no one's quite done it yet
and we have a question and I didn't get
to getting it to the right shape again
part could you explain that again
children so dead thank you for the
question
set it's being called for every time set
so at the end of it we have to return
the new hidden set and then that new
hidden state is going to come back into
the next step right so in other words
the thing that we end up with here needs
to be the same shape as we had here
right so but it that doesn't happen you
know automatically because we're
actually taking this this weighted sum
and we're actually contaminating onto it
the decoder input we end up with
something that's a totally different
shape so but you can always change the
shape of state by chucking a trivial mo
multiplying it by a matrix where the
thing you multiply it by it has a number
of columns if you want to create right
so Plato's made sure the w3 has the same
number of columns as as the H that we
want add and so as a result but by the
end of this we've got something which we
can feed back into the errand and again
you know we just need to make sure you
know what R and n set can't change the
shape that it started with writes it
needs to be able to keep going set set
set every step things to be the same
emphasize
and you showed how you figured out
tested the tensor shapes how did you do
bug the attention class itself as a
whole our RNs easier and cleaner and PI
torch with the attention class have been
relatively easier in by torch
what if I told you Rebecca
so the main thing for me to see if I
really was built right because this bit
is Jeffrey humans or nativity scenes
equations right there's not too much to
get wrong here so really it was the
cases like I'm doing it as if they like
step by step in cells and printing out
the shape at each point and you'll see
that like I created these
you know all of these different
dimensions at the side right and I made
sure all of these numbers are different
so that every time I saw the number 64 I
knew that was the batch size to live
contort for I'm you go time steps 32 is
the input then 48 of the opportunity so
I could go through and I could see okay
is my shaky a push up here and then you
know all I just did was I just chucked
in some print statements you know print
HW to print you with a and so forth and
so I didn't even see the contents of
them when you print a tensor flow tensor
like that it prints the dimensions of it
which in my experience once your
dimensions work you're done and as long
as you didn't make the mistake of having
multiple things having the same number
of dimensions because it's like you know
as long as your product you know this
and you know if if H and W 2 didn't line
up for rows and columns you know the
error you get is pretty clear you know
it'll be a tensor flow play the mismatch
and show you what the dimensions are and
so you can you know so generally
speaking getting these things a mess
isn't too bad yeah I don't know it's no
fun at all but it's kind of menial if
you know you'll get there of industries
so now that's done you know I've written
it right so feel free to use it as you
can see it's easy to use and at the end
you know we get these pretty good
results one thing to point out is when
we go
so we get the predictions right by the
same model dropper date for that test
set right and then those predictions
you'll notice we go split while its uses
later one predictions
fikriye not split on underscore why'd we
spit on underscore and that's because
when I created the vocabulary earlier on
I fit underscore to be the zero element
and remember that all of our words are
padded at the end of zeros so when the
decoder predicts that this is the end of
the word it's going to spit out zero or
underscore right so this is a kind of
power decoder knows to stop now
it doesn't actually stop like in terms
of computation the decode is still going
to keep plant letting all of the rest of
the sense because we don't have the
ability at least in care us to say stop
now you know everything is rectangled so
hopefully the decoder learned pretty
quickly that if the previous token was
underscore the next token will always be
underscore right once you finish this
sandwich so that's a minor issue then
okay so that's that so we're going to
have a seven minute break and when we
come back we're going to see this in PI
torch we're going to use it for actual
language translation so I'll see you at
eight o'clock
[Music]
so I am so happy to see so one of our
students some into like a visit study
group a couple of weeks ago and was like
writing all these like I can values and
eigenvectors equations allow to do any
like idea is something in this style
transferred like we can apply concealer
sorry to sing keep going and out of them
last week I liked ordering some more and
this button looks and strains noisy
teachable experience then on Friday you
know quite a few of us got together
that's recent hacking in you know I
still sorry I'm doing the same thing I
know there's something here if we get
close and just told me he sent me an
email so here is a photo and here is a
painting and here is the regular style
transfer results so that and here is
what happens when you use his new
mathematical technique it's almost
similar so hopefully by next week I
won't understand it enough that that
anymore actually explain it to you but I
know what are the key differences is
actually using the earth moves in the
distance which is the basis that there
was a sign game about this idea so I've
been to avoid teaching about eigenvalues
and eigenvectors over which oh yeah I
don't know how we're going to do that
anyway that is like yeah so there this
is a breakfast yeah this is this has got
to be a paper like yeah you know if you
disappear to the whole new change this
is super exciting so congratulations I
look forward to learning more about
you know people just keep doing cold
sauce I love it
you know you guys just different along
you
[Music]
all right so
so let's translate English into French
right now here the problem the the
teacher for thing
this is fun Oh question I was then going
to say just the two questions I think
from right before the break
one was could we use time distributed
lambda right before the RNN okay so so
no you can't so what this question is
getting at is like you know why don't we
use the lambda player to do the you know
the the attention calculations and then
feed that into the sand and irn but
remember those calculations are being
done inside the set function right so in
other words each step uses attention to
calculate the output of the step which
impacts the next set so if you inside
the are an end
you can't just pre-process the whole lab
then the next question was is there any
reason why we used hyperbolic tanh as
opposed to sigmoid no no reason middle
so so hyperbolic tanh and Sigma way to
the same thing hyperbolic tanh mission -
one - one second with custom 0 to 1 the
size is fine
okay teacher for thing with this thing
where we're concatenating the the
previous correct answers embedding with
our attention weighted encoder inputs in
order to kind of help our staff our
model to kind of keep track of where at
or feed and that helps the trading now
there's nothing wrong with training that
way but we can't use that at inference
time at test time but because you don't
know the correct answer
so Mike Harris model here is totally
cheating right I'm passing in the
previous letters correct answer to every
set but in real life I don't know that
so what we actually need to do is to an
inference time you don't use teacher
forcing but instead you take the
predicted previous tense result and feed
it in for the next step but
I have no idea how to do that in Paris
like it drove me crazy trying to figure
out how to do that in terror and that
was the thing that pushed me to high
polish right is they just I was so sick
of these goddamn attention player the
idea of like going back and sort of put
this thing in drove me crazy and I don't
even know how to do it
furthermore we actually want this to be
dynamic it turns out the best way if you
use teacher forcing the whole time you
actually end up with a model that gets
like sloppy it like it learns to take
advantage of the fact that it's about to
be told what the previous thing should
have been so it kind of uses a more
speculative approach right so actually
the best training approaches as it goes
through the epochs initially it is a
teacher forcing every time and like
halfway through it uses teacher for
theme randomly half the time and that
the RC fuck it doesn't use teachers
hosting at all right so kind of learns
to wean itself off this extra
information
and that kind of dynamic thing except
this really hard or maybe even
impossible to do in serra so for all
these reasons I moved to the play torch
okay I haven't done all of these things
in parks which I've done most of them
but like the dynamic changing a teacher
for thing I've actually left to one of
you guys to try out anyway the basic
ideas right here so let's look at the
plight watch version interesting
windpipe watch version in terms of like
the attention model itself turns out to
be way easier but we have to write more
code because there's less structure for
NLP models like the computer vision
stuff there's a place for vision project
which has all that loading and models of
blah blah blah we don't seem to happen
NLP kind of version of that so there's a
bit more code to write here anyway so
let's translate English to French and so
what I did was I downloaded this there's
Giga French corpus which I'll put a link
to on the wiki basically this is a
really cool idea what this researcher
did was he went to lots of Canadian
websites and and use the screen scraper
to figure out whether there was a little
button saying switch from English to
French and the screen space it would
automatically click the button and then
assume that those are two screens were
the same right and then he tokenizing in
two sentences and provides this corpus
of like a billion words so this is
pretty great I didn't really want to
create like a complete English French
translator because I just didn't have
the time to run it for long enough so I
try to think okay what's like a an
interesting subset of English to French
so I thought okay what if we learn to
translate English questions that start
with WH so right through where Y right
you know and so when I looked at
it turns out that that words yes and
that was something you know veterans
like eighty thousand or there's a lot of
sentences basically that the nice thing
is that all of those sentences are you
know have a somewhat similar structure
so it's like if we're going to learn
everything about translating English
into French that we're going to be doing
it with a slight subset so that's why I
did this
read check which says okay look the
things that start with WH and then with
a creditor mark keen English and where
the French can be anything at all but it
should end with a question mark okay so
I went through the French and English
files this is really cool trick we've
mentioned once before that once you go
open in pipes and that returns a
generator that you can look through and
so if use if the tree together you put
the English questions and offensive
questions and then just go through and
run the regex
and then return the ones that both of
the regex kamesh okay so here's some is
offensive stance so it's good and that
they can see a lot of them are really
simple and you know some of them are
more complex if the usual jump that the
people file so we promoted increase
another alright so we've got the English
question to the French press
and I will show you all the steps to a
real-world NLP so you can like to see
all the pieces we're going to do
everything by hand so you can get attend
to the class see what happens so the
next step is tokenization so a
tokenization is taking in a sentence and
turning it into a number or basically in
two words but this is not quite
straightforward because like what's a
word right so is
[Music]
is that a word okay or is that a word
or is better word okay and so you know I
had to make some decisions based on my
view of what was likely to work and
which especially is like okay I think
that's a word and so I just wrote so
regular expressions right for doing kind
of heuristic tokenization now you can
use NLP K the national language toolkit
that has a bunch of tokenizer
in honestly though I actually found my
hockey rules best techno sir
like I was happier with it than any of
the energy that they took notice I trade
for this problem so you can see that
basically for example if you have any
letter followed by apostrophe s correct
then I want you to make the apostrophe s
a word right because it's kind of more
like odd than anything else or else if
it's a letter followed by an apostrophe
followed by a letter that's probably
French in which case everything has to
the apostrophe is one word and
everything after it is another work
right so you can basically see it again
I'm tokenize the French curve s curve ba
boom ba okay that is exactly what I want
and here's English right and so then let
the test a very accurate statement like
Rachel's baby his tutors and others is
and you can see here the apostrophe s's
okay doing the right thing first to the
atrocity little okay so check out my
tokenizer
or looks good with that statement
directions baby as well so all good so
now that we've got that tokenizing we
can go ahead and like do the standard
thing that we do every time we work with
an LP which is to turn our visitors
words and promises numbers okay we
always do the same way basically create
a vocabulary for the olive bottle words
and health and there's here some insert
padding character and insert the start
of a stream character this is like the
asterisk in the previous one so create
the reverse mapping from words yd by
using this little enumerate tricks
and then go through every sentence and
turn it into a list of tokens I call in
math dictionary and you have a question
for motivation
you need a stammer before you and what
into numbers no no not at all
we different words for different things
about different words you have different
translations so we want to keep them
that healthy you know the tokenizer
really is just too
is to do something that we think we can
do in a purely rule-based way the
question of like how do we deal with
morphological differences is actually
highly complex there is like my language
you want to learn it in New York all
right so this is going to end up
returning the list of ID's for each
sentence the vocabulary the reversal
temporary and just a frequency count for
the Ojeda room great next step is to
turn these words into work vectors so
earlier on we used word to back because
word Tyvek has these like multi word
things but for translation I don't want
more solidity so a single word is so
that's why I'm going to use love so go
ahead and turn that into a dictionary
from the word to the work vector also
grab some French word vectors found
those represent active site that's got
some nice French word Lexus
and so now go ahead and build little
things that can go through my vocabulary
create a big array of zeros and then go
ahead and fill in all of those zeros
with word vectors
if you can of course sometimes you look
up a word and it's not in your word work
that work word vector list in which case
you can just stick a random badger
mayor's day so this is all stuff we've
done many many fun in there
I also am keeping track of how often I
find the word just make sure and for
English out of 19,000 in the vocab we
find 17 point mm work vectors in love so
this is something pretty good so most of
our work vectors are being found and the
French a little bit less that you're not
bad at properly because of my particular
tokenization strategy might have been
different with tech motivational
strategy they use these four pairs and
you still have the audio popping
crackling a problem from time to time
oh okay yeah I still have it in the same
mode as last time so he who used all the
juice you know
in fact letting us know the phone okay
now that of course the other thing we
have to do with NLP is to make
everything rectangular notice here I'm
calling a Karass function right if
carrots does something you need please
use it even if you're in pipes which is
fine right yeah I've had a number of
people they are trying to use pipes what
the heck it doesn't have a sequences or
if you're important particulate is an
FFD trainsets flinch to grab ten percent
of the data the trailer the test and
here we have it right so 47,000 train
5,000 tests and here's an example of the
French census and English sentence in
all the pen
so we can now have to do all the data
loading stuff outdoors right so I've
gone ahead and created a get batch
function that is going to go ahead and
return a random permutation of when X so
when X is the length of all of our
senses so this is going to return and
then grab the first batch size of them
this will return 16 random numbers
between 0 and 47,000 and 97 and so then
I can just return those for English and
little French so it's okay if you don't
have a data loader right this is all it
actually takes to create a basic
generator and this is basically doing
the same thing as a generator if you
don't need any data organization and
again you know here's a piece of code
you can still write you need a generator
inside torch is this a generator if I
push past it in your data and your
labels in your batch size a little
portion
I'm about to reach
all right so
Shadis I mentioned last time that I
created broadcasting functions for pi
torch and that you can see what has
happened was I had all this chaos code
that worked and I want to support its
high polish and PI torch doesn't have
broadcasting so none of this stuff
worked and like so my paid torch was
like way more complex than my own terror
because there was not tweezing done
squeeze your buttocks and everywhere so
I wrote add subtract multiply divide and
dot such that they'd have the exact same
broadcasting phonetic cetera this is
actually pretty interesting and I really
wish I had time to show you that maybe
you can have a look visitor in the week
and ask questions on the forum because
it's a little code right so the amount
of code to make all of that work is
basically that and then it's incredibly
little code but importantly I also want
to show you how I build this time I
always use test-driven development for
this kind of thing so basically I
created a whole bunch of matrices
sectors three-dimensional senses and
four-dimensional senses transposed
versions of them wrote something that
checks the two things are the same and
then I just go ahead went ahead and like
tried making sure that all of these
things ought to be the same as all these
other things and first of all I wrote it
you know all the tests and then I
gradually went through and putting
clothes to the test started the pattern
and then I went back and kept
refactoring the code into another super
and similar so you can see in the end
you don't all of multiple functions at
most and small and what this meant was I
could now write an attention model using
almost exactly the same notation as
before you know so that was how I
created these broad customer roads
okay so given the David here is a non
attention encoder and so you can see
basically all it is is create some
embeddings create a groove and then in
the forward pass run the embedding and
then run the crew on there okay and in
pi torch a grew you can you don't have
to actually write three crews next to
each other you can just see number of
players equals and that's going to set
the crews on top of each other okay so
that's that i'm pretty straightforward
the decoder is also pretty
straightforward again create the
embeddings
groove
okay for the decoder we also need a
linear layer at the end and care us to
this dense layer which is the correct
size for our output vocabulary right we
actually have to remember to that
inference time we don't just want the
stake we actually want to get out
something that we can let do an argument
on defined out like which word as we
just can say do this into so we needed
this layer eternity to the correct size
actually for the French vocabulary close
so the forward parts here is a little
different as you'll see when we get to
where we actually use this this is
actually just
a single step and so this is basically
just you doing one letter at a time as
you'll see when we get here and here's
the actual
softmax on the fence layer that we've
created ptosis embedding grew dense
layer soft matters okay and we returned
both the new hidden state if she'll be
using some for the next step as well as
the actual results of the output
friends that's all fun so here's the
attention decoder and as you can see
resonating a hundred lines of code it's
a screen on my arm okay
and the nice thing is this is all
basically the same as carrots right my
w123 my b2 tree movi my brew right and
then my final output um and then this is
basically all the same as carrots as
well right so I've got my life dodging
add and multiply sauce max is the
weighted sum is that catch it's a w3 ad
on the bias or groove and in and slayer
Huffman's
again we both return the
and actual predictions as well as they
face
now the thing is we have to write our
own training okay this is high polish so
we're going to have to go ahead and do a
bit more work here so basically here's
the code that trains in epoch okay
create an optimizer for the encoder and
optimize of the decoder the criterion is
you know what they call the the loss
function negative likelihood percentage
cross-entropy
here's that get batch function we
created ourselves earlier to grab one
batch of French in English put them onto
the GPU and then call crane some of that
at the moment keep check out the last
and say the time cringe at a loss so all
the works actually had in train which is
here like you should these things that's
left in the screen of code from Julian
on we had to write it ourselves
so encode our decoder an encoder and
remember with PI torch you have to
manually call zero bread perhaps you
have to zero out the gradient at the
side of your training loop and then go
through each word in your target we've
already in codebook and call the decoder
cutting in the decoder input the hidden
state and the encoded output and so then
next to each other important comes out
there key check the loss and then we
have to call drop backward manually we
have to call the optimizer set manually
returner
so it's not very interesting code and
it's a kind of stuff which has two specs
you know hopefully the pipes watch
community emitting some of us will all
be able to contribute to getting rid of
all this boilerplate kind of code kind
of care us so over time I'm sure that
will happen
anyways but now there's the code now
that it's there we can create our
encoder we can create our attention
decoder we can train it for a while and
then we can test it now potassium I need
another function for X I want to turn
off teacher 14 right so you'll see in
this function this is not very well
reflected and copy to encourage the
effort to get basically a end code and
then I go through my target length for
the decoder that look here I now take my
decoder output and find the top one this
is basically I've maxed that's insane
okay what what word is we predict so
we're not using teacher frosting what
I'm saying what was the actual word
because that'd be cheating we're saying
what words we predict right so that now
becomes the input to the next loop right
so this is how we've turned off teacher
14 so there are kind of exercise for one
or more of you guys this week if you're
interested is to do the thing I told you
earlier which is to kind of combine this
with the training loop and make the
training loop as it goes through the eat
box gradually move from always using
teacher 14 to over time randomly using
it less and less and less and come up
the very end it never used the texture
forcing and always uses this if you get
that working it's just what's active
long I think it's pretty straightforward
you'll get better test results what I'm
showing you here okay anyway let's test
it
so to approach to English we're
basically going to take our French
sentence turn it into a list of ID's
like tokenizing X and things like these
adding up the zeros all that evaluates
function I just showed you and then join
it together
there it is
so this was the correct English this was
the French we were given and this was
our prediction so you know it's not the
same but it's still correct you know as
a seeker so that's looking pretty good
so
there it is there's translation um I
guess there's a couple of things I
wanted to briefly mention one is a
literal stuff that you guys complain
with a fugitive
this decoding loop there's much better
ways to do it but what I'm doing here by
taking the top one every time is I'm
assuming in the decoder that the top
prediction is the correct one but what
is like two words for a nearly 50 CV
that is a 51% is one 49% and I go are 72
51 percent that might be a bad idea and
and so I'm going to actually feel some
slides from frame unique from lara
institute of science technology who has
been shown a fantastic simple example of
what you could do instead so he's doing
something slightly different which is to
say what if we had a sentence like
natural language processing bracket and
LP bracket and your job was to figure
out not how to translate it but to
figure out what part of speech each of
those things were and these are weird
letters are on penn treebank part of
speech tags and is noun
she is adjectives CBS verb left bracket
right great so the correct answer is
that natural isn't adjectives and
languages are now on and processing of a
now in circle this would be the correct
path through these options now how would
you create this time well you could
start out by figuring out how likely
natural is in language in general to be
a noun
versus an adjective this is the verb and
so forth and then having done that so
every single one of those you can figure
out how likely it is stretch one of
these two
then be a noun and then to be an
adjective in the river and so forth and
if you keep repeating this process
adding up the log predictions all the
way along all the way to the end and
pick the path with truth the best now
the problem is of course is that that's
basically five times five times five to
see if you really have five choices you
know exponentially combos and remember
in our case we're not picking from five
things we're picking from forty thousand
or twenty thousand whatever in order the
vocabulary of our french language things
this is called a Viterbi algorithm so
the Viterbi algorithm for machine
translation is np-complete if you
haven't come across that before it
basically means together
okay so let's not do that
but I'm sure you can see how obvious the
the answer is rather than doing the
Viterbi algorithm why don't we just pick
the top few hypotheses so far okay so if
here are the scores for what is the word
natural it's probably not a left bracket
it's probably not a right bracket right
it might be one of these okay well let's
assume it's one of the top three right
okay so given it's one of the top three
what might be next right and again just
pick the top three accommodations and
keep going through there as it is called
beam search in practice every
state-of-the-art algorithm for neural
language translation uses this for
decoding now writing this again it's
going to be less than the screen of code
I haven't written it why not go write it
it'll get sweet added to this code add
beam search like it here's the entire to
their code right and I'm sure you could
write it in probably less crate in there
so they've been searched there's one
thing permission you have to make sure
we have two questions but kind of going
back to you
yeah I'm done with these fish and one is
do you know if there are any training
methods that capture the fact that what
is the population of Canada and what is
Canada's population are very nearly the
same I thought but I'm not sure these
matters because
on average you know you're you know a
better system will be one which you know
translate so just a tiny the one versus
the other like the best the best
translator approach I don't think it's
going to varies depending on the answer
to that question so I'm not sure that
it's that important
MNM could we translate between Chinese
and English you doesn't say method yes
we can but it would be better if we use
a technique you're going to show you
names
so the picnic I'm going to show you next
subscribe in
[Music]
this paper
um neuro machine collection of rare
words with sub word use so interestingly
this actually came up say when I was
chatting to grab and Bradford asking me
how do I create an analysis of people's
tweets using their particular vocabulary
that makes it like you know not fall
apart if they use some word in the
future that I haven't seen before right
and that's a very similar question to
how do I translate language when
somebody uses the word I hadn't seen
before or more generally you know maybe
I don't want to use one hundred and
sixty thousand words in my vocabulary
not the huge embedding make sure it
takes a lot of memory it takes a lot of
time is going to be hard to train so
what do you do and so the answer is you
use something called the p/e which is
it's basically an encoder
[Music]
and what it's going to do is going to
take attention like hello I am Jeremy
all done come on and it's going to
basically say okay I'm going to try and
turn this into a list of tokens that
aren't necessarily the same as the words
and so the first I'm going to do is
going to look at every pair of whether
h-e-l-l-o and so forth to my whole
training set I'm going to say which pair
of letters is the most time and so maybe
the answer is
pyaare okay so I take those two and I
turn them into a so we start off with
like every character separate so we know
how to combine these into a single
entity court er right and then I go
through when I do that again and maybe
the next answer is that actually a.m.
appears a lot so they're not going to
take that turned that into a m and so
maybe the next thing is actually any are
a is the next most common thing editing
fine so now we check this
and replace it with the re
and it kick Terenas but you never cross
word boundaries so so in theory we could
do this forever until we end up
eventually with the words again but
instead what happens with this vpa
encoder is you provide a single
parameter which is what is the maximum
number of combiners you want to do like
a common default below 10,000 so at the
end of that you're going to end up with
like 10,000 sub word sequences so both
will end up like churning this sentence
in something like HCl
hello and then there's a special end of
word States I fix and a mythical B then
B like J and then ER e and then my
something like that right now the cool
thing is that you can do this by going
through this github site and downloading
this and running it on your on your on
your file of pros and it will spit out
the exact same thing but it's got a
little sick an app app space between
every one of these be PE codes but so in
other words to use this with what I just
showed you you don't have to write any
code you can just take the English and
the French sentences run it through this
and it will spit out you know be PE
encoded versions because having said
that you know I think maybe the optimal
approach would be to actually write
something which first of all figured out
like which are the most common 20,000
words or ten thousand words and lets
those words alone and they only run
there the BCE encoding on the on the
thing that's really rare words because
sometimes BCE encoding actually sets
things up in ways it isn't quite what
you want okay so this is a super
important technique and so for Chinese
you know for those of you that speak
Chinese you know that it's actually not
at all clear where words to get an end
not only in our spaces but grammatically
in Chinese there are
well what example would be you could
have a sequence of two verbs where the
government adjective or Virtanen verb
which basically the second verb or
adjective describes the result of the
first one and so like we could treat
that as a single word the certainty
result is 2 while you consider the three
words so it'd also be a perfectly
reasonable thing to do and there's no
right answer this kind of weird stuff
happens all the time in Chinese you can
insert the character nut into the middle
of a 2 a 2 character verb and it turns
that into a new word which means that
that theme can't be done just a new word
as in that three words it's very hard to
tell so it's started to use VPN with
Chinese you can kind of tokenize it in a
way that's entirely too digital
so I think that'd be the end of the
range okay so
I want to leave translation there
because I desperately wanted to insert a
discussion about segmentation it's like
we've kept including that segmentation
and I really could have realized in the
last week how exciting a particular part
of segmentation has turned out to be and
I really really really wanted to explain
it to you before the end of the course
so I'm going to do I'm half of it today
and out of it next week if we can and so
let me show you what is exciting so a
segmentation is about taking something
[Music]
like this and turning it into something
like this
where every color represents the thin so
it's kind of pink is Road this light
purple is line this blue is footpaths
this purple is car this red is building
an observable okay so this is quite a
challenging thing to do but it's really
important for anything that's going to
understand the world react to it so
clearly robotics and self-driving cars
that's what we have to be able to do
this very quickly very accurately but
really a whole range of computer vision
problems if you ever do this for example
last week we saw that hackathon winning
entry from a couple of our students that
was able to say take this cat and blur
it out or play this style transfer to
this cat or whatever so you need a way
of being able to know exactly where the
cat is and for something like one of the
things that showed was remove the
background now you actually need to be
able to do a really good job of
segmenting out the cat because if you
get it slightly wrong and then you
remove the background you know you often
see this like when people use Photoshop
badly you know you'll end up with like
the bit between the ears
see those two there or you know their
fur looks really slightly or something
so if you want to create the next
generation Photoshop initiative of this
so there's lots of reasons janeshia
goodness now turns out that there's a
fantastic way of doing this for the
fantastic name called the hundred layers
tiramisu and 100 layers tiramisu is a
fully convolutional denseness and so
therefore we're not going to look at
this yet instead we're going to look at
the denseness because we can understand
the chair issue without identity so here
is the paper that introduced the dance
man
and it turns out you really really need
to also know about business for other
reasons and let me show you the reason I
totally recently I fully appreciated
this here is the results for the
business net and if you look down here
you will recognize that it is being
compared to genuinely state-of-the-art
sub okay so network a network highway
network flexible neck ResNet represent
stochastic depth and wide Brezhnev okay
these are genuinely state-of-the-art
architectures
and it's being looked at on some
carefully studied data sets this is a
five ten this is a 500-ton plus is with
federal organization without classes
without that relevant issue so five
higher 100 the previous said at the art
which is late massively well studied was
twenty-eight and that itself was way
above everybody else this paper got my
scene and I'm like you guys have seen
enough of these now to know that you
don't decrease by 35% we can computer
vision nowadays you can see of the
Amazon so this is like a huge event now
the reason the chooser advanced is
important because specifically these no
data augmentation columns it is
offensive so far ten one similar thing
I've been down from seven point three to
five point one you know the twenty or
thirty two tenets eaters as well what
these represents these these without
data augmentation columns
they basically represents the
performance of this data set on a
limited amount of data but if you're not
using data augmentation you're basically
forcing it to have to work with less
hair and like I know that a huge number
of you are wanting to build stuff where
you don't have much data so if you're
one of those people you definitely need
new Center at this stage since net is by
far the state of the art results or
datasets where you don't have my share
so so I'm going to teach you about that
set for two reasons first is for the
next week we can learn about the
tiramisu and compliance tiramisu but
also so that we can find out how to
create way way way way better computer
vision models where you have analogous
data
okay so let's learn how to do this um
and I can actually describe it with
simple sentence with single sentence
a dense net is a RIF net where you
replace edition with concatenations
so that's actually the entirety of what
advancement is that understanding that
what it is and why it works is more
involved so let's remind ourselves about
ResNet okay we've looked at this many
times but there's no harm in just
reminding ourselves with ResNet we have
some input
input we put it through a convolution to
get some activation and another
convolution to get some activations
you
and we also have the identity
and this is edition right so basically
we end up with our kind of you know
layer T plus 1 equals some functions of
the convolution that is of the layer
T
plus layer T itself right and then
remind you what I've normally shown
after that is then to say okay so our
function
fools
the difference was basically calculating
residual cats having a function that
couldn't find the error so every time we
look at Reds net we read it in this way
okay so what is
we do exactly the same thing
we replace that with
[Music]
catenate drawing them together
and remember this is just one block
right so we've got like blah blah blah
blah blah so what that means is that you
know after the first layer we have both
the result of some convolutions and the
original input which we like literally
copied it in concatenated and then after
the second layer we've got some
convolutions on convolutions and the
original first layer of convolution and
the original input at and further book
that second layer convolutions was self
operating on this concat so that second
layer convolutions was operating both on
the original data as well as on the
outcome of the consider convolutions so
when people draw a dense net they tend
to draw it like this
they show like every layer going to
every layer after it now I didn't define
it that way because it's much easier in
practice to implement it other things
each layer equals all of the previous
layer concatenate it with the
convolution on top of the previous layer
and so you can catch that recursively
if you always have all of your previous
layers there as well okay so sometimes
people get confused when they see this
picture where everything is shown
connecting to each other better you look
at the code and it looks like it's only
connected to the previous letter and
that's because the previous layer itself
were connected to the previous layer
which was the previous lesson trees okay
so
because we kick at meeting the number of
filters is getting bigger and bigger but
so we could have to be careful not to
add too many filters at each letter so
the number of filters that are added in
each layer they call the growth rate and
for some reason they use the letter K is
K for corrosive they tend to use the
values of 12 or 24 in the tiramisu paper
they tend to use the value of 16 so
every layer has 12 more filters in the
previous layer and you generally can
have like 100 letters and so after 100
layers
you could have 1200 or 2400 filters
which is getting to be fun one yes
obviously so interestingly well though
they they kind of add up you actually
end up with less parameters to normal so
you can see that this here is 5 5 10
even this is a state-of-the-art result
set in the center and this is with only
a million parameters right so this is
beating Rebs net with 10 million
parameters by a third okay this is why
it's working so well with so little data
um I'm not convinced that this is the
right approach for or is it a
somatically better approach for imagenet
right this is the picture finish net
some this is the important one the
number of plots so it's another
floating-point operation committed plain
what it takes to your computer Stewart
versus the error rate you can see the
fence net and Resnick at about the same
error rate and then it's like yeah huh
you know it's about sly precise bit less
so it's you're better but it's not like
magically better and there are actually
better architectures than driftnet form
very much net neighbors so so really if
you're using something that's more of
the 100 to 100,000 images range we
probably want to use it as that but it's
more than a hundred thousand images and
maybe it doesn't matter too much
okay so you wanna see the code this
moment
so interestingly this turned out to be
something that suited carrots really
well the you know this kind of like
things where you're using standard kind
of layers connected in different ways
caris it's fantastically growing for
Italy so I'm going to use size 510 I
just copied and pasted the especially to
the Charis Charis of data set so 510 so
there's an example started up in if the
funny of data set is 32 533 pixel images
and so that's what it's like by the same
track translation there from lots 255 so
therefore launched 255 I want to make
them lots of one joy 511 all right so
we're going to try to figure out this is
a truck we have 10 categories and 5 5 10
[Music]
so the less code that you write the less
chance that there is for an arrow all
right so I try to refactor out
everything that happens more than once
and so even a simple thing like
activation really I create a function
for
drop out if you have dropped out I heard
a functionable
that storm with a particular mode and
access to the function for and then
applying radio on top of batch norm
searching for great convolutions are
always have this inert this border mode
this LG regularization and this dropout
so there's a faction ball
um
then we have a batch norm then rail un
convolution and dropout so there's a
function form in the paper they also
have something called a bottleneck layer
this is a one by one convolution where I
basically compressed the number of
filters down into the growth factor fine
for right and so this is a way of
reducing the dimensionality you'll see
here when they use a bottleneck and
something called compression we'll see
in a moment they call it dense net BC
and you can see that that reduces the
number of parameters even more and
therefore makes it even more accurate
right so I'm very speaking you'll
probably be wanting to use bottleneck
but it's just a one by one cons with
this case 48 filters so it's reducing
the dimensionality through that so
basically what happens in is you have a
number of dense blocks each sense slot
basically consists of a number of these
convolutions followed by concatenation
right so go to each layer convolution
concatenate and you see how I'm actually
replacing X with it right so it's
concatenated Twitter self again and
again so it's getting longer and longer
okay and then from time to time
um I then add in a transition block
which is simply a one by one convolution
followed by pulling layer right so just
like every computer visual model we used
to bunch of computation layers and then
pull bunch of computation for budget
computation or so this looks like a
pretty standard kind of architecture oh
and the intervention compression the
other thing that is in each transition
block you can optionally have this thing
called compression which normally you
would set us 0.5 that just says okay the
number of filters take however many
filters we currently have and multiply
by 0.5 so this is basically something
where every time you have a poorly layer
you also decrease the number of filters
so when you have this bottleneck layer
and you have this compression of 0.5
that's what dense near busy the first is
yes and can we do transfer learning
understand
absolutely you can and in fact pilot
torch Japs came to the Negro 16 up
yesterday or today and has been snatched
creature as some pre-trained festival
having said that
because the size of the affirmations
continues to increase increase increase
that we again have this problem that
there isn't really a nice kind of small
number of activations that you could
really build on top of so
I'm not sure I'm not sure how practical
it would be but you're certainly cool
all right so here is the whole Dan Smith
model basically there's four layers
which are part of the dance blocks which
is there's an initial feedback a
convolution there's a global effort
falling layer and there's also a real
innovation on
so if you subtract the four and then
divide by the number of tens blocks that
tells you how many layers you need for
every block so you do a three by three
khans then we go through each of those
lay those layers get a dense block and
for every one except for the last layer
we also do a transition block so that
when a boolean finally do a batch alarm
value global epoch falling and then a
dense layer to create a road under fire
so that's basically it if you create
that compile it and fit it so I ran it
last night
and so I couldn't quite run it as long
as they did but I did get to 90 3.33
which
be sort of a set of the artists
somewhere about shift to the bit so I
didn't have time to run it as long as
they did but I've certainly replicated
their state of the art result as you
know as you can see using nothing but
basically two screens or sort of scare
us
so I read through that pretty quickly
but honestly this is all stuff that you
guys are pretty familiar with so if you
read the paper so really easy paper to
read with the code which have an easy
code to read if you haven't done much
like implementing papers with code this
is a great place to start because it's
like there's no mess in the paper pretty
clear the chaos code is really easy to
read there's no new content so like this
would be a great way to get started and
as I fit in other students and I some of
the students and I basically started on
this on Friday and I've got it knocked
out so I think this is pretty exciting
alright so 9 o'clock
thanks everybody looking forward to
chatting to you in a week close to you
and next Monday for our last part